<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>119</id>
    <title>Catalog Exhibitions Help Put Your Products on the Map</title>
    <short_title>Catalog Exhibitions </short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the U.S. Commercial Service can help stimulate interest in your firm's products and services through exhibitions, literature and exhibits.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/29/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​The U.S. Commercial Service offers you a convenient, affordable way to stimulate interest in your firm's products and services from the comfort of your office.</p><p>U.S. Commercial Service trade specialists located in international markets will translate your company profile into the local language, display your marketing materials, collect sales leads from interested local buyers, and then assist you as you follow up with the local contacts.</p><h2>3 Types to Choose from:</h2><h3>Multi-State Catalog Exhibitions</h3><ul><li>Target four or more promising international markets</li><li>Promote across 20 or more high-demand sectors</li><li>In partnership with State Economic Development Agencies</li></ul><h3>American Product Literature Centers</h3><ul><li>Target a single promising international market</li><li>Focus on a single industry sector</li><li>Typically take place at a leading industry trade show</li></ul><h3>U.S. Embassy/Consulate-sponsored exhibits</h3><ul><li>Target a single promising international market</li><li>Managed by a U.S. Embassy or Consulate</li></ul><h2>What You Need to Know</h2><p>For all three types of Catalog Events the U.S. Commercial Service will:</p><ul><li>Coordinate support from local chambers of commerce, industry associations, and other trade groups</li><li>Provide you with trade leads generated by each exhibition</li><li>Help you capitalize on your leads by providing any needed export assistance</li></ul><p>Participating companies will:</p><ul><li>Provide catalogs and other marketing materials showcasing you firm's products, services, and technology in a timely manner</li><li>Provide your firm's business objectives to the U.S. Commercial Service for these target markets</li><li>Identify a contact in your company who will follow up with the trade leads after the event</li><li>Follow up in a timely manner on all trade leads, leveraging assistance from U.S. Commercial Service staff and/or state trade specialists</li></ul><p>Go to the<a href="https://admin.export.gov/events"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">export events calendar</span></a>to see a complet list of trade events, training programs, and webinars.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Promotion<sub_topic>Marketing</sub_topic><sub_topic>Sales</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Catalog Exhibitions Help Put Your Products on the Map</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the U.S. Commercial Service can help stimulate interest in your firm's products and services through exhibitions, literature and exhibits.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Sales, Exports, Promotions, Exhibitions, International Markets, Trade Specialists, Marketing Materials</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/119.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/119.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/119.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
