<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>124</id>
    <title>Defense Trade Export Controls and Licenses</title>
    <short_title>Defense Controls/Licenses</short_title>
    <summary>Resources on registering with the Department of State and obtaining the approval from the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls (DDTC) prior to the defense trade export. </summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/5/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​Registration</h2><p>By law, all U.S. manufacturers, exporters, and brokers of commodities covered by the U.S. Munitions List must<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/registration/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">register with the Department of State</span></a>.</p><h2>Defense Trade Controls - Applying for a License</h2><p>Any person or company who intends to export a defense article, technical data, provide defense services or engage in brokering, must obtain the approval from the<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Directorate of Defense Trade Controls (DDTC)</span></a>prior to the export. You must<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/licensing/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">register and apply</span></a>for a license.</p><h2>Defense Trade Information Center</h2><p>The<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/DTRADE/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Defense Trade Information Center</span></a>provides the Electronic Licensing System to U.S. persons who seek to export defense articles or defense services regulated by the ITAR.</p><h2>Compliance</h2><p>To ensure<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/compliance/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">compliance with U.S. export law</span></a>and regulations, the DDTC strongly advises that registered exporters and manufacturers have in place programs that assist in monitoring defense trade activities. These programs should include a manual that articulates the company's policy on and commitment to compliance with defense trade laws and regulations, and that outlines the procedures for dealing with licensing and compliance matters. Such a manual should also include the identification and duties of empowered and responsible persons, and procedures on record keeping and internal auditing.</p><h2>Commodity Jurisdiction</h2><p>An exporter should request a<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/commodity_jurisdiction/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">commodity jurisdiction (CJ)</span></a>determination to resolve any uncertainty regarding the export licensing jurisdiction of an item or service. A CJ is used to determine whether an item or service is subject to the export licensing authority of BIS or DTC.</p><h2>Response Team</h2><p>The<a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/response_team/index.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">DDTC Response Team</span></a>provides responses to the full range of defense trade inquiries, and can significantly facilitate your defense trade solutions while affording licensing and other officers in DDTC more time for casework. By handling telephone calls from industry and the public, it supports the work of licensing and compliance officers by allowing them to focus on their core activities.</p><p><a href="http://www.pmddtc.state.gov/reports/655_intro.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Section 655 Annual Military Assistance Reports</span></a>are provided to Congress and show for a fiscal year the aggregate dollar value and quantity of defense articles and defense services authorized as direct commercial sales to each foreign country. Note that these reports do not cover defense articles and services that are provided via the<a href="http://www.dsca.osd.mil/home/foreign_military_sales.htm"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Foreign Military Sales (FMS)</span></a>program.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, defense, trade, technical data, brokering, controls, license, DDTC, directorate of defense trade controls</keyword>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Regulations<sub_topic>Export Licenses</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Aerospace &amp; Defense</industry>
        <industry>Security &amp; Safety</industry>
      </industries>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Defense Trade Export Controls and Licenses</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Resources on registering with the Department of State and obtaining the approval from the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls (DDTC) prior to the defense trade export. </seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>commodity jurisdiction, license, DDTC, directorate of defense trade controls</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/124.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/124.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/124.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
