<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>142</id>
    <title>Freight Forwarders, Customs Brokers And INCOTERMS - Making Exporting Easier</title>
    <short_title>Making Exporting Easier with Agents and Brokers</short_title>
    <summary>Learn methods used by exporters to reduce confusion and delays associated with international trade logistics.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p><em>Export America, November 2001</em><br>Updated July 2003</p><p>While exporting can greatly contribute to a firm's economic growth, it can also be a time consuming process for the small and medium-sized business. This article outlines ways in which exporters can mitigate confusion and delays associated with international trade logistics.</p><h2>What is a Freight Forwarder?</h2><p>To comply with export documentation and shipping requirements, many exporters utilize a freight forwarder to act as their shipping agent. The forwarder advises and assists clients on how to move goods most efficiently from one destination to another. A forwarder's extensive knowledge of documentation requirements, regulations, transportation costs and banking practices can ease the exporting process for many companies. The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.fmc.gov"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Federal Maritime Commission</span></a>licenses U.S. forwarders for ocean operations, and some U.S. forwarders are affiliated with global organizations like the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.iata.org"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">International Air Transport Association</span></a>.</p><h2>Why Should I Use a Freight Forwarder?</h2><p>Whether the firm is large or small, the weight of the cargo light or heavy, the freight forwarder will take care of cargo from &quot;dock to door&quot; if requested to do so. This can include the correct filing of export documentation, all arrangements with carriers, packing, crating and storage needs. So, the small and medium-size exporter need not deal with many of the details involved with the logistics of exporting their goods. In addition, freight forwarders typically charge modest rates for their services and have access to shipping discounts. Given the years of experience and constant attention to detail provided by the forwarder, it may be a good investment.</p><h2>How Can I Find Freight Forwarder?</h2><p>Freight forwarders are located in most metropolitan areas. Local business telephone listings often feature a freight forwarder or transportation heading. Additionally, the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ncbfaa.org"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">National Customs Brokers and Forwarders Association of America</span></a>will provide exporters with information on their members. They can be reached at:<br><br>1200 18th Street, NW,<br>Suite 901<br>Washington, DC 20036,<br>Tel: (202) 466-0222,<br><br>Privately operated forwarder listing services can be useful when looking for a local forwarder. The following websites have listings:</p><ul><li><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.forwarders.com"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Directory of Freight Forwarding Services</span></a></li><li><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.1800miti.com/links/page84.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">1800Miti.com</span></a></li><li><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.freightgate.com/directories/directories.tet"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">FreightGate.com</span></a></li><li><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.freightnet.com"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">FreightNet.com</span></a></li></ul><h2>What Is a Customs Broker?</h2><p>A customs broker performs transactions at ports on behalf of other parties. In other words, an importer, whether into the United States or another country, hires a customs broker to guide their goods into a country. Like the forwarder, the broker will recommend efficient means for clearing goods through the maze of customs entry protocol. The broker can also estimate the landed costs for shipments entering the country. U.S. exporters typically do not book shipments directly with a foreign customs broker, because freight forwarders often partner with customs brokers overseas who will clear goods that the forwarder ships to the overseas port. Conversely, those same foreign customs brokers contract the services of the domestic freight forwarder when the goods are headed in the opposite direction.<br><br>The transactions negotiated for the importer will include the entry of goods into a customs territory, payment of taxes and duties and duty drawback or refunds of any kind. Furthermore, the broker has knowledge of regulations not only from the corresponding customs authority, but also from other regulating agencies involved in imports.</p><h2>What are INCOTERMS and When Are They Used?</h2><p>Incoterms is an abbreviation of International Commercial Terms, which were first published in 1936 by the International Chamber of Commerce. Since that time there have been six different revisions and updates to the Incoterms. The Incoterms provide a common set of rules for the most often used international terms of trade. The goal of the Incoterms is to alleviate or reduce confusion over interpretations of shipping terms by outlining who is obligated to take control of and/or insure goods at a particular point in the shipping process. Furthermore, the terms outline the obligations for the clearance of the goods for export or import and packing requirements. The Incoterms are used quite frequently in international contracts and an official version of the Incoterms should be referenced in the text of the contract.</p><p>Although the Incoterms are widely used and exceedingly handy, they are not appropriate for every type of contract. Specifically, the terms used in a contract state exactly when the shipper unloads and relinquishes obligation and when the buyer takes over for carriage and insurance. The Incoterms are not meant to replace statements in a contract of sale that outline transfers of ownership or title to goods. Therefore, the Incoterms may not be of use when looking to resolve disputes that may arise regarding payment or ownership of goods.<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/https://admin.export.gov/community/users/international-logistics/posts/44-incoterms"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Read more</span></a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, mitigate, international, logistics, trade, freight, forwarder, customs, broker, incoterms</keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>International Logisitics<sub_topic>Freight Forwarder</sub_topic><sub_topic>Incoterms</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Freight Forwarders, Customs Brokers And INCOTERMS - Making Exporting Easier | Trade.gov</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn methods used by exporters to reduce confusion and delays associated with international trade logistics.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Exports, Brokers, Shipping, Importers</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/142.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/142.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/142.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
