<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>159</id>
    <title>Legal Considerations </title>
    <short_title>Legal Considerations </short_title>
    <summary>Exporting legal issues and resources for considerations.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/5/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Exporters are frequently faced with legal issues, such as those relating to agent/distributor agreements, protection of intellectual property rights and appropriate licensing arrangements, which can determine the viability of a successful export transaction. Here are some other legal issues:</p><h2>Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA)</h2><p>U.S. firms seeking to do business in foreign markets must be familiar with the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.fcpa.us"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA)</span></a>. In general, the FCPA prohibits American companies from making corrupt payments to foreign officials for the purpose of obtaining or keeping business. The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.justice.gov/criminal/fraud/fcpa"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Department of Justice</span></a>is the chief enforcement agency, with a coordinate role played by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). The Commerce Department's<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.commerce.gov/os/ogc/international-commerce"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Office of the Chief Counsel for International Commerce (OCC-IC)</span></a>has posted useful background information on various legal issues facing exporters -- focusing mostly on export and investment issues.</p><h2>Anti-Boycott Regulations</h2><p>The United States has an established policy of opposing<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.bis.doc.gov/complianceandenforcement/antiboycottcompliance.htm"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">restrictive trade practices or boycotts</span></a>fostered or imposed by foreign countries against other countries friendly to the United States. In general, these laws prohibit U.S. persons from participating in foreign boycotts or taking actions that further or support such boycotts. The laws are administered by the Bureau of Industry and Security.</p><h2>Anti-Dumping</h2><p>If a company exports a product at a price lower than the price it normally charges on its own home market, it could be said to be &quot;dumping&quot; the product. Opinions differ as to whether or not this is unfair competition, but many governments take action against dumping in order to defend their domestic industries. The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.wto.org"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">World Trade Organization (WTO)</span></a>agreement does not pass judgment. Its focus is on how governments can or cannot react to dumping -- it disciplines anti-dumping actions, and it is often called the &quot;Anti-Dumping Agreement.&quot; (This focuses only on the reaction to dumping contrasts with the approach of the Subsidies and Countervailing Measures Agreement.)</p><h2>Other Legal Resources</h2><p><strong>District Export Councils</strong></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.districtexportcouncil.com"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">District Export Councils (DECs)</span></a>are organizations of leaders from the local business community, whose knowledge of international business provides a source of professional advice for local firms. Many DEC members are practicing attorneys. For more than 25 years, DECs have served the U.S. by assisting companies in their local communities export.</p><p><strong>American Bar Association</strong></p><p>Another useful source for legal information is the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.americanbar.org"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">American Bar Association (ABA)</span></a>. The ABA publishes numerous books on the subject of international business. Some of these<a href="http://informationportalprodhttp://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.americanbar.org/groups/international_law.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">publications</span></a>include guides to the legal aspects of doing business in specific countries and guides to foreign law firms and law groups abroad.</p><h3>Additional Resources</h3><ul><li><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/https://admin.export.gov/centers"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Find an Export Assistance Center</span></a></li></ul><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, legal issues, legal, issues, resources, justice, anti-boycott, anti-dumping, corrupt, payment, foreign, officials, ABA, DEC, </keyword>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
        <topic>Trade Regulations<sub_topic>Export Licenses</sub_topic><sub_topic>Foreign Corrupt Practices Act</sub_topic><sub_topic>Ant-Boycott Regulations</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Information &amp; Communication</industry>
      </industries>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Legal Considerations</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Exporting legal issues and resources for considerations.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>legal, trade regulations, foreign corrupt practices act, fcpa, anti-boycott, anti-dumping, </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/159.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/159.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/159.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
