<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>161</id>
    <title>Mandatory Screening of Cargo on Passenger Flights</title>
    <short_title>Cargo Screening on Passenger Flights</short_title>
    <summary>Get background information about the mandatory screening requirements for cargo on passenger flights.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Effective August 1, 2010, 100 percent of cargo flown on passenger aircraft (PAX) originating in the United States must be screened, per an act passed by Congress and signed into law by former President Bush. Beginning August 1, all PAX cargoes must now be screened at the piece level - which is the individual item within a shipment - before it can be loaded on an aircraft in the United States.</p><p>This requirement stems from the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://frwebgate.access.gpo.gov/cgi-bin/getdoc.cgi?dbname=110_cong_bills&amp;docid=f%3ah1enr.txt.pdf"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">9/11 Commission Act of 2007</span></a>(the &quot;9/11 Act&quot;), which mandates that countermeasures be taken to defend against threats that are posed to the public, transportation systems, and critical infrastructure. The PAX mandate is intended to close a large gap in the nation's aviation security, which threatens the safety of travelers and the transportation system. Earlier milestones in meeting this mandate are discussed below.</p><p>TSA responded to the Congressional mandate by creating the<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.tsa.gov/what_we_do/layers/aircargo/certified_screening.shtm"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Certified Cargo Screening Program</span></a>(CCSP). CCSP is a voluntary program which allows for industry to participate in the achievement of 100% cargo screening without impeding the flow of commerce. It facilitates screening of PAX cargo at a level of security commensurate to that of passenger baggage. While air carriers are ultimately responsible for ensuring that all cargo on their passenger aircraft has been screened, CCSP provides industry the flexibility to screen their own cargoes prior to delivery to the air carrier, to speed cargo acceptance by the carrier and to avoid system delays.</p><h2><strong>Key Milestones</strong></h2><ul><li><strong>October 2008</strong>– 100% screening of cargo flown on passenger narrow body aircraft. Screening conducted by TSA and passenger air carriers.</li><li><strong>February 2009</strong>- 50% screening of cargo flown on passenger wide body aircraft. Screening conducted by air carriers, freight forwarders, and shippers.</li><li><strong>May 2010</strong>- 75% screening of cargo flown on passenger wide body aircraft. Screening conducted by air carriers, freight forwarders, and shippers.</li><li><strong>August 1st, 2010</strong>– 100% screening of cargo flown on all passenger aircraft. Screening conducted by air carriers, freight forwarders, and shippers.</li></ul><p>For more information, visit<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.tsa.gov/ccsp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">www.tsa.gov/ccsp</span></a>.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, cargo, PAX, act, mandate, mandatory, screening, passenger flights, congress, TSA </keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>International Logisitics<sub_topic>Cargo Screening</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Mandatory Screening of Cargo on Passenger Flights | Trade.gov</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Get background information about the mandatory screening requirements for cargo on passenger flights.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Exports, Cargo, Passenger Flights, Certified Cargo Screening Program</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/161.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/161.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/161.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
