<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>172</id>
    <title>Platinum Key Service</title>
    <short_title>Platinum Key Service</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the U.S. Commercial Service's Platinum Key Service which allows U.S. companies to take advantage of longer term, sustained and customized assistance on a range of issues including market identification and market research.</summary>
    <creation_date>1/30/3013</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/3/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Commercial Service's Platinum Key Service allows U.S. companies to take advantage of longer term, sustained and customized assistance on a range of issues.</p><p>The service is solution-oriented and tailored to the client's needs through a mutually agreed upon scope of work. The service can include a range of issues including, but not limited to, identifying markets, launching products, developing major project opportunities, resolving commercial disputes and providing assistance on regulatory or technical standards matters.</p><p>Ongoing service is available for six months, one year, or a specified timeframe based on the mutually agreed-upon scope of work. Our overseas specialists will work closely with clients to identify and outline specific needs, provide progress reports and ensure timely delivery of service.</p><p>The Platinum Key Service will help you:</p><ul><li>Identify the best export markets</li><li>Locate valuable market research</li><li>Develop the most appropriate market entry strategy</li><li>Identify prospective agents, distributors, licensees, and other business partners</li><li>Develop marketing and selling strategies</li><li>Understand the regulatory and product standards in your target markets</li></ul><p>Overseas Trade Specialists will:</p><ul><li>Work closely with your company to identify and outline your specific needs</li><li>Provide progress reports</li><li>Ensure timely delivery of the service</li></ul><p>The service is fee-based and can last as long as a year, based on your company's requirements.</p><p>To request this service, contact an<a href="https://admin.export.gov/centers"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Export Assistance Center</span></a>.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, platimum key service, platimum, key, tailored, client, needs</keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Market Intelligence<sub_topic>Market Research</sub_topic></topic>
        <topic>Trade Promotion<sub_topic>Business Matchmaking</sub_topic><sub_topic>Marketing</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Platinum Key Service </seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the U.S. Commercial Service's Platinum Key Service which allows U.S. companies to take advantage of longer term, sustained and customized assistance on a range of issues including market identification and market research.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Exports, Agents, Distributors, Market Development</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/172.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/172.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/172.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
