<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>183</id>
    <title>Shipping to U.S. Territories - Tax and Tariff Information</title>
    <short_title>U.S. Territories Tariff Information</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the shipping tax rates and tariffs for U.S. territories.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/27/2014</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>Guam</h2><p>As a U.S. territory, Guam has no duty or quota requirements applicable on shipments to Territory of Guam.</p><p>However, there are fees and other requirements that apply to the type of importation and business.</p><ol><li>$5.00 procession fee for all shipments of cargo entering the Territory.</li><li>Business license required prior to engaging in any business issued by the Department of Revenue and Taxation.</li><li>4% gross receipt tax on all merchandise sold in Guam.</li><li>4% use tax on all items imported for personal or business use.</li></ol><h2>Puerto Rico</h2><p>As a U.S. territory, shipments to Puerto Rico are not considered exports so duties are not applied.</p><p>There is, however, a state sales tax of 5.5% and a municipal sales tax that can vary from 0% to 1.5 percent. Thus, taxes on consumption (levied to the end user) will vary from 5.5% to 7%.</p><h2>U.S. Virgin Islands (USVI)</h2><p>U. S. origin items shipped to the USVI are exempt from duties; however they will be subject to an excise tax. These taxes range from 0 to 6%. A few items, like cigarettes, are taxed at a higher level. Alcoholic beverages are subject to a flat rate based on volume.</p><p>Non-U.S. origin goods will be subject to a duty equal to the difference between the 6% the USVI normally levies on imports and whatever duty was paid on these items when they entered the U.S.( If there was a 5% duty charged at entry into the U.S., there would be an additional 1% charged upon entry into the USVI.)</p><p>For additional information about excise taxes, you can call the USVI excise tax office on 340-773-3766.</p><h2>Other U.S. Territories</h2><p>Shipments to US Territories are NOT considered exports. There are fourteen US territories and possessions:</p><ul><li>American Samoa</li><li>Baker Island</li><li>Guam</li><li>Howland Island</li><li>Jarvis Island</li><li>Johnston Atoll</li><li>Kingman Reef</li><li>Midway Islands</li><li>Navassa Island</li><li>Northern Mariana Islands</li><li>Palmyra Atoll</li><li>Puerto Rico</li><li>Virgin Islands (US)</li><li>Wake Island</li></ul><p>Please contact the U.S. Department of Interior for more information on shipping to these territories at (202) 208-6816</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, shipping, U.S. territories, territories, U.S., Guam, Puerto Rico, U.S. Virgin Islands, USVI</keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>International Logisitics<sub_topic>Tariffs and Import Fees</sub_topic><sub_topic>Shipping</sub_topic></topic>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Shipping to U.S. Territories - Tax and Tariff Information</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the shipping tax rates and tariffs for U.S. territories.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Fees, Tariffs, Guam, Puerto Rico, U.S. Virgin Islands, </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/183.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/183.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/183.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
