<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>186</id>
    <title>The Harmonized System</title>
    <short_title>The Harmonized System</short_title>
    <summary>Get information about the Harmonized System. 
</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>All import and export codes used by the United States are based on the Harmonized System (HS). The HS assigns 6-digit codes for general categories. This 6-digit code is known as the Harmonized System number.</p><p>Countries that use the HS are allowed to define commodities at a more detailed level than 6-digits, however all definitions must be within that 6-digit framework. The U.S., for example, defines products using 10-digit codes in its Harmonized Tariff Schedule (HTS).</p><p>Export codes, also known as Schedule B numbers, are administered by the U.S. Census Bureau.</p><p>Import codes are administered by the U.S. International Trade Commission (USITC).</p><h2>Harmonized System (HS) and Schedule B Numbers</h2><p>Harmonized System (HS) numbers are used to classify products for customs purposes. By international agreement, most countries recognize the same first 6 &quot;harmonized&quot; digits.</p><p>To get a duty rate, one needs to have the complete product number used by the importing country. Since this is sometimes difficult, companies can use the Schedule B number to approximate.</p><p>Schedule B Numbers are used to classify exported products in the United States and are based on the international HS system. HS numbers and Schedule B numbers will be the same up to the first 6 digits as the importing country's classification code.</p><h3>Why You Need to Know Your Product's Schedule B and HS Numbers</h3><p>Exporters need to know their product's Schedule B and HS numbers for the following reasons:</p><ol><li>To determine applicable import tariff rates and whether a product qualifies for a preferential tariff under a Free Trade Agreement.</li><li>The Schedule B number is needed to complete the Shipper's Export Declaration, Certificates of Origin and other shipping documents.</li><li>The HS Number may be needed on shipping documents, such as certificates of origin.</li></ol><h3>How to Identify Your Product's Schedule B Number</h3><p>The Census Bureau provides the<a href="https://uscensus.prod.3ceonline.com/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Schedule B Search Engine</span></a>as an online tool and an<a href="http://www.census.gov/foreign-trade/data/video022.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">instructional video</span></a>to help you classify your products. The Schedule B search tool is the most commonly used method for classifying products.</p><p>After consulting the Search Engine, you can obtain further assistance on Schedule B numbers from a commodity specialist at the U.S. Census Bureau Foreign Trade Division:</p><ul><li>Durable goods (metals, machinery, computer, electronic and other miscellaneous goods) call: 301-763-3259</li><li>Non-durable goods (food, animal, wood, paper, mineral, chemical and textile goods) call: 301-763-3484</li></ul><p>For assistance identifying your appropriate HS number you may also contact your local Export Assistance Center or call the Trade Information Center at 1-800-USATRAD(E).</p><p>If you are having difficulty determining your Schedule B number, you may also want to review the<a href="http://rulings.cbp.gov/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Customs Rulings (CROSS)</span></a>database.</p><p>The Census Bureau produces<em>The Schedule B: Statistical Classification of Domestic and Foreign Commodities Exported from the United States</em>that can be ordered from the Government Printing Office by calling 202-512-1800. The stock number is 903-009-00000-4. The CD-ROM version can also be purchased from the Census Bureau by calling 301-457-1086.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>export, exporting, harmonized, system, HS, number, schedule B, </keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>International Logisitics<sub_topic>Schedule B and HS Number</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>The Harmonized System | Trade.gov</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Get information about the Harmonized System. </seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Exports, Product Classifications, Customs Rulings, Duty Rates</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/186.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/186.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/186.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
