<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>189</id>
    <title>What Is a Freight Forwarder?</title>
    <short_title>What is a Freight Forwarder?</short_title>
    <summary>Learn what a freight forwarder is, the role they play and how to locate one.</summary>
    <creation_date>8/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>An international freight forwarder is an agent for the exporter in moving cargo to an overseas destination. These agents are familiar with the import rules and regulations of foreign countries, the export regulations of the U.S. government, the methods of shipping, and the documents related to foreign trade. Export freight forwarders are licensed by the International Air Transport Association (IATA) to handle air freight and the Federal Maritime Commission to handle ocean freight.</p><p>Freight forwarders assist exporters in preparing price quotations by advising on freight costs, port charges, consular fees, costs of special documentation, insurance costs, and their handling fees. They recommend the packing methods that will protect the merchandise during transit or can arrange to have the merchandise packed at the port or containerized. If the exporter prefers, freight forwarders can reserve the necessary space on a vessel, aircraft, train, or truck. The cost for their services is a legitimate export cost that should be included in the price charged to the customer.</p><p>Once the order is ready for shipment, freight forwarders should be review all documents to ensure that everything is in order. This is of particular importance with letter of credit payment terms. They may also prepare the bill of lading and any special required documentation. After shipment, they can route the documents to the seller, the buyer, or to a paying bank. Freight forwarders can also make arrangements with customs brokers overseas to ensure that the goods comply with customs export documentation regulations. A customs broker is an individual or company that is licensed to transact customs business on behalf of others. Customs business is limited to those activities involving transactions related to the entry and admissibility of merchandise; its classification and valuation; the payment of duties, taxes, or other charges assessed or collected; or the refund, rebate, or drawback thereof.</p><h2>How can I find freight forwarder?</h2><p>Freight forwarders are located in most metropolitan areas. Local business telephone listings often feature a freight forwarder or transportation heading. Additionally, the<a href="http://www.ncbfaa.org/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">National Customs Brokers and Forwarders Association of America</span></a>will provide exporters with information on their members. They can be reached at:<br><br>1200 18th Street, NW,<br>Suite 901<br>Washington, DC 20036<br>Tel: (202) 466-0222<br><br>Privately operated forwarder listing services, such as those below, can help to identify a local forwarder.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.forwarders.com/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Directory of Freight Forwarding Services</span></a></li><li><a href="http://www.1800miti.com/links/page84.html"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">1800Miti.com</span></a></li><li><a href="http://www.freightgate.com/directories/directories.tet"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">FreightGate.com</span></a></li><li><a href="http://www.freightnet.com/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">FreightNet.com</span></a></li></ul><h2>Agricultural Freight Forwarders</h2><p>An extensive, detailed database of<a href="http://apps.ams.usda.gov/tmd/freight/ffdb/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Agricultural Freight Forwarders</span></a>, including their experience shipping agricultural products.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword>freight, forwarder, export, exporting, agent, locate, overseas, destination, rules, regulations, shipping, air, ocean, maritime</keyword>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>International Logisitics<sub_topic>Freight Forwarder</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>What is a Freight Forwarder? | Trade.gov</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn what a freight forwarder is, the role they play and how to locate one.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Exports, Agents, International Air Transport Association (IATA), Federal Maritime Commission </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/189.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/189.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/189.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
