<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>206</id>
    <title>Partners - Austin U.S. Export Assistance Council</title>
    <short_title>Partners - Austin USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about partners of the Austin U.S. Export Assistance Council.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/11/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/10/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">There are a variety of international trade resources in Central Texas. The Austin U.S. Export Assistance Center partners with the following organizations to leverage their outreach into the Central Texas community:</span></p><p><strong>Texas Camino Real Export Council</strong>is a group of trade professionals who volunteer their time and expertise to provide leadership to the international business community as appointed by the U.S. Secretary of Commerce. The Councils are closely associated with the Commercial Service Export Assistance Centers. With four Councils in Texas, the Texas Camino Real Export Council covers the territory of Central and South Texas. The goal of the Council is in increasing the opportunities for Texas businesses to export include providing counseling and education on how to export, providing information on the various avenues of export financing, to serve as a voice in the local community by educating the benefits of free trade as a benefit to economic well-being and in the distribution of their publication, the Texas Exporters Resource Guide.</p><p><em>Contact: Karen Parker, Executive Secretary</em><br>Tel: 512-916-5939<br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Karen.Parker@trade.gov">Karen.Parker@trade.gov</a><br>Website:<a href="http://www.exporttexas.com/">http://www.exporttexas.com</a></p><p><strong>Small Business Administration - Office of International Trade</strong>offers exporters various trade finance programs from their lenders, such as Export Working Capital Program, International Trade Loan Program, SBA Export Express. To find a lender participating in these programs call:</p><p><em>Contact: Rick Schulze</em><br>Tel: 817-310-3749<br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Richard.Schulze@sba.gov">Richard.Schulze@sba.gov</a><br>Website:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.sba.gov/oit/finance/index.html">http://www.sba.gov/oit/finance/index.html</a></p><p><strong>The Export Import (ExIm) Bank</strong>is an independent federal government agency that helps finance the overseas sales of U.S. goods and services. Its mission is to create American jobs through exports. It provides guarantees of working capital loans for U.S. exporters, and it guarantees the repayment of loans or makes loans to foreign purchasers of U.S. goods and services. It also provides credit insurance that protects U.S. exporters against the risks of non-payment by foreign buyers for political or commercial reasons. It does not compete with commercial lenders, but assumes the risks they cannot accept. It must always have a reasonable assurance of repayment.</p><p><em>Contact: Patrick Crilley</em><br>Tel: 281-721-0465<br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:patrick.crilley@exim.gov">patrick.crilley@exim.gov</a><br>Website:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.exim.gov">http://www.exim.gov</a></p><p><strong>Office of the Governor- Office of Economic Development and Tourism's</strong>mission is to market Texas and assist communities in maximizing their economic development opportunities in the global economy. The Small Business division helps advocate for Texas companies to further promote their products and services to international buyers and partners through trade missions, trade shows, seminars and in-bound trade missions. The State of Texas has one international office located in Mexico City.</p><p><em>Contact: Amir Mirabi, Director – Small Business &amp; Exports</em></p><p>Tel: 512-936-0213<br>Website:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.governor.state.tx.us">www.governor.state.tx.us</a>and<a href="http://www.texaswideopenforbusiness.com/">www.texaswideopenforbusiness.com</a><br>Mexico City Office<br>Tel: 011-525-514-4353</p><p><strong>Texas Dept. of Agriculture (TDA)</strong>mission is to make Texas the nation's leader in agriculture while providing efficient and extraordinary service. To make the most of Texas' marketing and export opportunities, the Texas Department of Agriculture works with farmers, ranchers, commodity organizations, cooperatives and businesses through the GO TEXAN campaign to promote all Texas agricultural products – from food, fiber and wine to forestry and horticulture – to increase sales of these products both at home and abroad. TDA has an international marketing staff that can help assess an agricultural company's export readiness as well as provide export marketing counseling and assistance with export financial assistance programs.</p><p><em>Contact: T.J. Verver, Director for International Marketing</em><br>Tel: 512-463-7469<br>Email: <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:TJ.Verver@texasagriculture.gov">TJ.Verver@texasagriculture.gov</a><br>Website:<a href="http://www.gotexan.org/">http://www.gotexan.org</a></p><p><strong>Greater Austin Chamber of Commerce</strong>serves the citizens of Central Texas through its initiatives, programs, volunteer committees and business events. Its mission is to provide leadership that will help create regional economic prosperity and success for its members in Central Texas. The chamber hosts numerous inbound foreign delegation and dignataries and also works to attract foreign investment to the region.</p><p><em>Contact: Adriana Cruz</em><br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:acruz@austinchamber.gov">acruz@austinchamber.gov</a><br>Tel: 512-478-9383<br>Website:<a href="http://www.austinchamber.org/index.html">http://www.austinchamber.org/index.html</a></p><p><strong>City of Austin - International Program</strong>- The International Program of the City of Austin is the City's focal point for international business, trade, educational and cultural activities. The International Program office is the first point of contact in the Greater Austin area for international activities of all kinds and the City's primary liaison with Greater Austin's international organizations.</p><p><em>Contact: Ben Ramirez, International Programs Directoror Marianne Martinez, Sister City</em><br>Tel: 512-974-6416 or 512-974-6418</p><p>Website:<a href="http://www.ci.austin.tx.us/international/">http://www.ci.austin.tx.us/international/</a></p><p><strong>International Business Institute (IBI)</strong>at Austin Community College (ACC) is designed to provide a comprehensive international business education program, incorporating under one umbrella all parts of international education. Offering both credit and continuing education classes and seminars for International Business.</p><p><em>Contact: Bill Louden</em><br>Email: Wlouden@austincc.edu<br>Tel: 512-223-7292<br>Website:<a href="http://www.austin.cc.tx.us/intlbus/">http://www.austin.cc.tx.us/intlbus/</a></p><p><strong>South-West Texas Border Region International Trade</strong><strong>Center</strong>was specifically created to assist small- to medium-sized companies explore and develop business potential in global markets. The International Trade Center is located in San Antonio and a resource for 79 counties of the South Texas Border SBDC and is part of the nationwide Small Business Development Center (SBDC) network, which includes Austin. The center provides numerous training classes and counseling related to international business.</p><p><em>Contact: Cliff Parades, Director</em><br>Doug Smith, Senior Counselor, covers Austin<br>Tel: 210-458-2470<br>Email: <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:ddsmith@utsa.edu">ddsmith@utsa.edu</a><br>Website:<a href="http://www.iedtexas.org/">http://www.iedtexas.org</a></p><p><strong>The Small Business Development Centers</strong>have an office in Austin (Texas State University in San Marcos) and in Waco (McLennan Community College.) These organizations are partially funded through Small Business Administration, along with a host organization, such as a University or community college. The Small Business Development Centers (SBDC) work with existing and startup small companies to help them grow and compete in today's global economy. SBDCs are available for small companies in every phase of the business life cycle, helping entrepreneurs make sound decisions and succeed. The resulting improvement in their business performance leads to job creation, investments, and economic growth for communities all across South Texas.</p><p>Texas State SBDC (in Austin)<br></p><p>Tel: 512-716-4800; Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:sbdc@txstate.edu">sbdc@txstate.edu</a><br>Website<a href="http://www.business.txstate.edu/sbdc">www.business.txstate.edu/sbdc</a><br>MCC SBDC (In Waco)<br>Tel: 254-714-0077</p><p><strong>Greater Waco Chamber of Commerce</strong>works to promote the area and meet specific needs of business. They have partnered with the Austin USEAC in bringing export outreach programs to the area included surrounding rural communities. They have participated in the U.S. Chamber of Commerce Trade Roots Program, has an associate member to the Texas Camino Real Export Council, and has formed an international committee at the Chamber.</p><p>Tel: 254-296-0405<br>website:<a href="http://www.wacochamber.com/">http://www.wacochamber.com</a></p><p><strong>Greater Austin Hispanic Chamber of Commerce</strong>represents a broad array of organizations, with over 700 active members from corporations, small businesses, individuals, non-profit agencies, business associations and government agencies. The International Trade committee works to establish strategic alliances to promote and provide business opportunities for member Hispanic businesses and has most recently opened a Mexico Trade Center to foster and promote commerce between the greater Austin area and Texas.</p><p>Tel: 512-462-1417<br>Website:<a href="http://www.hispanicaustin.com/">http://www.hispanicaustin.com</a></p><p><strong>CIBER University of Texas</strong>has achieved considerable success in bringing the international expertise of the University directly to the international business community, and vice versa. Their business outreach has three main objectives: Strengthen Alliances with International Business Organizations, Mobilize University Resources to Contribute to Firms' Global Competitiveness, and Develop Products and Services to Contribute to Firm's Global Competitiveness.</p><p><em>Contact: David Platt, Director</em><br>Tel: 512-471-1829<br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:ciber@mccombs.utexas.edu">ciber@N0SPAM.mccombs.utexas.edu</a><br>Website:<a href="http://www.mccombs.utexas.edu/research/ciber/">http://www.mccombs.utexas.edu/research/ciber/</a></p><p><strong>Global Austin</strong>is the local contact agency for the U.S. Department of State. Each year hundreds of international program dignitaries come to Austin. Global Austin, with the help of its volunteers, works to provide people-to-people contact between current and emerging leaders of other nations and the United States.</p><p><em>Contact: Margie Kidd, Executive Director</em></p><p>Tel: 512-215-0140<br>Email: <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:ihcaustin@ihcaustin.com">ihcaustin@ihcaustin.com​</a><br>Website:<a>http://www.ihcaustin.com​</a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Partners - Austin U.S. Export Assistance Council</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about partners of the Austin U.S. Export Assistance Council.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>exports, exporting, Austin, Texas, assistance, partners</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/206.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/206.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/206.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
