<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>215</id>
    <title>Arizona U.S. Export Assistance Centers Strategic Partnership Program</title>
    <short_title>Arizona USEAC Strategic Partnership Program</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about how Arizona's U.S. Export Assistance Centers are is leveraging partnerships with trade associations and private corporations through the Strategic Partnership Program.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/14/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/13/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​​​​<img alt="U.S. Commercial Service logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/U.S.%20Commercial%20Service%20logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><p>To be more competitive in the global economy, the United States must grow its exporter base. Even though exporting is a proven source of growth for both U.S. companies and the U.S. economy, the United States is just beginning to tap its export potential.</p><p>​Approximately 58% of U.S. exporters sell to only one foreign market (source:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.census.gov/foreign-trade/Press-Release/edb/2006/edbrel.pdf">US Census Bureau</a>).</p><p>Exporting accounted for only 12 percent of the U.S. gross domestic product (GDP) in 2007. As compared to other industrialized nations like Germany, the United Kingdom, and France, where exporting accounts for 30 – 49 percent of GDP, the U.S. must do better (source:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.export.gov/build/groups/public/@eg_main/documents/webcontent/eg_main_020090.pdf">National Export Strategy</a>).</p><h2>What is the Strategic Partnership Program?</h2><p>To broaden and deepen the U.S. exporter base, the U.S. Commercial Service Strategic Partnership Program is leveraging partnerships with trade associations and private corporations. Through these innovative public-private partnerships, we are communicating to millions of U.S. businesses about global business opportunities through the U.S. Commercial Service.</p><p>In doing so, the U.S. Commercial Service Strategic Partnership Program creates triple win scenarios:</p><p></p><ul><li><p>National export objectives are supported;<br></p></li><li><p>Partners deliver valuable information to help their customers and members grow; and<br></p></li><li><p>More small- and medium-sized businesses get the export assistance they need to be successful and maintain good American jobs at wages 13 to 18 percent higher than workers in non-exporting firms​.​</p></li></ul><font color="#000000" face="verdana"></font><table width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.azcommerce.com"><img alt="Arizona Commerce Authority logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Arizona_Commerce_Authority_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"><p>The Arizona Commerce Authority (ACA) is the leading economic development organization with a streamlined mission to grow and strengthen Arizona's economy. The ACA uses a three-pronged approach to advance the overall economy: recruit, grow, create – recruit out-of-state companies to expand their operations in Arizona; work with existing companies to grow their business in Arizona and beyond; and partner with entrepreneurs and companies large and small to create new jobs and businesses in targeted industries.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/https://skysong.asu.edu"><img alt="ASU SkySong logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/ASU_SkySong_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p>SkySong, the ASU Scottsdale Innovation Center, is home to a global business community that links technology, research, education and entrepreneurship to position ASU and Greater Phoenix as global leaders in the knowledge economy.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.fedex.com/us"><img alt="FedEx logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/FedEx_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p>FedEx provides customers and businesses worldwide with a broad portfolio of transportation, e-commerce and business services. We offer integrated business applications through operating companies competing collectively and managed collaboratively, under the respected FedEx brand. Consistently ranked among the world's most admired and trusted employers, FedEx inspires its more than 300,000 employees to remain absolutely, positively focused on safety, the highest ethical and professional standards and the needs of their customers and communities.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.flagstaffchamber.com"><img alt="Flagstaff Chamber of Commerce logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Flagstaff_Chamber_of_Commerce_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p>An independent, non-profit organization financed by its members to promote business &amp; advocate on their behalf (Not a government agency or part of the City of Flagstaff). The Flagstaff Chamber of Commerce is more than 120 years old, having been founded in 1891 as the Board of Trade. It formally incorporated as an official Chamber of Commerce in 1949. It is a community problem solver that promotes Flagstaff community and its total economy. The Chamber knows that a great climate for businesses and organizations is not automatic and that their interests must be encouraged and promoted. The Chamber is more than 1,000 members strong. The vast majority of our members are small businesses employing fewer than 10 people.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ups.com"><img alt="UPS logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/UPS_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p>Founded in 1907 as a messenger company in the United States, UPS has grown into a multi-billion-dollar corporation by clearly focusing on the goal of enabling commerce around the globe. Today, UPS is a global company with one of the most recognized and admired brands in the world. We have become the world's largest package delivery company and a leading global provider of specialized transportation and logistics services. Every day, we manage the flow of goods, funds, and information in more than 200 countries and territories worldwide.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.sba.gov"><img alt="U.S. Small Business Administration logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/U.S._Small_Business_Administration_logo.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p>The U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA) was created in 1953 as an independent agency of the federal government to aid, counsel, assist and protect the interests of small business concerns, to preserve free competitive enterprise and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of our nation. We recognize that small business is critical to our economic recovery and strength, to building America's future, and to helping the United States compete in today's global marketplace. Although SBA has grown and evolved in the years since it was established in 1953, the bottom line mission remains the same. The SBA helps Americans start, build and grow businesses. Through an extensive network of field offices and partnerships with public and private organizations, SBA delivers its services to people throughout the United States, Puerto Rico, the U. S. Virgin Islands and Guam.</p></td></tr></tbody></table><font color="#000000" face="verdana"><span style="line-height:19.2px;font-size:12px;"><br></span></font><p></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Arizona U.S. Export Assistance Centers Strategic Partnership Program</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about how Arizona's U.S. Export Assistance Centers are is leveraging partnerships with trade associations and private corporations through the Strategic Partnership Program.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Arizona, strategic, partnership</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/215.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/U.S.%20Commercial%20Service%20logo.jpg" name="U"/>
      <image src="/Files/Arizona_Commerce_Authority_logo.jpg" name="Arizona_Commerce_Authority_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/ASU_SkySong_logo.jpg" name="ASU_SkySong_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/FedEx_logo.jpg" name="FedEx_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/Flagstaff_Chamber_of_Commerce_logo.jpg" name="Flagstaff_Chamber_of_Commerce_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/UPS_logo.jpg" name="UPS_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/U.S._Small_Business_Administration_logo.jpg" name="U"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/215.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/215.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
