<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>219</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Arkansas U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internship Opportunites - Arkansas USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities with the Arkansas U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/14/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/13/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​The U.S. Commercial Service in Little Rock, Arkansas offers internship opportunities throughout the year.</p><p>Interns will focus on the following types of assistance and support to Arkansas companies, under the direction of theU.S. Commercial Staff:</p><ul><li><p>​Identify appropriate market research and develop research databases of various industries in support of Arkansas' business export strategies</p></li><li><p>Review incoming business trade service requests, research request eligibility, &amp; follow-up when appropriate with qualified Arkansas businesses</p></li><li><p>Assist in the organization and implementation of export outreach workshops and seminars in Arkansas</p></li><li><p>Assist with development and implementation ofad hocprojects to include trade shows, expos, webinars and other trade related activities</p></li></ul><h2>Eligibility</h2><p>In order to participate in this program you must meet the following qualifications:</p><ul><li><p>U.S. Citizen</p></li><li><p>Enrollment in a college or university</p></li><li><p>Availability fora minimum of 3 months, with optional continuation</p></li><li><p>Good communication and computer skills</p></li></ul><p>Students of Business, International Relations, Economics, and Languages will benefit most from an internship at the U.S. Commercial Service.</p><h2>Payment Information</h2><p>The internship is avolunteer (non-paid) service. Federal regulations prohibit financial compensation. An official letter of recommendation will be provided upon successful completion of internship. University credit may also be available.</p><h2>Apply</h2><p>Interested applicants should send a cover letter and resume to the attention of James Bledsoe, International Trade Specialist, to the USEAC office via E-mail:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:james.bledsoe@trade.gov">james.bledsoe@trade.gov</a>​.​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Arkansas U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities with the Arkansas U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Arkansas, internship</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/219.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/219.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/219.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
