<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>233</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Baltimore U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Interships - Baltimore USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internships with the Baltimore U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/14/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​​The U.S. Commercial Service Internship Experience</h2><p>Are you interested in working in a dynamic, fast-paced environment full of challenge? How about sharpening your job skills while building your resume? Or perhaps you would like to compliment your academic expertise with international business training? If this sounds interesting, don't miss out on an opportunity to help U.S. companies engage the international marketplace!</p><p>As part of the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. Commercial Service is the premier federal agency that helps companies to achieve exporting success. Our office in Downtown Baltimore is part of a global network of more than 100 domestic offices and 150 international offices. We assist U.S. companies with entering international markets and with increasing export sales and market share by providing market research, introducing foreign buyers to U.S. exporters, and advocating on behalf of American business interests in more than 85 countries worldwide!</p><h2>What is the work environment?</h2><p>We are a team of highly motivated professionals with a range of international business expertise. We are responsible for providing high-value advice and guidance to companies making strategic business decisions. These decisions typically involve evaluating and entering new markets, increasing market share, resolving problems with overseas customers, financing export sales, product licensing, and selecting a distributor who will increase their company's sales. Because we know how much vital these decisions are, and that the market never sleeps, we emphasize accuracy and speed.</p><h2>What can you expect from this internship?</h2><p>U.S. Commercial Service's Baltimore office serves the entire state of Maryland. Our internship program is designed to provide real world experience to compliment academic lessons in international trade, international business, economics, and international affairs.</p><p>Through hands-on experience, interns will come to have a solid understanding of:</p><ul><li>Problems confronting small to medium sized companies in the international marketplace</li><li>Role of international trade in a regional economy</li><li>Problems that confront policy makers as they attempt to open international markets for U.S. products</li></ul><p>As part of the internship program, interns work closely with International Trade Specialists. Interns help to develop and prepare market research, match local companies with international opportunities, and answer export related questions from a wide variety of sources. Additionally, interns will also have the chance to work on special projects.</p><p>Interns have the opportunity to plan, recruit for, and host seminars that feature government officials, visiting overseas staff, and market and industry specialists from Washington D.C. Interns schedule appointments for the visiting staff and accompany the visitors to the meetings to provide assistance. Interns are often given the responsibility of representing our office in a variety of venues. We believe in giving interns responsibility for projects and mentoring them as they develop.</p><p>Though the internship is unpaid, the valuable experience gained during the program can prove to be very beneficial in the future, especially if the intern is interested in working for the federal government. If you are seeking paid Federal employment, please visit<a href="http://www.usajobs.opm.gov/">http://www.usajobs.opm.gov</a>​for a complete listing of job announcements.</p><h2>Qualities We Look For In An Intern</h2><ul><li>Strong interest in professional experience to compliment academic background</li><li>Solid analytical skills</li><li>Self-motivation and professionalism</li><li>Strong communication and interpersonal skills</li></ul><h2>Eligibility Requirements</h2><ul><li>You must be a U.S. citizen.</li><li>You must be at least a half-time student pursuing a bachelors or graduate degree.</li><li>You must be able to work 16 hours a week minimum during the fall/spring terms and 24 hours a week minimum during our summer term</li></ul><p>If you are a student interested in pursuing an internship with us and meet the eligibility requirements, please email your resume and cover letter to Paul Matino at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Paul.Matino@trade.gov">Paul.Matino@trade.gov</a>.<br></p><p>For more information, please contact:</p><p>Paul Matino, International Trade Specialist<br>U.S. Export Assistance Center Baltimore<br>300 West Pratt Street, Suite 300<br>Baltimore, MD 21201<br>Telephone: 410-962-4581<br>E-mail:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Paul.Matino@trade.gov">Paul.Matino@trade.gov</a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Baltimore U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internships with the Baltimore U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, internship, Baltimore, Maryland</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/233.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/233.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/233.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
