<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>237</id>
    <title>Idaho District Export Council Members</title>
    <short_title>Idaho District Export Council Members</short_title>
    <summary>Meet the members of the Idaho District Export Council.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​​​​Kirk Adams</h2><p>Kirk cuparrently works as aWorldwide Account Manager forFedex Services. Hehas 24 years experience in the transportation industry from operations to sales. Industry segments include truckload, LTL, small package Express and Ground as well as International Import and Export. Most recently his focus has been on Fortune 100 companies with regards to how their joint ventures and mergers will effect their Supply chain decisions. In the past he has worked with small startup companies and helped them set up Supply chains that were responsive to their needs and growth strategies.</p><h2>Joe Anderson - Commercial Lines Account Executive, Western States Insurance Agency</h2><p>Joe Anderson currently works as a Commercial Lines Account Executive with Western States Insurance Agency in Boise. He has two clientele goals: to minimize corporate business risk and to make companies more attractive to the insurance marketplace. The natural result of these goals is a large reduction in his clients Total Cost of Risk (TCR). TCR includes worker productivity down-time, claims, loss of experience, reputation and future opportunities due to non-core risks in the workplace. Other results include lower costs for insurance, better coverage, and a more profitable operation.</p><p>Mr. Anderson began his insurance career with Marsh of Boise in 2001 and quickly built up a sizable group of clients with a focus on growth companies, and industry niches of real estate, commercial agriculture, international business, and hard-to-place product liability risks. He has reviewed worldwide contracts for insurability, and property and liability exposures for one of the largest construction firms in the Northwest. He has also worked with exporters to secure their products and payments, as well as cover their liability exposures overseas.</p><p>He holds Accounting and finance degree from Pacific Lutheran in Tacoma and is a graduate of the Hartford School of Insurance and Leadership Idaho Agriculture. Mr. Anderson co-founded the BNI chapter Treasure Vally Accelerators. Joe currently is a member of the Meridian Chamber of Commerce, the Meridian Kiwanis, Idaho Affordable Housing Association, Building Owners and Managers Association. He is also a federally-appointed member of the Idaho District Export Council.</p><p>Joe can be reached at his Boise office at 208-383-6876 or by e-mail at<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.export.gov/idaho/idahodistrictexportcouncil/janderson@wsi-insurance.com">janderson@wsi-insurance.com</a></p><h2>Vince Brascia - DEC Vice Chairman</h2><p>Vince Brascia (<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:vdbrascia@micron.com">vdbrascia@micron.com</a>) is currently a Compliance Specialist at Micron Technology, Inc. Vince has 30 years of transportation experience. Prior to employment with Micron in 1998, Vince was the Import Manager of an international freight forwarder's San Francisco branch. Vince is a Licensed Customhouse Broker, and he has worked in the Ports of Reno, Atlanta, and San Francisco. In 1981, Vince received a B.S. in Management, specializing in International Finance, from the University of Nevada at Reno.</p><h2>Pat Collins</h2><p>Patrick Collins has over20 years of experience in foreign trade. A graduate of the University of Idaho and the American Graduate School of International Management (Thunderbird).In addition to aregulatory background, including extensive dealings with the U.S. Department of Commerce and U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Patrick is experienced in the application of terms of sale/Incoterms in foreign contracts, foreign market access and transportation. Patrick lives in Boise with his wife and two children.</p><h2>Gary DeGrange</h2><p>Gary DeGrance (<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:gary.degrange@usbank.com">gary.degrange@usbank.com</a>) is a Vice President with U.S. Bank's Global Trade Services Department in Boise. He has over twenty-seven years of international banking experience with an emphasis on international trade finance. His territory includes Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Utah, Colorado, Wyoming and Southern Texas where he assists companies both large and small with their international banking needs. DeGrange is a frequent speaker at public forums and college courses and enjoys sharing his knowledge of international business.</p><h2>Ying Donegan</h2><p>Ying is the owner of 7E International Enterprises, a consulting firm specializing in doing business with China. She is also a consultant on how to do business successfully in China, manufacturing operation set-up, supply chain analysis and manufacturing outsourcing as well as marketing for American business in China. Working together with her business partners in China, Ying helped many businesses reduce their costs and improved their time to bring new products to markets.</p><p>Before starting her own business, Ying worked for eight years in the US, in computer peripherals, telecommunications and commercial product industries. Before she came to the US, Ying worked in a household electronics company in China for two years, working with leading international companies to introduce new technologies to China and setting up joint ventures. Her most recent employment experience was with Hewlett-Packard as a Systems Management Engineer. She worked with HP's worldwide manufacturing centers and contract manufacturers for new product introduction, quality improvement, cost saving and distribution of LaserJet products.</p><p>Ying was educated in both America and China. She holds a Masters Degree in Industrial Engineering from Purdue University, a M.B.A. and a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering from University of Shanghai for Science &amp; Technology, China. She also studied in Germany for a year and enhanced her international experience.</p><h2>James Hogge</h2><p>James is an Idaho native. James obtained a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemistry from the College of Idaho in 1971, a Masters of Business Administration degree from the University of West Florida in 1991, and a degree in accounting from Boise State University in May 1993.</p><p>Before joining the Boise State University staff, Jim completed a military career, retiring from the U. S. Air Force in 1991. The majority of his career was devoted to flying. He flew the F-111 for over 10 years. The remainder of his career was focused on the development and testing of new aircraft systems.</p><p>James Hogge has been with the Idaho Small Business Development Center since 1992. He has served as the State Director of the Idaho Small Business Development Center since July 1995. Idaho Small Business Development Center provides high quality consulting and training services to improve the success of entrepreneurs in Idaho by using the combined resources of the Idaho SBDC, the private/public sector, and Idaho's colleges and universities.</p><p>James also helped start the TechHelp program for Idaho manfacturers, the TechConnect Program for high entrepreneurs, and the TECenter at Boise State University.</p><h2>Jason Prince - DEC Chairman</h2><p>Jason Prince is an attorney with Stoel Rives LLP, a full-service U.S. business law firm, where he represents and counsels exporting businesses on international commercial transactions and dispute resolution, as well as compliance with the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act and the Export Administration Regulations. Mr. Prince holds a bachelor's degree from Davidson College, a master's degree from the University of Cambridge, and a law degree from the University of Notre Dame Law School. Prior to law school, Mr. Prince lived in Tokyo, Japan, working as Deputy Press Secretary to Nobuteru Ishihara, Member of the Japanese House of Representatives and Japan's Minister of State for Administrative and Regulatory Reform. Before joining Stoel Rives, he clerked for Judge Susan H. Black on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Eleventh Circuit.</p><h2>James Corpstein-DEC Treasurer</h2><p>James Corpstein is the Import/Export Compliance Managerat the J.R. SimplotCompany, focusing on import and export coordination and regulatory compliance. He holds a degree in International Business Administration from Boise State University, and is a Licensed Customs Broker, certified through U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</p><p>James has a background in the semiconductor industry, working for the Transportation and Logistics Department at Micron Technology for several years. Most recently he was a Traffic Manager at Nunhems USA, Inc., a subsidiary of Bayer Crop Science, coordinating domestic and international movements of agricultural products.</p><h2>Ed Meyer</h2><p>Ed Meyer is the President for Meyer Industries who manufactures the Rodenator line of burrowing pest control products. As an Idaho Entrepreneur, Ed has been exporting the Rodenator product line since 2003, winning awards such as the U.S. Commerce Department's Export Achievement Certificate in 2006, the U.S. Small Business Administration's (SBA) Small Business Exporter of the year in 2007, the Stoel Rives Innovation Award for Agriculture and Environmental in 2007, and the Commercial News USA Exporter of the Year Award for Agricultural Category in 2009. As a member of the Idaho Direct Export Council, Ed enjoys helping other Idaho companies learn how to export their products to a world market. Aside from running a manufacturing business, Ed is also the current Mayor of Midvale, Idaho.</p><h2>David Christensen​</h2><p>David Christensen joined Boise State University as an adjunct professor in 1994. He currently teaches courses in global business management and exporting and importing procedures in the College of Business and Economics, as well as various regional history and Canadian Studies courses in the College of Social Sciences and Public Affairs.</p><p>In 1997, David was on the Advisory Board of the Boise-based Spur Products Company. As well as on the Advisory Board for the Boise-based Sloan Security Fencing Company from 2008 to present. From 1990-1997, David served as an administrator for the Division of International Business at the Idaho Department of Commerce, responsible for the state's efforts to assist small and medium sized companies expand Idaho exports around the world. Furthermore he has been the recipient of the U.S. Presidential &quot;E&quot; Award for excellence in export services and the &quot;Governor of Idaho's Export Award for Outstanding Service&quot; in 1997 and 2002.</p><p>For 25 years David also worked as a Foreign Service Officer with the U.S. Department of State with assignments in Africa, Asia, Australia and Europe. David holds a B.S. degree in geology from the Mackay School of Mines, University of Nevada; an M.A. from the University of Nevada; and post graduate work in African Studies at Stanford University. David Christensen is an active member of the Idaho Export Council since 1989.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Idaho District Export Council Members</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Meet the members of the Idaho District Export Council.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, Idaho, district, council</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/237.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/237.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/237.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
