<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>238</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Idaho U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internship Opportunities - Idaho USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about intership opportunities with the Idaho U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​<span style="line-height:1.6;">​The U.S. Commercial Service is proud to be able to offer students fall and spring semester internship programs to gain invaluable practical business experience in the field of international trade. A keen ability to understand the international business environment and global geography is essential.</span></p><p>The U.S. Commercial Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce is a federal government agency dedicated to helping small-to-medium sized Idaho businesses realize their export potential. The U.S. Export Assistance Centers located in Boise is part of an international network of global professionals. The organization has 158 offices in 80 countries throughout the world.</p><p>As an International Trade Intern, you will assist the U.S. Commercial Service by completing international market research projects; learn to use various commercial databases, assist with coordination of international trade events as well as perform other light clerical and administrative support duties. The International Trade Intern also provides support to the Idaho District Export Council, a business advisory group of executives from over twenty-five organizations.</p><p>International Trade Interns are chosen through a highly selective process. It is imperative that one is able to communicate in a professional environment, be enthusiastic, and willing to learn. Foreign travel, international studies, and multiple language capabilities add an important dimension to applicants.</p><p>Internships at the Boise U.S. Export Assistance Centers are typically one academic semester in length (i.e., three-to-four months) and are unpaid. Full academic year interns are also welcome. If supported by your University, students can choose to take the internship for credit.</p><h2>Internship Eligibility:</h2><p>Those interested in the intern position must be American citizens, be currently enrolled in a college or university and able to pass a federal background check.</p><h2>Major Areas of Study:</h2><p>All Business, Economics, Political Science, Public Administration, Law, International Relations, Marketing, Foreign Language, Communications, Geography, and History.</p><h2>For Questions and How to Apply:</h2><p>Please send a resume and cover letter to Amy Benson at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Amy.Benson@trade.gov">Amy.Benson@trade.gov</a>or visit<a href="http://www.export.gov/idaho">http://www.export.gov/idaho</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Idaho U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about intership opportunities with the Idaho U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, Idaho, internship</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/238.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/238.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/238.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
