<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>241</id>
    <title>Military Internship Opportunities - Connecticut U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Military Internships - Connecticut USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about military internship opportunities available with the Connecticut U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/16/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Connecticut_internships.jpg" alt="Seals for the American military branches - Air Force, Army, Coast Guard, Navy, and Marine Corps" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><p>The Commercial Service has a limited number of unpaid student internships available throughout the country for active and transitioning military considering careers in international business. Only U.S. citizens are eligible for consideration. Applicants must be enrolled no less than half-time in an accredited college or university.</p><h2>Eligibility:</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">​Must be U.S. citizens, students must be enrolled at least part-time in a college or university.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Military personnel must be on active duty or transitioning.</span><br></li></ul><p></p><h2>Required Skills:</h2><p>Proficient typing skills, data entry skills; Proficiency in Microsoft Office Suite and Lotus Notes; Proficient internet skills using Microsoft Internet Explorer, knowledge in information retrieval, search engines and cut/paste skills; and basic telephone etiquette skills, fax knowledge, and e-mail proficiency.</p><h2>Responsibilities:</h2><p>Throughout the internship the student will conduct a host of duties that range from responding to telephone inquiries concerning international trade to international market research. The value of the internship is centered on the research that the student will perform for the Middletown office staff. Students will research manufacturing and service companies to determine the extent of their international activities, assist companies in locating foreign agents and distributors for their products and services, and pursue foreign sales leads provided by commercial officers at U.S. Embassies abroad.</p><h2>Interns will assist trade specialists:<br></h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Conducting world class market research.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">With trade events that promote products or services to qualified buyers.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Introduce qualified buyers and distributors.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Provide counseling and advocacy through every step of the export process.</span><br></li></ul><p></p><h2>Benefits:<br></h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">I</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">nterns will also have the opportunity to work on individual projects. Such projects may include recruiting for Foreign Trade Delegations and Trade Shows, and organizing Foreign Buyer Programs, taking part in trade development meetings with American and foreign government officials and executives in key industries, writing on international trade and regulatory issues involving trade negotiations, and promoting industry trade events to the international community.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Learn more about commerce and U.S. Agencies.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Apply classroom theory to real work situations. (May be worth college credits)​</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Become more knowledgeable about general work functions in business fields.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Identify and/or test interests and talents.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Investigate organizational cultures.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Learn career-related skills.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Identify transferable skills.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Strengthen written and oral skills.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">See if a selected career path is one you truly wish to travel.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Find out what it's like to work in a business environment.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Enhance and strengthen your resume.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Make contacts to gain future employment (Build your Network!).</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Bridge between college and work.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Stimulate new interest in academic course work and frequently develop an interdisciplinary perspective.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Gain an increased awareness of skills, attributes, personal qualities and values.</span><br></li></ul><p></p><h2>Duration of Internship:</h2><p>Internships are usually for a period of three months and can be extended. The internship is a voluntary effort. No funds are available to cover any costs incurred during this internship. We request that an intern have at least24 hours per week to dedicate to the internship.</p><p>Email your resume and completed applicationto Melissa Grosso at:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:melissa.grosso@trade.gov">melissa.grosso@N0SPAM.trade.gov</a>.</p><p>For more information call (860)638-6950.</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;text-decoration:underline;">Intern Application (Microsoft Word, 319KB)</span><br></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Military Internship Opportunities - Connecticut U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about military internship opportunities available with the Connecticut U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, internship, Connecticut</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/241.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Connecticut_internships.jpg" name="Connecticut_internships"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/241.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/241.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
