<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>245</id>
    <title>Export Finance Resources in Massachusetts</title>
    <short_title>Export Finance - Massachusetts</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about financial resources available to exporters in Massachusetts.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/16/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/16/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">B</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">ecome familiar with the various government programs designed to help your company finance its export transactions, and give it the capital to carry out its export operation</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">.</span></p><p>We recommend that you review this information and then contact your local Commercial Service Trade Specialists to discuss how these programs can help you achieve your international sales goals.</p><h2>​Financing</h2><p>Do you need working capital loans? Does your foreign buyer need financing to buy your products? Do they prefer lease financing? Check out the U.S. Government International Financing Programs.</p><h2>Insurance</h2><p>The U.S. Government offers U.S. companies Insurance and Risk Mitigation policies that cover export transactions and for overseas investments. Coverage includes losses for non-payment, currency inconvertibility, asset expropriation and political violence.</p><h2>Grants</h2><p>The U.S. Government provides grants to U.S. firms to conduct feasibility studies on infrastructure projects and to train the foreign business community and government officials on U.S. business practices, regulatory reform and other economic development activities.</p><p><br></p><h2 style="text-align:center;">To better serve our clients, we work closely with the following export finance partners:</h2><h3>Small Business Administration</h3><p>The U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA) was created in 1953 as an independent agency of the federal government to aid, counsel, assist and protect the interests of small business concerns, to preserve free competitive enterprise and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of our nation. Although SBA has grown and evolved in the years since it was established in 1953, the bottom line mission remains the same. The SBA helps Americans start, build and grow businesses.</p><p>The mission of SBA's Office of International Trade is to enhance the ability ofsmallbusinesses to compete in the global marketplace; facilitate access to capital to supportinternational trade; ensure that the interests of small business are considered and reflected in trade negotiations; and support and contribute to the U.S. Government's international agenda.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/aboutsba/sbaprograms/internationaltrade/index.html">I want to learn more about SBA's export finance programs</a></li></ul><p><strong><em>For more information, contact:</em></strong></p><p><strong>Mr. John Joyce</strong><br>SBA Export Trade Finance Manager<br>JFK Federal Building<br>55 New Sudbury Street, Suite 1826A<br>Boston, MA 02203<br>Phone: (617) 565-4305<br>Fax: (617) 565-4313</p><p><br></p><h3>Export-Import Bank of the United States</h3><p>​The Export-Import Bank of the United States (Ex-Im Bank) is the official export credit agency of the United States. Ex-Im Bank's mission is to assist in financing the export of U.S. goods and services to international markets. The New England regional office is located in New York.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.exim.gov/products/index.cfm">I want to learn more about Ex-Im Bank's services and policies</a>​</li></ul><p><strong><em>For more information, contact:</em></strong></p><p><strong>Mr. Bruce Drossman</strong><br>Business Development Officer​<br>Export Import Bank of the United States<br>33 Whitehall Street, 22nd Floor<br>New York, NY 10004<br>Phone: (212) 809-2651<br>Fax: (212) 809-2687<br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
        <topic>Trade Finance</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Export Finance Resources in Massachusetts</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about financial resources available to exporters in Massachusetts.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, financial, Massachusetts</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/245.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/245.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/245.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
