<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>250</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Indiana USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities with the Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/17/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/17/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​Are you ready to:</h2><p>Interact with top-level executives across a variety of industries?</p><p>Collaborate with colleagues located around the world?</p><p>Learn how public and private sectors work together to promote international trade?</p><p>Join the dynamic environment of international business as an intern with our office in Indianapolis!</p><p>Previous interns have moved on to work in a variety of capacities at both public and private institutions such as:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">U.S. Department of Commerce Headquarters</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Monarch Beverage</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Indiana University</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Roche</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Japan Exchange and Teaching Program</span><br></li></ul><p>Others have chosen to continue learning at higher education institutions around the world including the Monterey Institute of International Studies and the University College of London.</p><p><br></p><h2>Responsibilities:</h2><p>Based on your interests and goals, along with the current needs of the office,you will have the opportunity to work on a variety of tasks and projectsto help improve and support:</p><p></p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Congressional Outreach</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Marketing and Networking</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Cross Agency Coordination</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Event Management</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Industry and Market Research</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Social Media Management</span></li></ul><span style="line-height:20.7999992370605px;"><br></span><p></p><h2>Requirements:</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">U.S. Citizenship</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Undergraduate junior or senior enrolled in an Accredited University</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Ability to accept unpaid position – flexible hours available</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Interest in international marketing, sales, or law Organized &amp; efficient worker</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Ability to learn new programs quickly</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Strong research skills</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Demonstrates consistent professionalism</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Creativity, Initiative, &amp; Drive</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Must pass background check</span><br></li></ul><span style="line-height:20.7999992370605px;"><br></span><h2>Major Areas of Study:</h2><p>We welcome students from diverse academic backgrounds, and encourage those focused on Business, Economics, Political Science, Public Policy &amp; Administration, International Relations, International Business, Marketing, Communications, Sociology, Geography, and History to apply.</p><p><br></p><h2>Quotes fromPrevious Interns</h2><p>&quot;Whether looking to enter the Federal Government or business arena, an internship with the Indianapolis Export Assistance Center will provide you with valuable experience. Its staff offers years of experience and personal mentoring on international trade issues ensuring that you will gain the most from the very real responsibilities you are given. Helping clients identify and develop new markets for their products or navigate the complexities of rules of origin and the harmonized tariff schedule, you will personally make a tangible difference for Indiana businesses. The skills developed and connections made through an internship with the U.S. Commercial Service in Indianapolis will be invaluable to your future endeavors.&quot;</p><ul><li>Horn, Fall 2012</li></ul><p>&quot;Although I did not go into the field of international economics and trade, the skills gained during my internship at the Export Assistance Center in Indianapolis, such as professional communication, market research, professional etiquette and networking, were invaluable and transferable across industry lines. I have been able to apply what I learned during my internship to my current role at Indiana University&quot;.</p><ul><li>Hayes, Summer 2011</li></ul><br><h2>Forother internship opportunities withthe U.S. Commerce Dept. and other government agencies, please visit these sites:</h2><p><a href="http://www.commerce.gov/about-commerce/careers">http://www.commerce.gov/about-commerce/careers</a></p><p><a href="http://www.usajobs.gov/">http://www.usajobs.gov/</a>- Search 'internship'</p><p><br></p><h2>To Apply:</h2><p><strong>Email resume &amp; cover letter to:</strong></p><p>Mark Cooper, Director, U.S. Commercial Service in Indiana,<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Mark.Cooper@trade.gov">Mark.Cooper@trade.gov</a>.</p><p><em>Applicants desiring university credit for their Internship should apply 8 weeks before their intended start date to allow for adequate processing time. Applications submitted without a cover letter will not be considered. Additional materials such as work samples and references are welcome.</em></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities with the Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, internship, Indiana</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/250.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/250.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/250.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
