<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>252</id>
    <title>Welcome to the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Illinois USEAC Homepage</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/18/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/17/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">​<strong style="line-height:1.6;text-align:center;">​&quot;10 Things Commerce Secretary Wants Business Owners To Know&quot;</strong></p><p style="text-align:center;">&quot;The Commerce Department's Gold Key Matching Service helps businesses export their products. For a modest amount of money, we will examine your business, tell you where your product is competitive (overseas) and introduce you to the appropriate people so you can bring your product to that country.&quot;<a href="http://www.chicagobusiness.com/article/20131107/NEWS02/131109848/10-things-penny-pritzker-wants-business-owners-to-know">Read the entire Crain's Chicago Business, Nov 7, 2013 article of Secretary Penny Pritzker's speech</a>.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Illinois_homepage.jpg" alt="Photo of the staff of the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Centers with Commerce Secretary Penny Pritzker" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p style="text-align:center;">From left to right – Julie Carducci, Marianne Drain, Debra Rogers, Mary Joyce (Center – Commerce Secretary Penny Pritzker), Christian Koschil, Megan Schildgen, Michael Marangell and Neil Pickett. Staff not pictured: Patrick Hope, Haley Pitonyak, Shari Stout, Vicki Tolefree and Monica Toporkiewicz</p><h2>Client Testimonials:</h2><p>&quot;The service we provide is quite complex, and because of this I did not know what to expect from the Gold Key Service. I was in for a surprise! The Commercial Service quickly understood what Regis did, and assembled a very complete list of potential companies to meet during my trip to Israel. These meetings were incredibly challenging for me, but the Commercial Service was there helping me all the way. The follow up report to the visit alone was worth thousands of dollars to Regis and illustrated the potential for yet another trip to Israel.&quot;<em>Regis Technologies, Paul Flynn, Business Development Manager</em></p><p style="text-align:center;">To View More Client Testimonials – Click here to <a href="http://www.export.gov/illinois/eg_us_il_046505.asp">view</a><br>Video of Client Testimonials – Click here to<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hkwFsOyHKVU">view​</a></p><h2>Commercial Service– Who We Are</h2><p>The U.S. Commercial Service is the trade promotion agency of the U.S. Department of Commerce and provides export assistance to U.S. exporters. Our Trade Specialists work with your company to help you increase your sales to new global markets. We operate in 108 U.S. cities and nearly 80 countries.</p><h2>Our Support for U.S. Exporters Includes:</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Introductions to qualified buyers and distributors</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Counseling and advocacy through every step of the export process</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">World class market research</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Trade events that promote your product or service to qualified buyers and distributors</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">For every $1 in federal funding our agency receives, we help create $215 in exports</span><br></li></ul><h2>Export Assistance in Illinois:</h2><p>Our three Illinois offices are committed to assisting Illinois firms in realizing their export potential. We provide export counseling and advice, information on markets abroad, international partner contacts and advocacy services. During 2012-2013, this assistance resulted in 1466 export successes for small and medium businesses, generating nearly 467 million dollars in export sales for the Illinois economy.</p><p>Take the first step into finding new markets! Contact your local<a href="http://www.export.gov/illinois/contactus/eg_us_il_023117.asp">Trade Specialist</a>who can help increase your export sales.</p><p>U.S. Commercial Service Illinois Offices:</p><ul style="list-style-type:square;"><li>Chicago, Peoria and Rockford</li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Welcome to the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Illinois</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/252.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Illinois_homepage.jpg" name="Illinois_homepage"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/252.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/252.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
