<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>259</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Illinois USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities at the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/18/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align:center;">​​​U.S. Department of Commerce International Trade Internship</h2><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>**Accepting applications forFall/Winter/Spring terms 2014/2015**</strong></p><p><strong>&quot;</strong>In retrospect, I can't think of a better way to have spent my semester. This was an incredible learning opportunity for me, to better understand international trade and get an insider's look at exporting. That's only half of it, however; I so thoroughly enjoyed my time with the Commercial Service because I got to work with all of the you. Your patience, humor, and strong work ethic made this experience feel less like an internship and more like an incredible learning opportunity among supportive friends. Thank you!&quot;<strong>--</strong><em>Feedback from Fall 2011 intern</em></p><p>The U.S. Commercial Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce is a federal government agency dedicated to helping small-to-medium sized U.S. companies with their exporting strategies. For over 25 years the U.S. Commercial Service has successfully brought together exporters of U.S. goods and services with importers from around the world. Our team of more than 1,300 trade professionals in 100+ U.S. cities and 80+ U.S. Embassies around the world is here to help companies navigate the complex world of international trade so they can start exporting or increase sales to new global markets.</p><p>The U.S. Department of Commerce Commercial Service Chicago office offers internships that allow students to spend time on the inside track of international business and gain real world experience that can provide an essential edge for entering today's job market. Participants will learn to answer inquiries from exporters regarding trade requirements, regulations, documentation, country issues and commodity classifications; contact exporters to determine interest in overseas trade shows, export leads, seminars and other trade activities; and utilize federal government databases, trade journals and internet based market research to disseminate information to exporting companies.</p><h2>Daily Job Activities:</h2><p>International Trade Interns become involved in the daily operational aspects of managing a high activity office. Projects range from coordinating market research to counseling U.S. companies seeking new international trade partners. Interns will be required to support our International Trade Specialists with development of trade seminars, presentations and other projects, as well as assist walk-in visitors, handle telephone calls, light clerical and administrative support duties.</p><h2>Internship Eligibility:</h2><p>Students interested in the position must be a U.S. Citizen or U.S. National (copy of your Naturalization certificate is required prior to starting) and be currently enrolled in a college or university at least part-time. Seeking self-starters with excellent writing, communication and multi-tasking skills who are comfortable working in a professional office environment and willing to learn. Part-time (minimum 20 hours per week) and full-time positions available. Internship is UNPAID, but experience is priceless!</p><p>Students interested in the position must be a U.S. Citizen or U.S. National (copy of your Naturalization certificate is required prior to starting) and be currently enrolled in a college or university at least part-time<strong>as an undergraduate junior or </strong><strong>senior.</strong>Seeking self-starters with excellent writing, communication and multi-tasking skills, who are comfortable working in a professional office environment and willing to learn. Part-time (minimum 25 hours per week) and full-time positions available. Internship is UNPAID, but experience is priceless!</p><h2>Major Areas of Study:</h2><p>All Business majors, Economics, Political Science, Public Policy &amp; Administration, International Relations, International Business, Marketing, Foreign Language, Communications, Sociology, Geography and History students are encouraged to apply.</p><h3 style="text-align:center;">**University Credit Available**</h3><h2>To Apply:</h2><p>Start/end dates are negotiable with each student (minimum 20 hours/week and 3 month duration preferred). A comprehensive background check and fingerprints are required by Commerce security office once intern is selected. Process can take up to 1 month, please apply early to allow for processing time. Send your resume, writing sample on any topic (no more than 5 pages) and introductory cover letter stating what you have to offer and how you hope to benefit from the internship. Indicate current year in school, major, areas of interest and available time commitment (daily hours and start/e​nd dates). If you would like to contact a former intern and ask about their experience working in our office, please mention in cover letter, we will be happy to provide their contact information. Click here to view bios of past Chicago <a href="http://www.export.gov/illinois/internshipprogram/eg_us_il_024892.asp">interns</a>.</p><p>Please forward documents to the attention International Trade Specialist Monica Toporkiewicz at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Monica.toporkiewicz@trade.gov">Monica.toporkiewicz@trade.gov</a>. Questions, call Monica at 312-353-8059.</p><h2>Forother internship opportunities withthe U.S. Commerce Dept. and other government agencies, please visit these sites:</h2><p><a href="http://www.commerce.gov/about-commerce/careers">http://www.commerce.gov/about-commerce/careers</a></p><p><a href="http://www.usajobs.gov/">http://www.usajobs.gov/</a>- Search 'internship'​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities at the Illinois U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internship, Illinois</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/259.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/259.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/259.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
