<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>261</id>
    <title>International Buyers Program Select</title>
    <short_title>IBP Select</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the International Buyer Program Select option that focuses on trade opportunities in five international markets.</summary>
    <creation_date>4/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/19/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>IBP Select Program</h1><p>To support more U.S. trade shows, the International Buyer Program has a service called IBP Select. Like the regular IBP service, the core value proposition of IBP Select is that our global network recruits pre-screened international buyers to U.S. trade shows to meet with U.S suppliers exhibiting at those shows. The main difference between IBP and IBP Select is that IBP offers worldwide promotion and recruitment whereas Select focuses on promotion and recruitment in no more than five international markets. </p><h2>What are the differences between IBP and IBP Select?</h2><ul><li>IBP Select Service is a great value for smaller shows (under 1,200 exhibitors), shows that are ready to make the strategic shift and focus on international attendance, and shows that are in niche/specialty sectors. </li><li>IBP Select is essentially the same service as the regular IBP, EXCEPT: </li><ul><li>Recruitment of foreign buyer delegations is limited to 5 delegations.</li><li>Staffing at the venue will be 2 Global Teams members versus 1 IBP Project Officer and 2 Global Teams members. (The IBP Office will still handle all administrative aspects of the IBP, e.g., MOA, cost recovery, etc.)</li><li>The price is $6,000 versus $9,800.</li></ul><li>The show organizer must only provide 500 square feet for the International Business Center versus 900/1,600 square feet.</li><li>IBP-recruited delegates would continue to receive either waived or significantly reduced admission to the event. </li><li>Delegation leaders recruiting a minimum of 10 delegates would be eligible for a complimentary hotel room – hopefully making it easier to lead the delegation to the show. </li></ul><h2>IBP Select shows in 2014</h2><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Graphics of the Americas</span></a><br>February 27-March 1, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">MODEX 2014</span></a><br>March 17-20, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Techtextil North America</span></a> and <a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Texprocess Americas</span></a><br>May 13-15, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">2014 AIA Convention</span></a><br>June 26-28, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Natural Products Expo East</span></a><br>September 17-20, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">SupplySide West</span></a><br>October 6-10, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Irrigation Show and Education Conference</span></a><br>November 19-20, 2014</p><p><a><span style="text-decoration:underline;">52nd Annual National RV Trade Show</span></a><br>December 2-4, 2014</p><h2>2015 International Buyer Program SELECT Now Accepting Applications!</h2><p>The International Trade Administration is now accepting applications for the International Buyer Program SELECT service for trade events taking place between January 1, 2015 through December 31, 2015. Details regarding the application, eligibility, participation requirements, and selection process are provided in the Federal Register Notice below. The deadline for applying to the International Buyer Program SELECT for 2015 events is<strong>Monday</strong>,<strong> May 19, 2014. </strong>Please see the <a href="http://export.gov/ibp/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">IBP Home page</span></a> for more application information.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>International Buyers Program Select</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the International Buyer Program Select option that focuses on trade opportunities in five international markets.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>International Markets, Trade Shows, International Buyers Program</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/261.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/261.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/261.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
