<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>280</id>
    <title>Part 810 Authorization</title>
    <short_title>Part 810 Authorization</short_title>
    <summary>Information on obtaining an 810 Authorization for nuclear trade.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/20/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​Not Rated <br></p><p>Government-to-government assurances obtained by either the Department of State or the Department of Energy are required for the 810 approval and 110 licensing process.</p><p>The assurances for 810 approvals affirm that the recipient government pledges to use the acquired technology exclusively for peaceful purposes and will not re-transfer it to another country without the consent of the supplier-country government.</p><p>The authorization letter for 810 Authorization requires the following information:</p><ul><ul><li>The name, address, and citizenship of the applicant, and complete disclosure of all real parties in interest; if the applicant is a corporation or other legal entity, where it is incorporated or organized, the location of its principal office, and the degree of any control or ownership by any foreign person or entity</li><li>A complete description of the proposed activity, including its approximate monetary value, the name and location of any facility or project involved, the name and address of the person or legal entity for which the activity is to be performed, and a detailed description of any specific project to which the activity relates</li><li>(c) Any information the applicant may wish to provide concerning the factors listed in § 810.10(b)</li><li>Designation of any information considered proprietary whose public disclosure would cause substantial harm to the competitive position of the applicant.</li></ul></ul><h2>How Part 810 Applies</h2><p>Part 810 will apply to your company's ability to bid on a foreign tender if the bidding or pre-bidding process requires releasing business proprietary or export-controlled information. If bidding on a foreign tender does not require your company to release business proprietary or export-controlled information, you do not need 810 Authorization; but to be certain, your company should consult the National Nuclear Security Administration.</p><p>In some instances companies may seek an 810 Authorization before submitting a bid, so as not to run the risk of licensing issues arising after having already won a contract.</p><p>For additional information, please contact:</p><p><strong>Agency:</strong>Department of Energy<br><strong>Name:</strong>Richard Goorevich<br><strong>Address:</strong>Office of International Regimes and Agreements<br>National Nuclear Security Administration<br>1000 Independence Ave, SW<br>Washington, DC 20585<br><strong>Phone:</strong>202-586-0589<br><strong>Email:</strong><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Richard.goorevich@nnsa.doe.gov">Richard.goorevich@nnsa.doe.gov</a></p><p>The Civil Nuclear Export Portal can be viewed as a<a href="http://informationportalprodhttp://informationportalprod/Pages/http://export.gov/build/groups/public/@eg_main/@civnuc/documents/webcontent/eg_main_022098.pdf">Flow Chart (PDF)</a>or in<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.export.gov/civilnuclear/eg_main_022240.asp">Step-By-Step</a>format.</p><h2>More Information:</h2><p>Part 810 refers to the process set forth in 10 Code of Federal Regulations Part 810. Under the authority of section 57.b of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, and in accordance with established procedures, only the Secretary of Energy may authorize, through the Part 810 process, persons to engage, directly or indirectly, in the production of special nuclear material outside the United States. This provision applies to technology transfers and technical assistance to all activities of the nuclear fuel-cycle, including non-power reactors.</p><h2>Related Files</h2><a href="http://informationportalprodhttp://informationportalprod/Pages/http://export.gov/build/groups/public/@eg_main/@civnuc/documents/webcontent/eg_main_022098.pdf">Civil Nuclear Exporter's Guide PDF</a>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Regulations<sub_topic>Export Licenses</sub_topic><sub_topic>Export Control</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Energy &amp; Mining</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Civil Nuclear</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Part 810 Authorization</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Information on obtaining an 810 Authorization for nuclear trade.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>authorization, 810, bidding, foreign tender</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/280.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/280.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/280.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
