<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>289</id>
    <title>International Buyer Program Trade Show Video Series</title>
    <short_title>IBP Trade Show Videos</short_title>
    <summary>Get assistance in making international sales.</summary>
    <creation_date>1/21/2011</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>International Buyer Program Trade Show Video Series</strong></h1><p>The Commercial Service <a href="http://www.export.gov/ibp/eg_main_018009.asp">International Buyer Program</a> Trade Show Video Series is a set of four videos that can assist you in making your international sales. It focuses on some services that you can take advantage of, but also highlights how to take advantage of International Buyer Program trade shows if you are an international buyer. The four videos included in this series are:</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/ibp/eg_main_023158.asp#P7_730">How to Make International Sales without Leaving the U.S.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/ibp/eg_main_023158.asp#P15_1387">How to Make International Sales without Leaving the U.S.: Matchmakers on a Mission</a></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/ibp/eg_main_023158.asp#P23_2177">How to Make International Sales without Leaving the U.S.: Showtime for Showtime</a></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/ibp/eg_main_023158.asp#P32_3049">How to Make the Most of a Buying Trip to a Trade Show in the U.S.</a></li></ul><h2><strong>How to Make International Sales Without Leaving the U.S.</strong></h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ijGAmoGdH8I?rel=0" frameborder="0"></iframe><p>Download Video: <a href="http://trade.gov/videos/trade-show-series-part1.mp4">mp4</a> (47 MB)</p><p>Each year more than 80,000 international buyers attend key trade shows in the U.S. These buyers spend tens of millions of dollars on U.S. made products. Using one of the International Buyer Program participating shows—the National Association of Broadcasters—as a model, this video describes the scope of this business and introduces some of the small U.S. companies that derive a significant chunk of their annual revenues from selling to these buyers through the International Buyer Program.</p><h2>How to Make International Sales Without Leaving the U.S.: Matchmakers on a Mission</h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mg9pKyNUOfU?rel=0" frameborder="0"></iframe><p>Download Video: <a href="http://trade.gov/videos/trade-show-series-part2.mp4">mp4</a> (50 MB)</p><p>Many international buyers and U.S. sellers at these competitively selected U.S. trade shows in the International Buyer Program receive business counseling and other assistance from the U.S. Commercial Service, the trade promotion unit of the Department of Commerce. Broadly described, the Commercial Service excels at business matchmaking: introducing buyers and sellers and creating an atmosphere of trust. In this video at an International Buyer Program event you'll meet the matchmakers and their grateful clients from across the U.S. and the world—all part of the International Buyer Program.</p><h2>How to Make International Sales without Leaving the U.S: Showtime for Showtime</h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/J7ODdhqa7y8?rel=0" frameborder="0"></iframe><p>Download Video: <a href="http://trade.gov/videos/trade-show-series-part3.mp4">mp4</a> (57 MB)</p><p>Showtime is one of the services offered at domestic trade shows by the U.S. Commercial Service as part of the International Buyer Program. U.S. producers exhibiting at the show can introduce their products and services to commercial specialists from U.S. embassies who accompany delegations of buyers from their countries. The specialists then set up meetings on the show floor and contact additional potential buyers when they return to their countries after the show. In this video we meet these specialists, hear from sellers and buyers, and learn about other services including financing that help generate sales. The cost for all this to U.S. exhibitors at the show: nothing.</p><h2>How to Make the Most of a Buying Trip to a Trade Show in the U.S.</h2><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/I1bZS0Oz5ZQ?rel=0" frameborder="0"></iframe><p>Download Video: <a href="http://trade.gov/videos/trade-show-series-part4.mp4">mp4</a> (44 MB)</p><p>For the international buyer, U.S. trade shows can be overwhelming. How can you make the most of your time when visiting trade shows in the International Buyer Program? How can you check out the suppliers before you leave for the U.S.? How can you get a visa? This video presents the stories of buyers from throughout the world who are attracted to U.S. trade shows participating in the International Buyer Program, and the matchmaking assistance of the U.S. government to fill their order books. To confidently access the world's best technology and the world's best prices, watch now.</p><p></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
        <topic>Export Training</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>International Buyer Program</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>International Buyer Program Trade Show Video Series</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Get assistance in making international sales.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Videos, International Sales, International Buyers, Trade Shows</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/289.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/289.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/289.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
