<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>312</id>
    <title>United States-Oman Free Trade Agreement</title>
    <short_title>U.S.-Oman FTA</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the United States-Oman Free Trade Agreement. </summary>
    <creation_date>10/12/2011</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>The United States—Oman Free Trade Agreement</strong></h1><h2><strong>General Information</strong></h2><p>The United States-Oman FTA represents an important tool to foster continued economic engagement with Oman, open opportunities for U.S. farmers, manufacturers and services providers, and improve economic ties with a key U.S. ally. The FTA went into force on January 1, 2009.</p><p>The FTA between the United States and Oman spurs U.S. trade with Oman in goods and services by eliminating most tariff and nontariff barriers. Under the market access provisions of the FTA, the United States and Oman provided each other immediate duty-free access for tariff lines covering almost all consumer and industrial goods and 87% of all agricultural tariff lines. Both countries agreed to phase out all tariffs on the remaining eligible goods within 10 years.</p><p>The FTA contains trade facilitation measures designed to expedite the movement of goods and the provision of services between Oman and the United States; investment provisions intended to strengthen protections for U.S. investors operating in Oman, including allowing them to fully own a business without a local partner; and provisions on safeguards, intellectual property rights, government procurement, labor, environment, and dispute settlement to improve the regulatory climate for bilateral trade and investment.</p><h2><strong>By Sector</strong></h2><p>In 2010, U.S. exports to Oman totaled $1.1 billion. Growth sectors included organic chemicals, optical and medical instruments, plastics, and iron and steel products. Principal U.S. exports to Oman in 2010 were vehicles, machinery, and electrical machinery.</p><h2><strong>Additional Information</strong></h2><ul><li><a href="http://www.ustr.gov/trade-agreements/free-trade-agreements/oman-fta"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">U.S. – Oman Free Trade Agreement legal text</span></a></li><li><a href="http://export.gov/exportbasics/eg_main_017483.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Trade Information Center</span></a></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/oman/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">U.S. Commercial Office in Oman</span></a> </li><li><a href="http://export.gov/eac/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">U.S. Export Assistance Center in your neighborhood</span></a></li></ul><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Free Trade Agreements<sub_topic>U.S.-Oman Free Trade Agreement</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Middle East</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <countries>
        <country>Oman</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>United States-Oman Free Trade Agreement</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the United States-Oman Free Trade Agreement. </seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Trade Barriers, Exports, Tariffs</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/312.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/312.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/312.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
