<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>320</id>
    <title>Success Stories - North Dakota U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Success Stories - North Dakota USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Read success stories from the clients of the North Dakota U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p></p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/northdakota/static/Superior%20Mfg%20Export%20Success_Latest_eg_us_nd_079350.pdf">Superior Mfg. Attains Global Grain Bin Market</a><br>October 2014<br>Superior Manufacturing fabricates steel grain bins and drying equipment from Kindred, ND. The company has transformed from a regional business into a global player in four short years. The company has developed a secret sauce that has yielded impressive results in many countries that are not easy export markets. In this story, International Sales Manager Jon Engelstad takes a break from criss-crossing the globe to share his insights into Superior's secret sauce.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/northdakota/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_nd/documents/webcontent/eg_us_nd_076855.pdf">CH Trade – Presidential E Award Winner</a><br>July 2014<br>CH Trade LLC is a Fargo, N.D. based firm providing export management assistance to U.S. manufacturers. On May 28, 2014 in Washington, DC, CH Trade received the Presidential &quot;E&quot; Award - the highest recognition any U.S. entity may receive for exporting. Learn how CH Trade is assisting multiple Midwest manufacturers</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/northdakota/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_nd/documents/webcontent/eg_us_nd_075760.pdf">J&amp;M Grain Carts to Africa</a><br>June 2014<br>J&amp;M Manufacturing is a Ft. Recovery, OH based agricultural machinery manufacturer. The company had been receiving international email inquiries for several years, so company managers decided to dip their toes into the waters of exporting. Learn how the company broke into the South African market.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/northdakota/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_nd/documents/webcontent/eg_us_nd_074321.pdf">Irish Eyes Smile Upon Fargo Automation</a><br>May 2014<br>Fargo Automation, a Fargo-based manufacturer of pharmaceutical and medical device packaging equipment, saw opportunity to sell outside the USA, but as a new-to-export company in a highly regulated industry, company managers were initially cautious of exporting. Learn what steps Fargo Automation took to successfully begin exporting.</p><p><a href="http://export.gov/northdakota/static/Northern%20Documents%20Export%20Success%20Final_Latest_eg_us_nd_072488.pdf">West Fargo's Northern Documents Finds NAFTA Export Success</a><br>April 2014<br>Since 1996, Northern Documents has been manufacturing custom labels and tags for hundreds of customers from their facility in West Fargo, ND. They do business all across the nation and were recently met with a unique challenge - one of their national customers wanted to export to Canada and needed NAFTA Certificates of Origin for all finished goods and materials purchased from Northern Documents. Learn how Northern Documents met the challenge.</p><p><a href="http://export.gov/northdakota/static/Appareo%20Vaderstad_Latest_eg_us_nd_069856.pdf">Swedish Firm Väderstad Adopts Appareo Systems Technology</a><br>February 2014<br>Appareo Systems, based in Fargo, ND, builds custom engineered agricultural and aviation electronics solutions for original equipment manufacturers. Learn how the company used the USA Pavilion at Agritechnica to make valuable connections.​</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Success Stories - North Dakota U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Read success stories from the clients of the North Dakota U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, success, North Dakota</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/320.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/320.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/320.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
