<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>330</id>
    <title>What is a Foreign Trade Barrier?</title>
    <short_title>Foreign Trade Barriers</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how to identify foreign trade barriers.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>What is a Foreign Trade Barrier?</h1><h2><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages">Definition of trade barrier</a></h2><p>A trade barrier can be broadly defined as a <em>foreign government</em> policy, practice, or procedure that unfairly or unnecessarily restricts U.S. exports.</p><p>Trade barriers may:</p><ul><li>be imposed overtly, often for the purposes of shielding or artificially stimulating domestic industries</li><li>occur as a result of a government failure to provide the necessary infrastructure for competitive conditions</li><li>result from the failure of a government to live up to trade agreement obligations with the United States</li></ul><p>Foreign trade barriers may affect U.S. exports of goods and services, foreign direct investment by U.S. persons, and protection of intellectual property rights. These barriers can come in the form of laws and regulations or informal policies, practices, or procedures.</p><h2><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages">Is your situation caused by a foreign government barrier?</a></h2><p>It requires investigation to determine whether foreign government action or lack of action is the cause of a trade barrier.</p><p>We are happy to review your situation with you and if warranted, investigate these complaints.</p><p>Some trade complaints are clearly not caused by foreign government policies, practices, or procedures and are best handled by other government agencies or programs.</p><p>We encourage you to<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://tcc.export.gov/report_a_barrier/trade_barrier_examples/index.asp"> review our list of questions to see if your situation might be caused by foreign government policies, practices, and procedures which we address</a><strong>.</strong></p><p>If you do not find your trade problem in this trade barrier list, please review the <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://tcc.export.gov/Report_a_Barrier/general_trade_problem_list.asp">general trade problem list</a> to assist in finding the appropriate resource to help you with your trade complaint. Specialists in the programs offered by other parts of the United States Government have the expertise and resources available to help you with problems or questions that may be outside the scope of the Trade Agreements Compliance Program.</p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://tcc.export.gov/Report_a_Barrier/index.asp">Report a Trade Barrier Now</a></p><p>See how the Trade Agreements Compliance Program helped a Pennsylvania exporter overcome a Chinese technical barrier to trade.</p><iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0"></iframe><p>​<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://trade.gov/videos/tcc-klinge.mp4">Download the full video (42 Mb)</a></p><table width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:100%;">Related Links</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><ul><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Additional_Info/About_TCC/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Get more information about foreign trade barriers</span></a> </li><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Trade_Agreements/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">View trade agreements</span></a></li></ul></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Tariff and Customs Barriers</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>What is a Foreign Trade Barrier?</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how to identify foreign trade barriers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Trade Barriers, Foreign Investments, Exports, Trade Complaints, Trade Problems</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/330.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/330.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/330.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
