<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>331</id>
    <title>Foreign Trade Barrier Examples</title>
    <short_title>Identifying Trade Barriers</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how to identify common foreign trade barriers.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/20/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>​Foreign Trade Barrier Examples</h1><p>Though there are many different ways that foreign governments can discriminate against U.S. exports and investment, the following are the most common foreign government-imposed trade barriers that U.S. companies encounter abroad:​</p><table width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default" cellspacing="0" style="height:425px;"><tbody><tr class="ms-rteTableHeaderRow-default"><th class="ms-rteTableHeaderEvenCol-default" rowspan="1" colspan="1" style="width:50%;">Type of Barrier</th><th class="ms-rteTableHeaderOddCol-default" rowspan="1" colspan="1" style="width:50%;">​Definition</th></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​High or Unfairly Applied Tariffs?</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default"><ul><li>​Is a WTO Member or FTA partner applying a tariff at the border which is higher than it committed to charge on that product?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​Classification and Customs Barriers at the Border</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default"><ul><li>​​Are your goods being classified under the wrong tariff schedule heading?</li><li>Are you having problems with a foreign customs office's documentation requirements?</li><li>Are you having problems with any consularization requirements?</li><li>Has the valuation of your goods been rejected on the basis of a minimum or reference price?</li><li>Are the duties charged for your goods higher than what you expected?</li><li>Are the duties charged for your goods based on an arbitrary or inappropriate valuation by foreign customs?</li><li>Are you unable to locate an official public source of information for current data and information regarding a country's customs procedures?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​Burdensom Rule of Origin, Certificate of Origin, or Import Licensing Requirements</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default">​<ul><li>Are you having a problem with a burdensome rules of origin certification requirement?</li><li>Are you having a problem with a burdensome country-of-origin marking requirement?</li><li>Are you having a problem with an unreasonable qualification for rules of origin status?</li><li>Is there a requirement for a U.S. government certification that does not exist?</li><li>Are you unable to locate an official public source of information for current data and information regarding a country's origin requirements?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​Technical Barriers to Trade - Unfair Standards, Testing, Labeling, or Certification Requirements</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default"><ul dir="ltr" style="margin-right:0px;"><li>​Is the obstacle related to a government regulation requiring mandatory standards, testing, or certification?</li><li>Does the barrier entail:</li><ul><li dir="ltr">a burdensome or unclear new national standard</li><li dir="ltr">a standard not based on an international standard</li><li dir="ltr">a burdensome or unclear labeling requirement</li><li dir="ltr">a vague or unclear process to comply with a standard</li><li dir="ltr">a factory inspection that is difficult to obtain</li><li dir="ltr">a national quality mark that is unclear or difficult to meet</li><li dir="ltr">a burdensome or unclear testing or certification requirement</li><li dir="ltr">a burdensome or unclear product registration requirement</li><li dir="ltr">a standard or testing requirement that applies only to foreign companies</li><li dir="ltr">a duplicative or redundant testing or certification requirement</li><li dir="ltr">an unreasonable time frame to comply with the standard or testing requirement</li><li dir="ltr">a regulation developed in a non-transparent manner</li><li dir="ltr">a regulation developed without consideration of available scientific and technical information<br>unnecessary or unreasonable administrative costs</li></ul></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​Unfair Sanitary and Phytosanitary (SPS) - Animal and Plant Welfare - Measures</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default"><ul><li>​Do you face a sanitary or phytosanitary (SPS) barrier to trade which has kept your food or agricultural product out of a specific export market?</li><li>Does the barrier entail:</li><ul><li>an SPS measure developed in a non-transparent manner</li><li>an SPS measure--including requirements, testing and certification--addressing food safety, animal health or plant health, which is not based on science</li><li>an SPS measure not based on an international standard (Codex, OIE, IPPC)</li><li>an SPS requirement that applies only to foreign companies</li><li>a vague or unclear process to comply with an SPS measure</li><li>an unreasonable time frame to comply with the SPS measure or testing requirement</li></ul></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">​Discrimination in Government Procurement</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default"><ul><li>​Are you prohibited from bidding on foreign government contracts?</li><ul><li>Are you facing discriminatory treatment in foreign government procurements?</li><li>Are there inappropriate technical requirements in bid documents that exclude your goods or services?</li></ul><li>Are there mandatory domestic content requirements or price preferences in foreign government tenders?</li><li>Are there bid deadlines that are too short to prepare and submit proposals?</li><li>Are there restrictions that prohibit you from applying to be on a qualified suppliers list?</li><li>Are there problems with procedures to challenge the winning bid; do you have problems getting these procedures?</li><li>Are there contract liabilities and guarantees that are too costly and keep your company from competing for foreign government contracts?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Intellectual Property Rights Protections Problems</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" rowspan="1"><ul><li>​Are your intellectual property rights being violated in a foreign market?</li><li>Have you registered your intellectual property (copyright, patent, trademark, etc) in the foreign market where the violation is occurring?</li><li>Are counterfeit or pirated products which violate your intellectual property rights being sold in the United States or in another country?</li><li>Have you registered your patent or trademark with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office?</li><li>Have you registered your copyright with the U.S. Copyright Office?</li><li>Have you recorded your U.S. trademarks or U.S. copyrights with U.S. Customs?</li><li>Are you unable to register the patent, trademark, or copyright with a foreign government? </li><ul><li>Are similar trademarks, patents, or copyrights registered in that country?</li></ul><li>Have you trusted a foreign government with your intellectual property and has it passed your business confidential information, technology, or trade secrets on to a local company without your permission? </li><ul><li>Is the local company now your main competitor?</li></ul><li>Is a foreign government not helping your agent, distributor, or wholly-owned subsidiary to stop a violation of your trademark, patent or copyright's violation?</li><li>Is your patent, trademark, or copyright being used illegally in a foreign market?</li><li>Is your patent, trademark, or copyright protected under international law (the World Trade Organization's Trade Related Aspects of Intellectual Property - TRIPs, the Berne Convention, or the World Intellectual Property Organization - WIPO)?</li><li>Is your trademark considered a famous mark?</li><li>Do you have documentation or other proof of the patent, trademark, or copyright violation?</li><li>Are you unable to register the patent, trademark, or copyright with a foreign government? </li><ul><li>Are similar trademarks, patents, or copyrights registered in that country?</li></ul><li>Have you trusted a foreign government with your intellectual property and has it passed your business confidential information, technology, or trade secrets on to a local company without your permission?</li><ul><li>Is the local company now your main competitor?</li></ul><li>Is a foreign government not helping your agent, distributor, or wholly-owned subsidiary to stop your trademark, patent or copyright's violation?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Excessive or Unfair Government Requirements Related to Investment or Taxation</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" rowspan="1"><ul><li>​Are you experiencing difficulties exporting because of subsidized local products? </li><ul><li>Is the foreign market dominated by a domestic company or controlled by monopolistic business practices?</li></ul><li>Is the country restricting your product based upon the percentage of foreign-origin content or of foreign ownership of the supplier or service provider?</li><li>Is the country restricting your product because of its components/ingredients, structural composition, or product design?</li><li>Is your product facing overly limiting or unreasonable shelf life restrictions in the foreign market?</li><li>Does a foreign country prohibit the importation of used or re-manufactured goods?</li><li>Is your ability to export affected by the way your goods are classified in a foreign market?</li><li>Are your foreign wholesalers, retailers, or customers having difficulty obtaining certifications, licenses, or other necessary approvals to sell/use your product in other countries?</li><li>Is a foreign country asking for your company to disclose proprietary product information before allowing your product to be imported or approved for sale?</li><li>Have customs duties on your product increased in a country?</li><li>Do you suffer from higher customs duties in a foreign market than your competitors? </li><ul><li>Are your exporting problems a result of the trade agreement benefits shared by other countries?</li></ul><li>Are you encountering a problem with a State-owned or controlled enterprise?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Import Licensing</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" rowspan="1"><ul><li>​Are there unreasonable fees associated with obtaining an import license?</li><li>Is there an overly burdensome process for obtaining an import license?</li><li>Are you having problems learning where/how to obtain an import license?</li><li>Is the purpose for an import license unclear?</li><li>Are there long delays in receiving approval for an import license?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Concerns about Corruption</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" rowspan="1">​Bribery of a public official, including a foreign official, is a crime under U.S. law. Bribery is also a crime under the laws of other countries.<ul><li>Do public officials ask you for bribes in exchange for services, contracts, permits, licenses or other business you may have or would like to have with them?</li><li>Do you know whether your competitors are promising, offering or giving such bribes to public officials?</li><li>Are there any other situations related to corruption you would like to tell us about?</li></ul><p>The United States and many of its trading partners have signed and ratified several international conventions devoted to combating bribery and corruption, including:</p><ul><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Trade_Agreements/All_Trade_Agreements/exp_005875.asp">Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions </a>(OECD Anti-Bribery Convention);</li><li>UN Convention Against Corruption <a href="http://www.unodc.org/pdf/crime/convention_corruption/signing/Convention-e.pdf">(offsite link)</a>; and</li><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Trade_Agreements/All_Trade_Agreements/exp_005436.asp">Inter-American Convention Against Corruption</a>.</li></ul><p>The text of these conventions, along with relevant reports, guides, and links, is provided as a public service. Further anti-corruption resources are provided by:</p><ul><li>the U.S. Department of Commerce <a href="http://www.ogc.doc.gov/trans_anti_bribery.html">Office of General Counsel</a>,</li><li>the Department of State <a href="http://www.state.gov/p/inl/crime/corr/index.htm">Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs</a>, and </li><li>the ITA <a href="http://www.ita.doc.gov/goodgovernance/">Good Governance Program</a></li><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Bribery/Yearly_Antibribery_Reports/index.asp">Commerce Anti-Bribery Reports</a></li><li><a href="http://www.oecd.org/dataoecd/11/40/44176910.pdf">OECD Recommendation On Further Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials - 2009</a></li><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Trade_Agreements/Exporters_Guides/List_All_Guides/exp_000930.asp">Exporter's Guide to the OECD Anti-Bribery Convention</a></li><li><a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Report_a_Barrier/index.asp">Report a Bribery Complaint</a></li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Barriers to Services Provision</td><td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" rowspan="1"><ul><li>​Are all relevant measures (including new and existing laws, regulations, rules, procedures, decisions and administration actions) pertaining to or affecting trade in your company's services published or made readily accessible?</li><li>Do you find registration requirements, licensing procedures, qualification requirements and procedures, and technical standards in a foreign market more burdensome for your company than for domestic service providers?</li><li>Are foreign laws administered in a reasonable and impartial manner? Do they discriminate against you as opposed to third party foreign service providers?</li><li>Has your company faced:</li><ul><li>Quotas (direct access to labor)</li><li>Limitations on foreign capital participation</li><li>Limitations on the size or location of your establishment</li></ul><li>Do you face restrictions in establishing or expanding a commercial presence (e.g., joint venture, branch, affiliate, representative office) to provide your service in a foreign market?</li><li>Do you experience foreign ownership limitations or limits on the number of company directors or managers in providing your service in overseas markets?</li><li>Do you face citizenship, nationality or residency requirements in providing your service in a foreign market?</li><li>Does your company experience limitations or restrictions on the temporary entry/mobility of key business personnel (including executives, managers and other skilled intercorporate transferees) in your business operations in foreign markets?</li></ul></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableFooterRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableFooterEvenCol-default" rowspan="1">​Discriminatory Competition Laws or Unfair Competition from State-Owned Enterprises</td><td class="ms-rteTableFooterOddCol-default" rowspan="1"><ul><li>​Are you facing a trade barrier due to the application of competition laws in a foreign country?</li><li>Are you concerned about receiving fair treatment in anti-trust proceedings?</li><li>Are the competition laws and procedures you are facing transparent?</li></ul></td></tr></tbody></table><p></p><p>If unsure whether you're facing a foreign trade barrier, ask yourself <a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Report_a_Barrier/trade_barrier_examples/questions.asp">these questions</a>.</p><p>If you answered <strong>yes </strong>to any of these questions, you may be facing an unfair trade barrier. <a href="http://tcc.export.gov/Additional_Info/Contact_TCC/index.asp">contact us</a> today to report it so that the United States Government can begin working with you to remove the unfair treatment and restore your access to the market.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Bribery</sub_topic><sub_topic>Excessive Government Requirements</sub_topic><sub_topic>Intellectual Property Infringement</sub_topic><sub_topic>Rules of Origin</sub_topic><sub_topic>Tariff and Customs Barriers</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Foreign Trade Barrier Examples</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how to identify common foreign trade barriers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Trade Barriers, Common Trade Problems, Exports</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/331.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/331.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/331.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
