<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>348</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Florida U.S. Export Assistance Centers</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Florida USEACs</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the Florida U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p>The ​U.S. Department of Commerce, Ft. Lauderdale and Miami Export Assistance Centers are pleased to announce internship opportunities for local, enrolled college students in the South Florida region. We provide firms with direct sales leads, help them establish contacts with prospective overseas business partners, and offer promotional vehicles to introduce their products and services worldwide. As the principal federal government resource for international trade development and assistance, the U.S. Export Assistance Center offers a unique internship opportunity for those interested in pursuing a career in international business. In this position you will have the ability to correspond with foreign diplomats and overseas staff within embassies, on behalf of international trade specialists consulting with U.S. companies. You will also have the opportunity to interact with senior staff in the both south Florida offices.</p><h2>Major Job Responsibilities</h2><ul><li>Evaluate global opportunities for the purpose of presenting to targeted business groups.</li><li>Prospective client follow up calls.</li><li>Campaign support to generate attendance at trade shows and events.</li><li>Maintain database by entering, verifying, and backing up data</li><li>Create marketing materials and campaigns.</li><li>Conduct global market research.</li><li>Support staff before/after major international trade shows.</li><li>Aid and attend trade seminars.</li><li>Work with office staff in consulting on global market entry strategies.</li></ul><h2>Job Requirements</h2><ul><li>A relevant (for example, Marketing, Economics, International Relations, Political Science or Business Administration) major is not required, but is preferred.</li><li>Excellent telephone communication and interpersonal skills.</li><li>The ability to effectively manage time, meet deadlines, and balance multiple priorities.</li><li>The ability to work independently and proactively, yet cooperate and fit into a team.</li><li>A strong and consistent academic background, solid analytical skills, and the ability to present information – written and orally – in an organized, logical manner.</li><li>Strong candidates will have marketing expertise, an ability to build strong relationships with clients and the internal staff, and possess problem solving and organizational skills.</li><li>You must be a U.S. Citizen</li><li>You must be able to work a minimum of 16 hours per week during the Fall/Spring school semester and 24 hours per week in the summer</li></ul><p>Students with a wide mix of skills have completed successful internships with us, with undergraduate majors ranging from business, cultural studies, languages, economics, and political science. In short, we look at your capabilities, motivation and attitude more so than a specific major or grade point average when evaluating our candidates. Some general qualifications include a strong and consistent academic background, solid analytical skills, and the ability to present information – written and orally – in an organized, logical manner. We look for evidence of personal motivation, resourcefulness, initiative and professionalism. This intern program is on a volunteer basis and is unpaid. Academic credit may also be offered as arranged by your educational institution.</p><p><strong>** We are now accepting applications for the Fall 2013 and Spring 2014 semesters.</strong></p><p>If you are interested, please send a resume and cover letter to Kathryn Dye at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Kathryn.Dye@trade.gov">Kathryn.Dye@trade.gov</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Florida U.S. Export Assistance Centers</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the Florida U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, Florida</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/348.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/348.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/348.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
