<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>350</id>
    <title>US Commercial Service &amp; RVIA</title>
    <short_title>US Commercial Service &amp; RVIA</short_title>
    <summary>Watch webinars produced by the Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center in partnership with the Recreational Vehicle Industry Association (RVIA) to serve RVIA members and help promote their business around the world.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_logo.jpg" alt="U.S. Commercial Service logo and Recreational Vehicle Industry Association logo" style="margin:5px;" /></span></p><p><span style="line-height:1.6;">Market Development Cooperator Program (MDCP) awards include financial and technical assistance from the International Trade Administration (ITA) to support projects that enhance the global competitiveness of U.S. industries. An MDCP award establishes a partnership between ITA and non-profit industry groups such as trade associations and chambers of commerce.</span></p><p>The Recreational Vehicle Industry Association received an award from the MDCP in 2012 to increase recreational vehicle exports to China and Japan. This investment by the US Department of Commerce in the RVIA will help boost exports and create jobs in the United States.</p><p>The US Commercial Service in Indianapolis is pleased to partner with the Recreational Vehicle Industry Association (RVIA). In order to serve RVIA members and help promote their business around the world, we have developed this series of educational webinars.</p><p>Please note that once you click on a video, you will be redirected to an external website.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CSVRBpCjfNM&amp;feature=youtu.be"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video1.jpg" alt="screenshot from RVIA intro video on YouTube" style="margin:5px;" /></a>​<br></p><h2>Introduction by Director Mark Cooper</h2><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxJ13bdYQoY"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video2.jpg" alt="screenshot from How to Write an Effective Export Plan YouTube video" style="margin:5px;" /></a><br></p><h2>How to Write an Effective Export Plan</h2><p>In this webinar, you will learn how to write a simple but effective export plan for your business, featuring the new Small Business Administration's Export Planning Tool. You will learn the framework for writing your export plan. You will understand the value of having a written export plan, the key sections of the plan and how to find the information to complete the plan.</p><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Et79dJsLtHE"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video3.jpg" alt="scrrenshot from Export Documentation YouTube video" style="margin:5px;" /></a><br></p><h2>Export Documentation</h2><p>In this webinar, you will get an overview of each commonly used export document: common challenges in preparation and processing; responsibilities of the parties to the transaction; Incoterms; customs valuation and more.</p><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WYF5dm0NE7I"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video4.jpg" alt="screenshot from How to Identify Potential International Markets YouTube video" style="margin:5px;" /></a><br></p><h2>How to Identify Potential International Markets for Your Products and Services</h2><p>In this webinar, you will learn where to find and analyze key information and how to customize it for your own products and business. You will also learn an analytical framework for evaluating your product or service in potential markets. You will learn what questions to ask in adapting your product for consumers from different cultural backgrounds and will find customized valuable information on export.gov and other sources.</p><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hg-I6nvqNEM"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video5.jpg" alt="screenshot from Financing Your Exports YouTube video" style="margin:5px;" /></a><br></p><h2>Financing Your Exports and Getting Paid</h2><p>In this webinar, you will learn the basics of trade finance and what you need to know about getting paid for exports. You will learn about the range of payment methods used in export transactions and how to evaluate which is best for your business. You will also learn about letters of credit and U.S. government programs for financing exports including a program that enables buyers to purchase your product or service.</p><p><br></p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qehy2E1SFzc"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/RVIA_video6.jpg" alt="screenshot from How to Select a Freight Forwarder YouTube video" style="margin:5px;" /></a><br></p><h2>How to Select a Freight Forwarder</h2><p>When shipping a product overseas as part of a commercial transaction, the exporter must be awar​e of packing, labeling, documentation, and insurance requirements. An international freight forwarder is an agent for the exporter and can move cargo from &quot;dock-to-door,&quot; providing several significant services. In this webinar you will learn how to select a forwarder; how a freight forwarder can help minimize shipping costs; documents that forwarders can process and submit on your behalf; and how forwarders coordinate with their counterparts in other countries to clear customs and get your goods to the customer.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>US Commercial Service &amp; RVIA</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Watch webinars produced by the Indiana U.S. Export Assistance Center in partnership with the Recreational Vehicle Industry Association (RVIA) to serve RVIA members and help promote their business around the world.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Indiana, RVIA, webinars</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/350.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_logo.jpg" name="RVIA_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video1.jpg" name="RVIA_video1"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video2.jpg" name="RVIA_video2"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video3.jpg" name="RVIA_video3"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video4.jpg" name="RVIA_video4"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video5.jpg" name="RVIA_video5"/>
      <image src="/Files/RVIA_video6.jpg" name="RVIA_video6"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/350.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/350.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
