<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>363</id>
    <title>EBRD Home</title>
    <short_title>EBRD Home</short_title>
    <summary>Homepage of the U.S. Commercial Service Liaison Office to the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (CS-EBRD). Discusses the Bank's programs.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee</source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1 class="Header-1"><strong>Welcome to U.S. Commercial Service Liaison Office to the<br> European Bank for Reconstruction and Development <img class="ms-rtePosition-3" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/eg_ebrd_034649.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></strong></h1><p class="DefaultParagraph-1">The U.S. is the largest single shareholder in the EBRD, the world’s newest multilateral development bank. The Bank’s program promotes the growth of market-based economies in30 countries in Central and Eastern Europe and the Former Soviet Union. With US$20 billion of capital, the Bank offers a wide range of financing mechanisms to promote privatization, restructuring, and liberalization in this highly dynamic region. </p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1">TheU.S. Commercial ServiceLiaison Office to the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (CS-EBRD) is an integral part of U.S. representation at the EBRD and works closely with the Executive Director's office to increase the effectiveness of U.S. participation in Bank programs. CS-EBRD provides information to U.S. businesses on how the EBRD works and how U.S. companies can participate in EBRD projects. CS-EBRD also offers guidance to U.S. companies throughout the project cycle.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Finance</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Finance</industry>
      </industries>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>EBRD Home</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Homepage of the U.S. Commercial Service Liaison Office to the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (CS-EBRD). The Bank's programs promote privatization, restructuring, and liberalization.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>European Bank, privatize, restructure, liberalize, Liaison</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/363.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/eg_ebrd_034649.jpg" name="eg_ebrd_034649"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/363.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/363.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
