<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>377</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Hawaii U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Hawaii USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities available with the Hawaii U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​<span style="color:#f09609;font-family:'segoe ui semilight', 'segoe ui', segoe, tahoma, helvetica, arial, sans-serif;font-size:1.46em;line-height:1.4;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/U.S.%20Commercial%20Service%20logo.jpg" alt="U.S. Commercial Service logo" style="margin:5px;" />​</span></p><p><span style="color:#f09609;font-family:'segoe ui semilight', 'segoe ui', segoe, tahoma, helvetica, arial, sans-serif;font-size:1.46em;line-height:1.4;">Internship Overview</span></p><p style="text-align:justify;">The International Trade Internship with the local Honolulu office of the U.S. Department of Commerce's U.S. Commercial Service is an unpaid internship for college credit. This dynamic internship provides students with an opportunity to interact with real businesses in the community and work on real world trade issues.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">The internship requires completion of at least 4 months with a minimum of 12 hours per week. We can be flexible in working around your school schedule. Openings are available on a rolling basis but usually coincide with the semester schedule. Interviews are usually conducted at our office but can be conducted over the phone.<br><br>The Honolulu office operates Monday - Friday.</p><h2>Requirements</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Must be a U.S. Citizen. Position is an unpaid internship. Applicants must fulfill minimum hourly requirements. Must be enrolled at least part-time in a college or university.</p><h2>Major Areas of Study</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">All Business Majors, Economics, Political Science, Public Administration, Law, International Studies and Relations, Marketing, Finance, Foreign Language, Communications, Sociology, Geography and History.</p><h2>Daily Internship Activities</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Provide support to International Trade Specialists in outreach, market research, trade promotion, and international trade and policy development</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Meet with real companies to learn about their export challenges and counsel them on solutions and available resources</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Research and analysis on commercial markets in Asia, Europe, Latin America, Africa, and the Middle East</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Collaboration with local Hawaii Pacific Export Council members in conducting export outreach and education training programs</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Opportunity to take part in trade development meetings with American and foreign government officials and executives in key industries</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Research on policy and regulatory issues impacting trade with global markets</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Update and management of export resources website</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Publishing of quarterly newsletter on international trade news</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Promotion of industry trade events and training programs</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Database management of key contacts</span><br></li></ul><h2>Internship Contact Information<br></h2><p style="text-align:justify;">If you would like to apply for the International Trade Internship, please send your resume and an introductory email to the contact info below. Please include the dates you are available for the internship.</p><p>Mr. John Holman<br>Director, Pacific Islands<br>U.S.Commercial Service<br>U.S. Department of Commerce<br>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:John.Holman@trade.gov">John.Holman@trade.gov</a>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Hawaii U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities available with the Hawaii U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Hawaii, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/377.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/U.S.%20Commercial%20Service%20logo.jpg" name="U"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/377.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/377.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
