<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>384</id>
    <title>Local Events - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Kansas City</title>
    <short_title>Local Events - Kansas City USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about events presented by the U.S. Export Assistance Center of Kansas City.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/22/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/22/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Commercial Service in Kansas City, Missouri organizes and supports conferences, seminars, and events to educate our clients and promote international trade. Our goal is to help local U.S. exporters sell globally. A sampling of our events includes:</p><ul><li>Executive briefings in our office with one of our visiting Commercial Service Officers from around the world.</li><li>Educational export seminars and online webinars.</li><li>Matchmaking and export counseling services at international trade shows overseas and the U.S.</li></ul><p>By organizing trade missions and educational seminars; providing matching or export counseling services at trade shows; and recruiting buyer delegations to U.S. trade shows, the U.S. Government helps U.S. exporters expand global sales at trade events.<br></p><h2>Upcoming Events/Trainings:<br></h2><h3>July 8, 2014 – Where's Your Export Market?</h3><p>Join the MO Small Business &amp; Technology Development Centers, the Missouri Department of Economic Development, and the U.S. Commercial Service – Kansas City for a hands-on, interactive session designed to provide insight and information on actions you can take to successfully identify, research and enter new international markets.</p><p>When: Tuesday, July 8, 2014 - 11:00 AM – 1:30 PM</p><p>Where: UMKC SBTDC</p><p>4747 Troost Ave.</p><p>Kansas City, MO 64110</p><p>Fee: $35 (lunch included)</p><p><strong>Questions?</strong>Contact UMKC SBTDC @ 816-235-6063.<strong>Register online –</strong><a href="http://www.sbtdc.umkc.edu/">www.sbtdc.umkc.edu</a><br></p><h3><br>July 22, 2014 – NASCO Regional Competitiveness Summit – Kansas City</h3><p>Join the North American Strategy for Competitiveness (NASCO) at its regional summit in Kansas City as they highlight important North American trade &amp; transport work underway! In &quot;Sharpening the Focus on North America&quot; you will hear direct from leaders across the continent on their innovative business strategies and new pro-business public policies in the works.<br></p><p>When: Tuesday, July 22, 2014 – 11:00 AM – 4:00 PM<br></p><p>Where: Kauffman Foundation Conference Center</p><p>4801 Rockhill Road</p><p>Kansas City, MO 64110<br><br>Fee: NASCO Member: $50 / Non-member: $75 (lunch &amp; meeting)</p><p>For event details and to register online -<a href="https://www.regonline.com/Register/Checkin.aspx?EventID=1568210">https://www.regonline.com/Register/Checkin.aspx?EventID=1568210​</a></p><p>(NASCO) is a tri-national coalition of governments, businesses and educational institutions driven by a common interest in collaboration along key freight, energy and trade networks.</p><p><br></p><h3>July 29-31, 2014 – Certified Global Business Professional Exam (CGBP) Training – Colombia, MO</h3><p>CGBP Exam Training – Targeted at those seeking national credentialing as a &quot;Certified Global Business Professional.&quot;</p><p>Mr. James Foley, an expert trainer on international sales and marketing, will be in Colombia, MO, July 29 -31, to lead a three-day course covering the primary content areas of the CGBP Exam: global business management, global marketing, resources and data sources, international supply chain management – with a focus on export facilitation, and trade finance.</p><p>This course is aligned with the national NASBITE CGBP trade professional exam and would support efforts of participants to sit for the national exam.</p><p>For more details and to register, contact: Yvetta Hamilton, Tel: 573-884-1555 or<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:musbdcadmin@missouri.edu">musbdcadmin@missouri.edu</a>. Questions: Larry Dill @<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:dill@missouri.edu">dill@missouri.edu</a></p><p><br></p><h3>August 17 – 20, 2014 – Missouri Governor's Trade Mission to Calgary &amp; Edmonton, Canada</h3><p>Missouri Governor Jay Nixon will be leading a trade mission to Alberta, Canada from August 17-20, 2014. Canada is the biggest export partner for the United States, with the equivalent of $1.6 billion in goods traded every day. Likewise, Canada is the biggest export partner for the State of Missouri with about one third of its annual exports going there. Missouri exports to Canada totaled almost $4 billion in 2013 and just over $4.3 billion in 2012.<br></p><p>Whether you're an experienced exporter or looking to grow your business through exports for the first time, Canada offers tremendous opportunities. Key industry sectors for this trip will be energy, aerospace, advanced manufacturing, life sciences, processed foods, agricultural products, transportation equipment and tourism.</p><p>All companies that participate in the mission will receive pre-scheduled meetings with potential buyers, as well as several other benefits exclusive to mission participants.</p><p>The<strong>deadline to register</strong>for this mission is<strong>June 30</strong>, but space is limited, so<a href="http://www.ded.mo.gov/docs/export_missouri/AlbertaMissionflyer.pdf">apply today</a>!</p><p>If you have any questions or need further assistance, please contact the Missouri International Trade &amp; Investment Office at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:exports@ded.mo.gov">exports@ded.mo.gov</a>or 573-751-4855.</p><p><br></p><h2>Search for Worldwide Trade Events</h2><ul><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/eac/trade_events.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">Worldwide trade events</a><br></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/mrktresearch/eg_main_018213.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">Webinars</a><br></li></ul><p></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Local Events - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Kansas City</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about events presented by the U.S. Export Assistance Center of Kansas City.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Kansas City, Missouri, events</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/384.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/384.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/384.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
