<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>388</id>
    <title>Ohio’s Diebold Gains Duty Free Access into India’s $100+ Million IT Market</title>
    <short_title>Diebold Gains Duty Free Access in India</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration assisted Ohio based Diebold gain duty free access into India's IT market.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/23/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/23/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Ohio's Diebold Gains Duty Free Access into India's $100+ Million IT Market</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) supported Diebold, a Canton, Ohio-based manufacturer of automated teller machines (ATMs), in its efforts to overcome an unfair cost of doing business in India's IT sector.</p><h2>Why it matters: </h2><p>Though India had committed to provide duty free access to certain IT products, including ATMs, its decision not to classify Diebold's machines as ATMs subjected Diebold to a 30 percent duty. This significantly raised the cost of Diebold's exports and undermined their competitiveness in the Indian market.</p><p><img alt="India Flag" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/oh_india_sep2012.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></p><h2>The problem:</h2><p>Indian Customs authorities refused to classify Diebold's machines as ATMs because the machines did not accept deposits, thus depriving Diebold of the benefits of duty-free treatment to which India had previously agreed under the World Trade Organization's (WTO) Information Technology Agreement.</p><h2>The solution: </h2><p>ITA, in cooperation with other U.S. Government agencies, placed sustained pressure on the Indian Commerce and Finance Ministries to reclassify Diebold's machines appropriately as ATMs. As a result, India finally reclassified Diebold's machines, reducing the tariff's Diebold owed from 30% to zero, and ensuring its continued duty-free access to the $100+ million market for the company in India. </p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Tariff and Customs Barriers</sub_topic><sub_topic>Government Contracting Barriers</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Asia<geo_subregion>South Asia</geo_subregion></geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Information &amp; Communication</industry>
        <industry>Metal Manufacturing &amp; Products</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>India</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Ohio’s Diebold Gains Duty Free Access into India’s $100+ Million IT Market</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration assisted Ohio based Diebold gain duty free access into India's IT market.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>ATMs, WTO Technology Agreement, Tariffs,  Government Procurement </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/388.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/oh_india_sep2012.jpg" name="oh_india_sep2012"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/388.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/388.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
