<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>394</id>
    <title>ITA Opens Doors to U.S. Elevators in Japan</title>
    <short_title>ITA Assists Pneumatic Vacuum Elevators</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped Pneumatic Vacuum Elevator overcome Japanese trade barriers.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/23/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/23/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Commerce Opens Doors to U.S. Elevators in Japan</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) helped Pneumatic Vacuum Elevator LLC (PVE), a small-to-medium size enterprise (SME) headquartered in Miami, Florida, overcome a foreign trade barrier that threatened to exclude it from the Japanese market.</p><h2>Why it Matters</h2><p>If Japan had enacted its proposed new safety standard that was based on design rather than performance requirements, PVE would have lost $5 million in exports to Japan. Japan's decision to instead rely on a performance-based standard in keeping with its trade agreements opened doors to the Japanese construction market for other American businesses.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img alt="Vacuum Elevator" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/commerce_opens_door.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br>Photo courtesy Pneumatic Vacuum Elevators, LLC</p><h2>The Problem</h2><p>Japan proposed requiring all residential elevator cabins to be manufactured using &quot;sliding&quot; doors. This new standard would exclude PVE from the Japanese market because its elevators use &quot;swinging&quot; doors. The proposed standard conflicted with Japan's World Trade Organization (WTO) obligations to specify technical standards in terms of performance, rather than design characteristics, when appropriate.</p><h2>The Solution</h2><p>A team of ITA specialists raised the issue to Japanese government officials and at the WTO, indicating that a specification based on performance rather than design would not keep Japan from meeting its safety goals. As a result of the team's actions, Japan revised the technical standard, permitting the use of swinging doors on residential elevators and averting the potential restriction of$5 millionin PVE's exports to Japan. PVE's representatives thanked the ITA for its &quot;tremendous support.&quot; The revised technical standard creates opportunities in Japan for other U.S. exporters of elevators with similar technology. </p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Excessive Government Requirements</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Asia<geo_subregion>East Asia</geo_subregion></geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Construction, Building &amp; Heavy Equipment</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>ITA Opens Doors to U.S. Elevators in Japan</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped Pneumatic Vacuum Elevator overcome Japanese trade barriers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Safety Standards, Technical Standards, Trade Agreements, Technical Barriers</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/394.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/commerce_opens_door.jpg" name="commerce_opens_door"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/394.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/394.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
