<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>395</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - U.S. Export Assistance Centers in Michigan</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Michigan USEACs</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities available with the U.S. Export Assistance Centers in Michigan.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/22/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/21/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​U.S. Export Assistance Center, U.S. Commercial Service, U.S. Department Of Commerce Internships</h2><p>The Commercial Service (US&amp;FCS) is the export promotion arm of the U.S. Department of Commerce/International Trade Administration.</p><p>The U.S. Export Assistance Center (USEAC) engages in the counseling of Michigan companies on export marketing procedures, regulations, and methods of doing business in foreign countries. Assistance is provided for Michigan companies in the area of market research, locating marketing partners and matchmaking with distributors and/or representatives. The USEAC provides international trade promotion programs and seminars to promote U.S. products and services overseas. There are four USEACs located in Michigan.</p><p>The USEAC internship program is a non compensated position. The principle function of an intern is to assist the office in the execution of their strategic marketing plan and that of each international trade specialist. It is an opportunity to acquire real world experience from professional export counselors. The responsibilities of this internship include, but are not limited to the following:</p><ul><li>Assist International Trade Specialists in the areas of international business research</li><li>Assist in the coordination of event planning for international trade shows and Michigan based trade seminars</li><li>Enter client information into database and provide general administrative support</li><li>Provide assistance to International Trade Specialists as they help Michigan businesses develop and execute export marketing plans</li></ul><h3>What is the Export Assistance Center looking for in an intern?</h3><p>Our offices seek students who are self motivated and willing to work 20-40 hours a week. Preference is given to Junior, Senior or Graduate Students with 3.0 GPA or better in the following fields of study:</p><p>International Marketing or International Business</p><ul><li>Economics</li><li>Political Science</li><li>Foreign Languages</li><li>Business Law</li><li>International Studies</li></ul><h3>Must have the following skills:</h3><ul><li>Excellent oral and written communication skills</li><li>Good r​esearch skills</li><li>Computer literate</li><li>Creative and self motivated</li></ul><p><strong>Note: Position is unpaid; must be a U.S. Citizen,minimum of 18 years of age,and a full/part-time student.​</strong></p><h3>If you are interested in applying for an internship, please send your resume with a cover letter via e-mail to the following internship coordinators:</h3><p>Detroit:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Sara.Coulter@trade.gov">Sara.Coulter@trade.gov</a></p><p>Pontiac:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Richard.Corson@trade.gov">Richard.Corson@trade.gov</a></p><p>Grand Rapids:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Kendra.Kuo@trade.gov">Kendra.Kuo@trade.gov</a>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - U.S. Export Assistance Centers in Michigan</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities available with the U.S. Export Assistance Centers in Michigan.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Michigan, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/395.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/395.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/395.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
