<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>401</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - U.S. Export Assistance Center in Minnesota</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Minnesota USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities available at the U.S. Export Assistance Center in Minnesota.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/23/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/22/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align:center;">​​U.S. Department of Commerce | International Trade​ Administration</h2><h2 style="text-align:center;">Global Markets</h2><h2 style="text-align:center;">Interning with theU.S. Commercial Service-Minnesota</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Internships at the U.S. Commercial Service provide students with an opportunity to gain real world, professional experience by working with professionals in the field of international trade and business. Currently, the U.S. Commercial Service has positions available for<a href="http://www.export.gov/minnesota/static/Intern%20Recruiting%20Flyer%20Spring-Summer%202014_Latest_eg_us_mn_070900.pdf">International Trade Interns</a>.</p><h3><br>Requirements include:</h3><p><strong><em>U.S. Citizenship</em></strong><br>Interest in International Affairs<br>Enrollment in an accredited school<br>Graduate or undergraduate status<br>3.0 GPA minimum<br>16 hours per week availability<br>20 hours per week availability in summer<br>Good interpersonal skills<br>Ability to communicate verbally<br>Strong writing skills<br>Strong research skills<br>Knowledge of Excel spreadsheets &amp; formulas<br>Background check</p><h3>To apply email resume and optional cover letter to:</h3><p>Jim Curtis<br>U.S. Commercial Service Minnesota<br>U.S. Export Assistance Center<br>100 N 6th Street, Suite 210-C<br>Minneapolis, MN 55403<br>Email: Jim.Curtis@trade.gov</p><h3><br>Intern testimonials:</h3><p>&quot;I have not only enjoyed my time at the Minneapolis USEAC, but have gained tangible research and writing skills applicable to both my classwork as well as future employment opportunities. I have gained &quot;real world&quot; experience by way of conducting research for numerous clients who will directly benefit and make business decisions based upon my findings. The U.S. Commercial Service will help you export your career to the next level.&quot;—Dan, Northeastern University, Summer 2014<br></p><p>&quot;The U.S. Commercial Service internship is perhaps the best kept secret in Minneapolis –it creates the unique opportunity to work at the epicenter of international trade here in Minnesota. Throughout my time here I have attended meetings with clients and government officials, created international market research reports for clients, assisted staff in promoting U.S. foreign trade, and learned what it means to be a part of a federal government agency. You could not hope for a better opportunity to grow in a rigorous international business environment with a supportive, helpful staff to guide you in your professional development.&quot;—Chris, University of St. Thomas, Summer 2014</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - U.S. Export Assistance Center in Minnesota</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities available at the U.S. Export Assistance Center in Minnesota.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Minnesota, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/401.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/401.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/401.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
