<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>402</id>
    <title>Promoting Minnesota as an International Tourism Destination</title>
    <short_title>Minnesota as a Tourism Destination</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about how the U.S. Commercial Service promotes Minnesota as an international tourism destination.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/22/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/22/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="color:#f09609;font-family:'segoe ui semilight', 'segoe ui', segoe, tahoma, helvetica, arial, sans-serif;font-size:1.46em;line-height:1.4;">​How the U.S. Commercial Service Supports International Tourism​​</span></p><h3>​Travel and Tourism in Minnesota</h3><p>Minnesota has many attractions for international tourists. Extensive lakes and parks, shopping outlets and malls, world-class medical care, renowned art galleries, gaming venues, and award winning dining options are just some of those attractions. And the impact tourism has on the state's economy is significant. According to Explore Minnesota, in 2011 tourism in Minnesota generated nearly $12 billion in revenue and employed close to 240,000 people. Over three million of those visitors were international tourists.​</p><p><br></p><h3>Our Support</h3><p>The U.S. Commercial Service office in Minneapolis is focused on helping to promote international travel to Minnesota by supporting U.S. tourism companies, organizations, and local agencies including promotion bureaus, CVBs, hotels, tour operators, and others to capture international business. How do we do that?</p><p><br></p><h3>Media Placement</h3><p>Our office can provide support through our network of U.S. Commercial Service offices in Embassies and Consulates around the world in placing articles in overseas newspapers and magazines that highlight the many attractions of Minnesota. Our office welcomes press releases and photos on a range of topics of interest to tourists from abroad—shopping destinations, outdoor activities, or dining venues, to name a few—which we can share with our overseas offices so that they can assist in having articles published in foreign publications targeted to international travelers. While placement is up to the each publication, often overseas journalists welcome content that can be readily used. If you have material already translated, that is even better. Placing the content in the overseas publication is done at no cost for the U.S. organization.</p><p><br></p><h3>International Travel &amp; Tourism Shows</h3><p>The U.S. Commercial Service supports a number of major international tourism shows and often organizes a U.S. Pavilion at these events. Major trade shows include ITB in Berlin and WTM in London, not to mention Pow Wow in the U.S. At these shows, U.S. Commercial Service staff work to facilitate connections between U.S. industry contacts and those in in the other counties, including journalists, tour operators, airlines, and others. Interested groups can contact our office to learn which upcoming trade shows are supporting a U.S. Pavilion.</p><p><br></p><h3>Up-to-Date Travel Market Research</h3><p>The U.S. Commercial Service has a number of existing off-the-shelf research reports on the tourism industry in key overseas markets. These reports can be downloaded for free from our U.S. Commercial Service Market Research Library at:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://export.gov/mrktresearch">http://export.gov/mrktresearch/</a>.For details and links for locating research on international visitations, spending data, and other tourism related statistics, visit out U.S. Commercial Service Travel and Tourism webpage at:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://export.gov/industry/travel/index.asp">http://export.gov/industry/travel/index.asp</a>.</p><p><br></p><p></p><h3>Memorable Promotional Events or Find Travel Distribution Partners Overseas</h3><p></p><p>Do you want to make a PR splash or showcase your company to a targeted group of travel agents? Or perhaps you're looking to find qualified tour operators, wholesalers, agents, sales reps, or partners? The U.S. Commercial Service also has paid for services to assist you to identify and recruit for high-profile events, or in find qualified overseas contacts. For more details, please contact our office in Minneapolis at:<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:Office.Minneapolis@trade.gov">Office.Minneapolis@trade.gov</a>or (612) 348-1638.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Promoting Minnesota as an International Tourism Destination</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about how the U.S. Commercial Service promotes Minnesota as an international tourism destination.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, Minnesota, tourism, promotion</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/402.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/402.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/402.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
