<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>411</id>
    <title>Mississippi International Trade Resources</title>
    <short_title>Mississippi Trade Resources</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about local trade resources and partners of the U.S. Export Assistance Center in Mississippi.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/23/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/23/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​Local Partners</h2><p>​</p><h2>Mississippi World Trade Center​<br></h2><p>The Mississippi World Trade Center, which is affiliated with the World Trade Centers Association, is a non-profit membership organization dedicated to promoting international trade, investment, and tourism. The organization seeks to develop and promote international events, programs, and services and to unify the State's efforts in the global marketplace. The World Trade Center is a resource to the public and private sectors on international opportunities and requests.</p><p><strong>Mississippi World Trade Center</strong></p><p>175 East Capitol Street, Suite 255</p><p>Jackson, Mississippi 39201</p><p>Phone: (601) 353-0909</p><p>Fax: (601) 353-0974</p><p>Contact: Barbara Travis, Executive Director</p><p><br></p><h2>Hinds International Trade Center</h2><p><a href="http://www.hindscc.edu/Departments/economic_development/Small_Biz.aspx">Hinds International Trade Center</a>, an arm of the Small Business Development Center, offers many resources and services to help companies with their international business needs. These services include counseling, seminars and training, and trade leads.</p><p>Located at: Eagle Ridge Conference Center</p><p>1500 Raymond Lake Road</p><p>Raymond, MS 39154</p><p>Mailing:<strong>International Trade Center</strong></p><p>Hinds Community College</p><p>PMB 11263</p><p>PO Box 1100</p><p>Raymond, MS 39154</p><p>Contact: Jim Harper</p><p>Phone: (601) 857-3581</p><p>Fax: (601) 857-3474</p><p><br></p><h2>Mississippi Development Authority​<br></h2><p>The international division of the<a href="http://www.mississippi.org/">Mississippi Development Authority (MDA)</a>fosters economic growth, job creation, and internationalization of the state's economy. MDA promotes business development and exports, and it seeks to attract foreign capital. The international division is made up of trade specialists assigned by geographic region. They are responsible for helping to identify prospective buyers and assisting clients in their respective regions.</p><p><strong>Mississippi Development Authority</strong></p><p>Trade Bureau</p><p>P.O. Box 849</p><p>Jackson, MS 39205 USA</p><p>Phone: (601) 359-6672</p><p>Fax: (601) 359-3605</p><p>Contact: Elizabeth Cleveland, Director</p><p><strong><br></strong></p><h2>Export-Import Bank of the United States</h2><a href="http://www.exim.gov/" style="line-height:1.6;">The Export Import (ExIm) Bank</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">is an independent federal government agency that helps finance the overseas sales of U.S. goods and services. Its mission is to create American jobs through exports. It provides guarantees of working capital loans for U.S. exporters, and it guarantees the repayment of loans or makes loans to foreign purchasers of U.S. goods and services. It also provides credit insurance that protects U.S. exporters against the risks of non-payment by foreign buyers for political or commercial reasons. It does not compete with commercial lenders, but assumes the risks they cannot accept. It must always have a reasonable assurance of repayment.</span><br><p><strong>Export-Import Bank of the United States</strong></p><p>1880 S. Dairy Ashford II Suite 405</p><p>Houston, TX 77077</p><p>Phone: (281) 721-0469</p><p>Fax: (281) 679-0156</p><p>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:John.Johnson@exim.gov">John.Johnson@exim.gov</a></p><p>Contact: John Johnson</p><p><br></p><h2>Mississippi Economic Development Council​<br></h2><p><a href="http://medc.ms/">The Mississippi Economic Development Council (MEDC)</a>serves as the voice for Mississippi's economic and community development professionals and their constituencies. MEDC establishes and advocates Mississippi's economic and community development agenda. MEDC facilitates a network of trained professionals and serves as an information resource hub for strategies for economic and community development.</p><p><strong>Mississippi Economic Development Council</strong></p><p>P.O. Box 3721</p><p>Jackson, MS 39207-3721</p><p>Phone: (601) 352-1909</p><p>Fax: (601) 352-2061</p><p>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Carol@medc.ms">Carol@medc.ms</a></p><p>Contact: Carol Hardwick</p><p><br></p><h2>Mississippi District Export Council</h2><p>Mississippi District Export Councilmembers represent a cross-section of local public and private-sector individuals willing to work in close concert with the Mississippi U.S. Export Assistance Center to better serve the needs of the export community. Appointed by the Secretary of Commerce for their leadership abilities, knowledge of international trade, interest in export development, and willingness to devote their time to council activities, members devote their time and energy to council activities and assisting local firms export their products and services.</p><p>Contact: Craig Harvey, Chairman</p><p>Phone: (228) 242-0015</p><p>Fax: (228) 242-0013</p><p>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Charvey@nvisionsolutions.com">Charvey@nvisionsolutions.com</a></p><p><br></p><h2>Mississippi Department of Agriculture</h2><p>The mission of the<a href="http://www.mdac.state.ms.us/Index.asp">Mississippi Department of Agriculture and Commerce</a>is to regulate and promote agricultural-related businesses within the state and to promote Mississippi's products throughout both the state and the rest of the world for the benefit of all Mississippi citizens.</p><p><strong>Mississippi Department of Agriculture</strong></p><p>121 North Jefferson Street</p><p>Jackson, MS 39201</p><p>Contact: Patrick Sullivan</p><p>Phone: (601) 3589-1158</p><p><br></p><h2>Mississippi Manufacturers Association​</h2><p><span style="line-height:1.6;">Promoting and protecting the interests of manufacturers in Mississippi, the<a href="http://www.mma-web.org/">Mississippi Manufacturers Association​</a>currently has membership of more than 2,000 manufacturers and business firms. They have active staff members who keep the interests of Mississippi business and manufacturing in mind.</span><br></p><p><strong>Mississippi Manufacturers Association</strong></p><p>P.O. Box 22607</p><p>Jackson, MS 39225-2607</p><p>Contact: Jay Moon</p><p>Phone: (601) 948-1222</p><p>Fax: (601) 948-1475</p><p>Email:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Jay@mma-web.org">Jay@mma-web.org</a></p><p><br></p><h2>U.S. Small Business Administration, Jackson Office​</h2><p>The<a href="http://www.sba.gov/">U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA)</a>is a federal agency which provides assistance to exporters through loan guarantees, management assistance, and export legal assistance. Their<a href="http://www.sba.gov/category/navigation-structure/loans-grants/small-business-loans/sba-loan-programs">Export Working Capital Program (EWCP)</a>provides short-term financing to small business for export related transactions. They also have an International Trade Loan (ITL) program that provides long-term financing to exporters. Management assistance is available through their Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE). Export legal assistance is available through their Export Legal Assistance Network (ELAN).</p><p><strong>U.S. Small Business Administration, Jackson Office</strong></p><p>AmSouth Bank Plaza</p><p>210 E. Capitol Street, Suite 900</p><p>Jackson, Mississippi 39201</p><p>PH: (601) 965-4378</p><p>FAX: (601) 965-5629</p><p><br></p><h2>​Minority Business Development Agency</h2><p><a href="http://www.mbda.gov/">Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA)</a>promotes the establishment and growth of minority-owned businesses. MBDA is the only federal agency that specifically assists minority businesses of all sizes.</p><p><strong>​MBDA</strong></p><p>JoAnn Hill</p><p>Atlanta National Enterprise Center</p><p>W. Peachtree St., NW, Suite 1715</p><p>Atlanta, Georgia 30308-3516</p><p>Phone: (404) 730-3300</p><p><a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:jhill@mbda.gov">jhill@mbda.gov</a></p><p><br></p><h2>Overseas Private Investment Corporation</h2><p>The Jackson Export Assistance Center also works closely with<a href="http://www.opic.gov/">the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC)</a>. OPIC helps U.S. businesses invest overseas, fosters economic development in new and emerging markets, complements the private sector in managing the risks associated with foreign direct investment, and supports U.S. foreign policy. TheEast Mississippi Business Development Corporationserves as a Chamber of Commerce and economic development organization in the east central part of the state. TheGreater Jackson Chamber Partnershipis an economic and community development organization in Mississippi's Capital Community.​​</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:4px;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Mississippi International Trade Resources</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about local trade resources and partners of the U.S. Export Assistance Center in Mississippi.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, Mississippi, trade, resources</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/411.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/411.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/411.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
