<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>418</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Houston U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Houston USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities offered by the Houston U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/24/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/23/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;text-align:justify;">The Houston U.S. Export Assistance Center has a limited number of unpaid internships to offer undergraduate and graduate students considering careers in international business. Only U.S. citizens are eligible for consideration. Applicants must be enrolled no less than half-time in an accredited college or university.</span></p><h2>Eligibility</h2><ul><li>Students must be U.S. citizens;</li><li>Must be enrolled at least part-time in a college or university; and,</li><li>Must be able to work at least 20 or more hours per week.</li></ul><h2>Major Areas of Study</h2><ul><li>All Business Majors, Economics, Political Science, Public Administration, Law, International Studies and Relations, Marketing, Finance, Foreign Language, Communications, Sociology, Geography and History.</li></ul><h2>Required Skills and Computer Knowledge</h2><ul><li>Proficient typing skills, data entry skills;</li><li><em></em>Proficient computer skills-<em>Windows XP or higher, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Internet Explorer, knowledge in information retrieval, and search engines;</em></li><li>Basic telephone etiquette skills, fax knowledge, and e-mail proficiency.</li></ul><h2>Responsibilities</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Throughout the internship the student will conduct a host of duties that range from responding to telephone inquiries concerning international trade to international market research. The value of the internship is centered on the research that the student will perform for the Houston USEAC office staff. Students will research Houston manufacturing and service companies to determine the extent of their international activities, assist companies in locating foreign agents and distributors for their products and services, and pursue foreign sales leads provided by commercial officers at U.S. Embassies abroad. Students will visit U.S. companies with Trade Specialists to discuss the clients' export readiness, assess which international markets to focus, and to create an action plan to pursue business abroad. Not only will the intern gain an insight into international market research and exporting, but the student will also acquire an understanding of the resources available to businesses at the city, state, and federal levels.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Interns will also have the opportunity to work on individual projects. Such projects may include recruiting for Foreign Trade Delegations and Trade Shows, and organizing Foreign Buyer Programs, taking part in trade development meetings with American and foreign government officials and executives in key industries, writing on international trade and regulatory issues involving trade negotiations, and promoting industry trade events to the international community.<br></p><h2>Duration of Internship</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Internships are usually for a period of three months and can be extended. The internship is a voluntary effort. No funds are available to cover any costs incurred during this internship. We request that an intern have at least 20 hours per week to dedicate to the internship.<br></p><h2>How to Apply</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Please email your cover letter, resume, and your completed application (see link below) toNyamusi Igambi, Senior International Trade Specialist and Intern Coordinatorat<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Nyamusi.Igambi@trade.gov">Nyamusi.Igambi@trade.gov</a>Questions? Please contact Ms. Igambi via email or at (713) 209-3112.<br><br>WE ARE CURRENTLY ACCEPTING APPLICATIONS.</p><h2>Application Deadlines:</h2><ul><li><strong>Fall Semester​</strong>- Application deadline July 15</li><li><strong>Spring Semester</strong>– Application deadline November 15</li><li><strong>Summer Semester</strong> – Application deadline April 15​</li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Houston U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities offered by the Houston U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Houston, Texas, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/418.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/418.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/418.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
