<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>432</id>
    <title>ITA Helps End Burdensome Re-Registration Requirements on Medical Devices in Korea</title>
    <short_title>ITA Smooths Medical Device Exports Path in Korea</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped to ease burdensome registration requirements for medical device manufacturers in Korea.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/25/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/25/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>ITA Helps End Burdensome Re-Registration Requirements on Medical Devices in Korea</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) helped U.S. medical device manufacturers overcome a Korean regulatory trade barrier that imposed onerous registration requirements on U.S. medical devices.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>Without ITA's assistance, U.S. companies with global supply chains would have been forced to register products by country of origin. This would have put them at a disadvantage compared to their domestic competition and prevented them from accessing Korea's multi-billion dollar medical device market.</p><h2>Problem </h2><p>In 2009, South Korea's Food and Drug Administration (KFDA) implemented regulations that required companies to register their goods by country of origin as a means of receiving approval. This resulted in costly redundancies as many U.S. companies with shifting global supply chains and were required to repeat the registration process if they relocated their production to a different country. As we noted previously, this put them at a severe disadvantage vis-à-vis Korean firms. Korea's actions raised concerns under the World Trade Organization's Technical Barriers to Trade Agreement, which requires that such regulations not be unnecessarily trade restrictive. AdvaMed, an association representing U.S. medical device companies, contacted ITA for assistance after it failed to receive a response from KFDA.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img alt="Medtronic Medical Devices" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/dc_korea_may2013.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br>Photo courtesy Medtronic Korea</p><h2>Solution</h2><p>ITA, working closely with other U.S. Government agencies and AdvaMed, raised industry's concerns with KFDA and successfully persuaded it to revise the relevant implementing regulations. Foreign medical device manufacturers and importers no longer need to re-register their products if they choose to relocate their production to another country.</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Excessive Government Requirements</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Asia<geo_subregion>East Asia</geo_subregion></geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Health Technologies</industry>
        <industry>Consumer Goods &amp; Home Furnishings</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>South Korea</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>ITA Helps End Burdensome Re-Registration Requirements on Medical Devices in Korea</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped to ease burdensome registration requirements for medical device manufacturers in Korea.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Medical Devices, Supply Chains, Trade Barriers, Government Regulations, Technical Barriers</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/432.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/dc_korea_may2013.jpg" name="dc_korea_may2013"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/432.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/432.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
