<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>442</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Wisconsin U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Wisconsin USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the Wisconsin U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/25/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/24/2014</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​<span style="line-height:1.6;">As part of the Commercial Service internship program for the U.S. Department of Commerce, an intern will work closely with International Trade Specialists. An intern's role is to help International Trade Specialists to develop and prepare market research, match local companies with international opportunities, and answer export-related questions from a wide variety of sources. Additionally, an intern gains a familiarity with export finance, marketing, cultural issues, and rigorous analyses in a fast-paced, real-world setting. Here at the Milwaukee U.S. Export Assistance Center, an intern will come to have a solid understand of the…</span></p><ul><li>Issues confronting small- to medium-sized companies in the international marketplace</li><li>Role of international trade in a regional economy</li><li>Problems that confront policy makers as they attempt to open international markets for U.S. products</li></ul><h2>Daily Activities and Responsibilities</h2><ul><li>Provide support to International Trade Specialists in outreach, market research, trade promotion, and international trade and policy development</li><li>Research and analysis on commercial markets worldwide</li><li>Research on policy and regulatory issues involving global markets</li><li>Develop and present reports based on research</li><li>Database management</li><li>Promotion of industry and trade education events</li><li>Fulfill duties of assisting visitors, handling telephone inquiries, and performing clerical and administrative support</li></ul><h2>Academic Major (s)/Areas of Study</h2><p>Interns majoring in Business (Finance, Marketing, etc.), Economics, Political Science, Public Administration, Law, International Studies and Relations, Foreign Language, Communications and History. *Priority will be given to business and international majors.</p><h2>Qualifications and Requirements</h2><h3>General Qualifications</h3><ul><li>Strong and consistent academic background</li><li>Solid analytical and research skills</li><li>Able to communicate effectively – written and orally – in an organized, logical format</li><li>Evidence of personal motivation, initiative, professionalism, and resourcefulness</li><li>Demonstrates strong interpersonal skills in person and on the phone</li></ul><h3>Eligibility Requirements</h3><ul><li>Able to use MS Office applications and email</li><li>At least 18 years of age</li><li>A U.S. citizen</li><li>A full or part-time student, enrolled in a degree-seeking program at an accredited academic institution with a minimum of a 3.0 GPA</li><li>Able to commit to at least 16-20 hours per week during the term.</li></ul><h3>Salary/Wage</h3><p>The internship is on a volunteer/unpaid basis; however, academic credit may be offered as arranged by your educational institution, and the valuable experience gained during the program can prove to be very beneficial in the future (especially if the intern is interested in working for the federal government). *If you are seeking paid Federal employment, please refer to<a href="http://www.usajobs.opm.gov/">http://www.usajobs.opm.gov</a>for a complete listing of job announcements.</p><h3>Application Process</h3><p>If you are an undergraduate or graduate student pursing an internship with us and meet the eligibility requirements, please send your application and cover letter to<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Damian.Felton@trade.gov">Damian.Felton@trade.gov</a>​.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Wisconsin U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the Wisconsin U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Wisconsin, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/442.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/442.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/442.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
