<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>456</id>
    <title>Harley-Davidson, the Motorcycle Manufacturer, Overcomes Bahrain Trade Barrier</title>
    <short_title>Harleys Overcome Bahrain Trade Barriers</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped overcome trade barriers in Bahrain to benefit Harley-Davidson.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/26/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/25/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Harley-Davidson, the Motorcycle Manufacturer, Overcomes Bahrain Trade Barrier</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) helped Harley-Davidson, headquartered in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, overcome a foreign trade barrier that threatened to prevent access of its motorcycles into Bahrain.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img alt="Motorcycles" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/harley_davidson.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br><em>Courtesy: Harley-Davidson USA</em></p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>If the United States did not assert its rights under the U.S. Bahrain FTA in the case of Harley-Davidson, other American businesses might find themselves losing benefits the U.S. negotiated as part of the agreement.</p><h2>The Problem</h2><p>Harley-Davidson was denied duty-free access for its motorcycles manufactured in the United States as provided for under the U.S.-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement (FTA); instead it was charged a 5 % duty. The Government of Bahrain (GOB) claimed that because the motorcycles were not imported directly into Bahrain from the United States and instead were transshipped (shipped through a third country), they therefore did not fulfill the FTA's rules of origin which would grant Harley-Davidson duty-free access.</p><h2>The Solution</h2><p>A team of ITA specialists and representatives from other USG agencies advocated on behalf of Harley-Davidson and provided specific guidance on the FTA rules of origin for transshipped goods which resulted in the GOB allowing for transshipment stop-overs. In addition, ITA and representatives from U.S. Customs and Border Protection provided training to Bahrain customs officers. Due to these efforts, Harley-Davidson was granted duty-free access and has received a refund of all duties paid from the Government of Bahrain. This solution will also benefit other U.S. exporters to Bahrain who transship their products. </p><p style="text-align:center;"></p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Tariff and Customs Barriers</sub_topic></topic>
        <topic>Free Trade Agreements<sub_topic>U.S.-Bahrain Free Trade Agreement</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Middle East</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Automotive &amp; Ground Transportation</industry>
        <industry>Consumer Goods &amp; Home Furnishings</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>Bahrain</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Harley-Davidson, the Motorcycle Manufacturer, Overcomes Bahrain Trade Barrier</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped overcome trade barriers in Bahrain to benefit Harley-Davidson.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Tariffs, Automotive Manufacturing, Border Barriers, </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/456.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/harley_davidson.jpg" name="harley_davidson"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/456.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/456.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
