<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>459</id>
    <title>Partner Organizations - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana</title>
    <short_title>Partner Organizations - Montana USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the partner organizations of the U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/26/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">​I</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">n order to better serve the needs of small ​business expansion into international markets, the U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana has partnered with other small business consulting and service providers. With these partnerships, exporters are better able to network and communicate with the global economy and, in turn, have better success at international expansion.</span></p><h2>Montana World Trade Center</h2><p>The Montana World Trade Center helps businesses establish and strengthen their international commercial capabilities. The Center develops untapped international trade opportunities and helps businesses capitalize on opportunities to expand their market share around the world.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.mwtc.org/">http://www.mwtc.org</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Department of Commerce</h2><p>The Montana Department of Commerce has set up exportmontana.com in order to give exporters the basic information needed to understand the complexities of moving product internationally as well as the tools to comply with export regulation.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.exportmontana.com/">http://www.exportmontana.com</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Manufacturing Extension Center</h2><p>The MMEC helps with practices for managing your equipment, building, processes, and people with hands-on consulting.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.mtmanufacturingcenter.com/">http://www.mtmanufacturingcenter.com​</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Small Business Development Centers &amp; Local Economic Development Corps.</h2><p>The Montana Small Business Development Centers (SBDCs) focus on the creation, retention and expansion of small businesses. SBDC offices offer customized local assistance to meet small business needs in their regional service areas. The SBDCs are a key access point to a broad network of public and private resources at the community level.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.sbdc.mt.gov/hosts.asp">http://www.sbdc.mt.gov/hosts.asp</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Small Business Administration (SBA)</h2><p>The U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA) was created as an independent agency of the federal government to aid, counsel, assist and protect the interests of small business concerns, to preserve free competitive enterprise and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of our nation.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/mt">http://www.sba.gov/mt</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Chamber of Commerce</h2><p>The Montana Chamber of Commerce has been Montana's leading business advocate since 1931. They represent and promote the interests of business at the national and state levels. Specifically, The Montana Chamber of Commerce is the advocate of business in Montana and the driving force for promoting a favorable business climate.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.montanachamber.com/">http://www.montanachamber.com​</a></li></ul><h2>Montana Department of Agriculture, Agricultural Development Division</h2><p>The Agricultural Development Division (ADD) is responsible for administering programs directed at promoting and enhancing Montana agriculture. Within the Division are four bureaus, the Rural Development Bureau, the Wheat and Barley Bureau, the Agriculture Marketing and Business Development Bureau, and the Montana State Grain Laboratory Bureau.</p><p>The Montana Wheat and Barley Bureau is responsible for marketing, promoting and encouraging intensive scientific and practical research in all phases of wheat and barley culture and production under the guidelines and policies developed by the Wheat and Barley Committee.</p><p>The Montana Wheat and Barley Committee (MWBC) is a producer-funded and directed check-off organization for wheat and barley growers in the state. The mission of the MWBC is to protect and foster the health, prosperity, and general welfare of the industry by encouraging and promoting intensive, scientific, and practical research into all phases of the wheat and barley culture and production, marketing, and end-use and, further, to aid in the development of markets for wheat and barley grown in Montana.</p><p>The Agriculture Marketing &amp; Business Development Bureau is responsible for market enhancement and development through direct market development activities, grants, seed capital loan investments in new and innovative products or process, marketing, and product development. Marketing and agri-business development personnel work closely with individuals and organizations to promote and enhance our agriculture industry.</p><p>Staff members assist exporters and those seeking international markets by providing access to federal financial assistance for international marketing, training on entering international markets, product promotion, regulatory assistance, and promotional efforts.</p><ul><li><a href="http://agr.mt.gov/business/busMktng.asp">http://agr.mt.gov/business/busMktng.asp</a></li><li><a href="http://wbc.agr.mt.gov/">http://wbc.agr.mt.gov/</a></li></ul><h2>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Foreign Agricultural Service</h2><p>The Foreign Agricultural Service (FAS) works to improve foreign market access for U.S. products. It operates programs designed to build new markets and improve the competitive position of U.S. agriculture in the global marketplace.</p><p>It is responsible for collecting, analyzing, and disseminating information about global supply and demand, trade trends, and market opportunities. FAS administers export financing and market development programs; provides export services; carries out food aid and market-related technical assistance programs; and provides linkages to world resources and international organizations.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.fas.usda.gov/">http://www.fas.usda.gov/</a></li></ul><h2>U.S. Department of Commerce, International Trade Administration</h2><p>The U.S. Commercial Service (USCS) is the trade promotion unit of the International Trade Administration.</p><p>U.S. Commercial Service trade specialists located in 107 U.S. cities and in more than 80 countries work with U.S. firms to help them get started in exporting or increase their sales to new global markets. USCS services include:</p><ul><li>World class market research</li><li>Trade events that promote US products and services to qualified buyers</li><li>Introductions to qualified buyers and distributors</li><li>Export counseling and advocacy</li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/montana/partnerorganizations/www.export.gov">www.export.gov</a></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/montana/partnerorganizations/www.buyusa.gov">www.buyusa.gov</a></li></ul><h2>U.S. Small Business Administration</h2><p>The U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA) is an independent agency of the federal government that aids, counsels, assists and protects the interests of small business concerns, and seeks to preserve free competitive enterprise and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of our nation. The mission objective of the SBA is to help Americans start, build and grow businesses.</p><p>SBA's Office of International Trade works to enhance the ability of small businesses to compete in the global marketplace; facilitates access to capital to support international trade; ensures that the interests of small business are considered and reflected in trade negotiations; and supports and contribute to the U.S. Government's international agenda.</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/aboutsba/sbaprograms/internationaltrade/index.html" style="line-height:1.6;">SBA Website</a><br></li></ul><p></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Partner Organizations - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the partner organizations of the U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Montana, partners</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/459.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/459.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/459.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
