<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>460</id>
    <title>ITA Ensures the Recall of Counterfeit Sporting Goods in Egypt</title>
    <short_title>Nike Gains Protection from Counterfeit Goods in Egypt</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped Nike overcome an intellectual property issue that risked damaging the company’s market share in Egypt and its international brand.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/26/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/25/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>ITA Ensures the Recall of Counterfeit Sporting Goods in Egypt</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) helped Nike, an Oregon-based consumer goods firm, overcome a high-profile intellectual property issue that risked damaging the company's market share in Egypt and its international brand.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>Intellectual property contributes significantly to the US economy and is important to many industries, including footwear and apparel.The outcome in this case – theEgyptian Olympic Committee (EOC) recalled the counterfeit sporting goods and allowed Nike to provide genuine products to Egyptian athletes – helped draw public attention to the importance of respecting U.S. intellectual property rights.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/or_egypt_jun2013.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /><br>Image Courtesy of Nike</p><h2>The Problem</h2><p>The Egyptian Olympic Committee (EOC) published a tender for the supply of &quot;sports outfits&quot; for the Egyptian delegation travelling to the 2012 London summer Olympics.The EOC awarded the contact to an unauthorized distributor, which provided the athletes with counterfeit uniform kits. Nike's authorized distributor in Egypt, Allied Trading and Consultancy, approached the EOC on several occasions about replacing the counterfeit uniforms with the legitimate product, but failed to receive a response from the EOC.</p><h2>The Solution</h2><p>ITA and U.S. embassies in Brussels, Cairo and London engaged with Nike,the Government of Egypt and its embassies in Washington, D.C., and London. This multi-channel engagement supported Nike's effortsand resulted in the EOC's acceptance of genuine Nike goods for the Egyptian athletes competing in the London 2012 Summer Olympics. In addition, the Government of Egypt indicated it will open an investigation into the EOC procurement practices. </p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Intellectual Property Infringement</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Middle East</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Textiles, Apparel &amp; Sporting Goods</industry>
        <industry>Consumer Goods &amp; Home Furnishings</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>ITA Ensures the Recall of Counterfeit Sporting Goods in Egypt</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration helped Nike overcome an intellectual property issue that risked damaging the company’s market share in Egypt and its international brand.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Brand Protection, Sporting Goods, Intellectual Property Infringement</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/460.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/or_egypt_jun2013.jpg" name="or_egypt_jun2013"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/460.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/460.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
