<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>461</id>
    <title>Montana District Export Council</title>
    <short_title>Montana District Export Council</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the Montana District Export Council.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/26/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Montana_DEC_logo.jpg" alt="Montana District Export Council logo" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><h2>Mission:</h2><p>The Montana District Export Council encourages and supports the export promotion efforts of other public and private organizations through partnership and collaboration, thereby creating a full-service export development infrastructure.<br></p><p>The Montana District Export Council (DEC) is a volunteer organization drawn from Montana State businesses, governmental agencies and non-profits. The members have in-depth knowledge and experience in international business and are available as a unique source of professional advice to help Montananscompete and win business in the international marketplace.<br></p><p>The Montana DEC works closely with the Montana U.S. Export Assistance Center and the public-private sector to accomplish its mission by:</p><ul><li>Coordinating the Governor's Excellence in Exporting &quot;Exporter of the Year&quot; nominations and awards</li><li>Promoting the export of Montana goods and services to strengthen the state's economy</li><li>Identifying issues affecting Montana's competitiveness in the global marketplace and advocating on behalf of Montana businesses</li><li>Promoting the importance of trade to Montana's economic performance</li><li>Enhancing the efforts of the Montana U.S. Export Assistance Center</li></ul><p>Established in 1973 by the President and the Secretary of Commerce, District Export Councils are mandated to support the export expansion activities of the U.S. Department of Commerce and serve as a link between the business community and U.S. Export Assistance Centers (USEAC) across the United States. Link to the National District Export Council website:<a href="http://www.us-dec.com/">http://www.us-dec.com/​</a>.</p><p>If you have an interest in contributing your knowledge and special talents to theMontana DEC, if we can provide a speaker for your event, or if we can answer your questions on international trade, finance, logistics, marketing or documentation, please contact us:</p><p><strong>Megan Harrington,</strong>Chair, Montana DEC:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:megan@.mwtc.org">megan@.mwtc.org</a></p><p><strong>Carey Hester,</strong>Executive Secretary, Montana DEC:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Carey.Hester@trade.gov">Carey.Hester@trade.gov</a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Montana District Export Council</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the Montana District Export Council.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Montana, export, council</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/461.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Montana_DEC_logo.jpg" name="Montana_DEC_logo"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/461.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/461.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
