<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>463</id>
    <title>Export Financing - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana</title>
    <short_title>Export Financing - Montana USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the assistance provided by the U.S. Small Business Administration to exporters in Oregon, southwest Washington, Idaho, and Montana.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/26/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/SBA_Your_Small_Business_Resource.jpg" alt="Logo for U.S. Small Business Administration - Your Small Business Resource" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><h2>Do You NeedFinancing?</h2><ul><li>Transaction financing to fill orders or a revolving line of credit for export sales</li><li>Purchase real estate or equipment for plant expansion related to exporting</li><li>Marketing funds for participation in overseas trade show, brochures, etc.</li><li>Supplier financing for pre-export inventory (manufacturing or trading companies)</li><li>Working capital to fulfill export service contracts</li><li>Bid or performance bonds for export projects</li></ul><p>The<strong>Small Business Administration</strong>has a representative in the Portland Export Center as a source of information / referrals / and financing assistance for<strong>exporters in the four state region of Oregon / SW Washington, Idaho, and Montana</strong>. The SBA staff's primary focus is to help your company obtain financing for any business purpose that can help start, strengthen, or grow your export sales. The SBA staff can provide access to SBA's export finance programs and information on other government guaranty programs that support exports, such as,<strong>the Export-Import Bank, Overseas Private Investment Corporation, etc.</strong></p><p>In addition, the SBA staff serves as a clearing house for your export financing questions and as source of information on how to insure payment from your foreign buyer, how to expand your plant and equipment with long-term financing, how to finance your short term needs with a revolving line of credit, or<strong>any other export finance related questions.</strong></p><p>Please contact<strong>Jeff Deiss at 503.326.5498.​​</strong></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Export Financing - U.S. Export Assistance Center of Montana</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the assistance provided by the U.S. Small Business Administration to exporters in Oregon, southwest Washington, Idaho, and Montana.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, financing, Montana, Small Business Administration</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/463.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/SBA_Your_Small_Business_Resource.jpg" name="SBA_Your_Small_Business_Resource"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/463.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/463.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
