<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>464</id>
    <title>ITA Utilizes Free Trade Agreement to Ensure Proper Customs Valuation and Appeal Procedures in Chile</title>
    <short_title>Free Trade Agreement with Chile Protects Epson</short_title>
    <summary>Learn how the International Trade Administration ensured customs valuation procedures in Chile in alignment with the in-force Free Trade Agreement.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/27/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/26/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Enforcement &amp; Compliance<source_office>Trade Agreements Negotiations and Compliance</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>​ITA Utilizes Free Trade Agreement to Ensure Proper Customs Valuation and Appeal Procedures in Chile</h1><p>The Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration (ITA) worked with Epson Chile (Epson), a wholly-owned subsidiary of Epson America Inc., based in Long Beach, CA, to ensure that Chile's customs valuation methods and appeal procedures complied with the World Trade Organization's (WTO) Customs Valuation Agreement and the U.S.-Chile Free Trade Agreement (FTA).</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>If the U.S. government (USG) had not ensured Chile's adherence to the relevant provisions under the WTO Customs Valuation Agreement and the U.S.-Chile FTA, the additional costs that Epson faced would have significantly impacted the competitiveness of its exports to the Chilean market. Inconsistent customs valuation procedures can cause uncertain business transactions and reduce the confidence of U.S. companies seeking to export to new markets.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/ca_chile_apr2013.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /><br>Courtesy of Epson America</p><h2>The Problem</h2><p>In February 2008, Epson reported to that Chile's respective customs agency had accused the company ofundervaluing itsimports of ink cartridges and other printing supplies. Epson maintained that it had not undervalued its goods and that it should not be subject to over $4 million in potential penalties and fines.</p><h2>The Solution</h2><p>Advocating on behalf of Epson, ITA officials, along with other USG agencies, supported Epson by raising its concerns with the Chilean government and pressing the importance of transparent customs valuation procedures and predictable appeal mechanisms consistent with its trade agreement obligations. In early 2012, the Chilean Customs' administrative review system found that Epson was not guilty of undervaluing its products, in turn demonstrating the value of the WTO Customs Valuation Agreement and the U.S.-Chile FTA. </p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Problems<sub_topic>Tariff and Customs Barriers</sub_topic></topic>
        <topic>Free Trade Agreements<sub_topic>U.S.-Chile Free Trade Agreement</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>South America</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Consumer Goods &amp; Home Furnishings</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>ITA Utilizes Free Trade Agreement to Ensure Proper Customs Valuation and Appeal Procedures in Chile</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn how the International Trade Administration ensured customs valuation procedures in Chile in alignment with the in-force Free Trade Agreement.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Printer Ink Manufacturer, Tariffs, WTO Customs Valuation Agreement , Valuations. Border Barriers</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/464.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/ca_chile_apr2013.jpg" name="ca_chile_apr2013"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/464.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/464.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
