<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>494</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities</title>
    <short_title>Internship Opportunities</short_title>
    <summary>Opportunities for undergraduate and graduate students to intern with the Advocacy Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/29/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/4/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Advocacy Center Internships </strong></h1><p>The Advocacy Center has an on-going need for energetic, enthusiastic undergraduate and graduate students to intern with us. We offer an excellent opportunity for students to learn how the U.S. Government assists U.S. companies win foreign government tenders. </p><h2><strong>Duties</strong></h2><p>Interns will help staff with day-to-day operations of the Advocacy Center. These tasks include the following: </p><ul><li>Process requests for advocacy assistance from U.S. companies, interacting with representatives of U.S. companies, U.S. Embassies, other ITA units and other U.S. Government agencies to evaluate these requests; </li><li>Assist in preparation for Cabinet or Sub-Cabinet members' trade missions, contract signings and other trade events; </li><li>Document successful advocacy efforts; </li><li>Gather and prepare information on advocacy efforts for senior ITA management; </li><li>Attend interagency staff meetings in which policy and advocacy strategies are developed for U.S. companies; </li><li>Input new advocacy requests into the Center's project database and files; and </li><li>Handle special projects as they arise. </li></ul><h2><strong>Important Qualifications</strong></h2><p>The Advocacy Center is looking for interns who are interested in U.S. trade promotion and export assistance programs geared to U.S. companies. Interns should be self-motivated, comfortable with a fast-paced work environment, have good writing skills and experience with word processing and spreadsheet programs. Experience with Lexis-Nexis and Lotus Notes software would also be helpful, but not required. You must be a U.S. citizen to work for the federal government. </p><p>Work schedules are flexible, but we require interns to work at least 24 hours per week. This internship is unpaid but offers an excellent opportunity to meet and network with U.S. Government officials and private sector representatives involved in international trade. We can arrange for you to get academic credit. </p><h2><strong>To Apply </strong></h2><p>If you are interested in applying for a position, please fax or mail a cover letter, your resume, your transcripts and a brief writing sample (one to three pages) to <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Amy.Tabine@trade.gov">Amy Tabine</a> at the Advocacy Center. </p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>U.S. Department of Commerce </strong><br><strong>The Advocacy Center </strong><br><strong>Room 2840 </strong><br><strong>14th Street &amp; Constitution Avenue, N.W. </strong><br><strong>Washington, DC 20230 </strong><br><strong>Phone Number: (202) 482-3896 </strong><br><strong>Fax Number: (202) 482-3508</strong></p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Promotion</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Information &amp; Communication</industry>
        <industry>Education</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>National Export Initiative</trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Advocacy</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>National Export Initiative</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Opportunities for undergraduate and graduate students to intern with the Advocacy Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>trade promotion, export assistance program, internships, intern</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/494.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/494.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/494.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
