<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>498</id>
    <title>Updates for Exporters - New Hampshire U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Updates for Exporters - New Hampshire USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about New Hampshire's top trading partners and other important information for exporters from the New Hampshire U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/29/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/28/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p><em><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/NH_updates.jpg" alt="Image of flags, cargo ship, and a body of water" style="margin:5px;" /><br></em></p><p><em>Market Reports</em>: International regulations and overseas opportunities change frequently. Included to the right are a few reports highlighting some recent changes to certain countries which might interest New Hampshire exporters. The full U.S. Commercial Service market research library can be searched by country or industry sector by clicking<a href="http://export.gov/mrktresearch/index.asp">here</a>or sign up to receive industry reports and trade leads based on your industry sector by clicking<a href="http://export.gov/industry/index.asp">here</a>.​</p><p><em>Smart Traveler Enrollment Program (STEP)</em>: The Smart Traveler Enrollment Program (STEP) is a free service provided by the U.S. Government to U.S. citizens who are traveling to, or living in, a foreign country. For more information, please visit:<a href="https://step.state.gov/step/">https://step.state.gov/step/</a>.</p><p><em>Top Trading Partners</em>: As of June 2013, New Hampshire's Top 20 international partners were:</p><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;">1. Canada</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;">11. Italy</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">2. Mexico</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">12. Brazil</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">3. China</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">13. Australia</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">4. Germany</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">14. UAE</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">5. Netherlands</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">15. Singapore</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">6. Hong Kong</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">16. South Korea</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">7. United Kingdom</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">17. Saudi Arabia</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">8. France</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">18. Thailand</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">9. Japan</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">19. Taiwan</td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">10. Turkey</td><td class="ms-rteTable-default">20. Sweden</td></tr></tbody></table><p><em>Bureau of Industry and Security</em>: As of April 2012, the Bureau of Industry and Security (BIS) has established a webpage where sources of publicly available information on Commodity Classifications can be found. If your company currently has, or plans to have, Commodity Classification information available on your company's website, or an export control point of contact, and you would like this information to be accessible via the BIS website, please visit<a href="http://www.bis.doc.gov/commodityclassificationpage.htm">http://www.bis.doc.gov/commodityclassificationpage.htm</a>.</p><p><em>U.S. Export Control Reform:</em>In August 2009, the President directed a broad-based interagency review of the U.S. export control system, with the goal of strengthening national security and the competitiveness of key U.S. manufacturing and technology sectors by focusing on current threats, as well as adapting to the changing economic and technological landscape. Updates on this process are available here:<a href="http://export.gov/ecr/">http://export.gov/ecr/</a>.</p><p><em>Harmonized System Updates</em>: The World Customs Organization's (WCO) recommended changes to the Harmonized System (HS) are scheduled to take effect on or about January 2012. These major changes usually take place every 5 years. For full details, please click visit<a href="http://export.gov/logistics/eg_main_042517.asp">http://export.gov/logistics/eg_main_042517.asp</a>.</p><p><em>New International E-Scams and Warnings from the FBI</em>: Recent analysis from the FBI and other government agencies demonstrates that malicious actors are targeting travelers abroad through pop-up windows while they are establishing an Internet connection in their hotel rooms. For the full story, please visit<a href="http://www.fbi.gov/scams-safety/e-scams">http://www.fbi.gov/scams-safety/e-scams</a>.</p><p><em>ATA Carnet Updates</em>: The U.S. Government is engaging the Brazilian government on the use of ATA Carnets. The ATA Carnet, an internationally accepted customs document, would facilitate the temporary importation of commercial samples, professional equipment, and goods for exhibitions and fairs. Legislation to implement ATA Carnet is currently under consideration in Brazil's Congress. For a full list of countries which accept the ATA carnet or to sign up for notification on new countries, please visit<a href="http://www.uscib.org/index.asp?documentID=1582">http://www.uscib.org/index.asp?documentID=1582</a>.</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Updates for Exporters - New Hampshire U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about New Hampshire's top trading partners and other important information for exporters from the New Hampshire U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, New Hampshire, updates, exporters</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/498.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/NH_updates.jpg" name="NH_updates"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/498.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/498.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
