<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>509</id>
    <title>Local Events - Utah U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Local Events - Utah USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about events presented by the Utah U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/29/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/29/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>UpcomingExport Events</h2><h3>September 16- Hot Topics for Export Compliance Professionals</h3><p><br>The Salt Lake Chamber, the World Trade Center Utah, the U.S. Foreign &amp; Commercial Service Utah, &amp; the Utah District Export Council invite you to participate in this unique, hands-on practical application-oriented workshop for Export Compliance Professionals.<br><br>This Timely, Engaging, and Interactive Program Will Address:</p><ul><li><strong></strong>Evolving regulatory requirements in the context of Export Control Reform (ECR) with a focus on the Export Administration Regulations and International Traffic in Arms Regulations.</li><li><strong></strong>Dramatic changes as a result of the migration and transfer of items from the US Munitions List to the Commerce Control List.</li><li><strong></strong>Key areas for managing export compliance, exposure, liability and risk.</li><li><strong></strong>The potential and sometimes devastating consequences of non-compliance and What Happens When You Are Not Where You Need to Be on ECR</li><li><strong></strong>References, resources and real world case study lessons learned.</li><li><strong></strong>Best practices, recommended approaches, ECR and proven solutions for a variety of real world export compliance challenges &amp; opportunities.</li></ul><p><strong>When:</strong>Tuesday, September 16, 2014, from 7:30 AM - 5:00 PM<br><strong>Where:</strong>Salt Lake Chamber, 175 East University Boulevard (400 South) Suite 600, Salt Lake City, Utah 84111<br><strong>Registration:</strong>$195/person. Registration deadline is Friday, September 12.<br><strong>Questions?</strong>Please contact Elizabeth Goryunova, WTC Utah, 801-532-8080,<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:egorn@wtcut.com">egorn@wtcut.com</a>.<br><br><em>For full program information, including agenda and link to registration, please click</em><em><a href="http://saltlakeutcoc.weblinkconnect.com/events/Workshops-for-Export-Compliance-Professionals-4396/details">here</a></em><em>.</em><br></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~</strong><br></p><h3>September 24- Utah Global Forum</h3><p><br>The Utah Global Forum will facilitate the dialogue on how businesses can expand beyond local borders and develop a strategy of expansion into the global marketplace. The program offers an incredible breadth of content, bringing experts from across industry, all with a single objective: move Utah businesses to the global business stage to meet the challenges of today's business environment.<br><br><strong>When:</strong>Wednesday, September 24, 9:00 am- 5:00 pm<br><strong>Where:</strong>100 SW Temple, Salt Lake City, Utah 84101<br><strong>Registration:</strong>$95/person by September 10; $115/person thereafter.<br><br><em>For details, including program agenda, speaker bios, and link to registration please click</em><em><a href="http://www.utahglobalforum.com/">here</a></em><em>.</em></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~</strong></p><h3>October 24- November 1:Mountain West Trade Mission to the United Arab Emirates &amp; Turkey</h3><p><br>Zions Bank, in coordination with the U.S. &amp; Foreign Commercial Service offices in Utah, Idaho, and Montana, the World Trade Center Utah, andadditional trade promotion partners,issupporting a trade mission of businesses from the Mountain Westregionto the UAE and Turkey, October 24- November 1, 2014. This trade missionpresents an excellent opportunity to meet potential partners or buyers in these two dynamic, regional gateway markets. For trade mission details, please click<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ut/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ut_077930.pdf">here</a>.<br><br><strong>The United Arab Emirates (UAE)</strong>is federation of seven emirates located on the Arabian Peninsula. The UAE's prosperity is based in large part on the country's vast oil and gas reserves, most of which lie in the largest emirate, Abu Dhabi. It is one of the wealthiest nations in the world with per capita GDP in 2012 approaching $50,000. The UAE, particularly the emirate of Dubai, has long been recognized as the commercial and business hub of the Middle East and beyond. With a $300 billion a year economy and excellent infrastructure, the UAE affords an excellent location for U.S. companies to conduct business in the region. The presence of almost 1,000 American firms in the UAE underlines this fact. The UAE has developed a leading role in business services, including finance, and has effectively created a logistics hub between east and west. It is home to one of the busiest man-made port in the world, Jebel Ali as well as two of the fastest growing airlines in the world, Emirates and Etihad. The country has no corporate taxes (with the exception of banks and foreign oil companies that have concessions in UAE oilfields), no income taxes, and a relatively low import duty of five percent on most products.<strong><em>For more information on leading industry sectors for U.S. companies in UAE, click</em></strong><a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ut/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ut_075668.pdf"><em>here</em></a><strong><em>.</em></strong><br><br><strong>Turkey's</strong>rapidly expanding economy, political and economic stability, and the possibility of EU membership continues to attract the attention of a variety of American companies. In 2011, U.S. exports to Turkey reached a record $14.7 billion, and while 2012 brought a slight decline in exports ($12.6 billion), total U.S.- Turkey trade remained at a near record of more than $19 billion. Turkey's financial sector is stronger than that of many other countries, due in part to a series of reforms in the wake of the 2001 financial crisis which left Turkish banks better leveraged than many of their U.S. and European counterparts.<strong></strong>Across many sectors, U.S. exporters have excellent immediate and medium-term prospects in this diverse market.<strong><em>For more information on leading prospective industry sectors for U.S. companies in Turkey, click</em></strong><a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ut/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ut_075654.pdf"><em>here</em></a><strong><em>.</em></strong><br><br><strong>What the trade mission will offer you and your business in the UAE and Turkey:</strong><br><br>• Meet prescreened business contacts face-to-face, including potential agents, distributors, buyers and joint-venture partners, in one-on-one appointments scheduled for you in advance.<br>• Connect with industry decision-makers and government officials at VIP networking receptions.<br>• Engage with U.S., UAE, and Turkish business leaders already successfully operating in the UAE and Turkey. Assess the business climate, trade policies and market opportunities to determine if the UAE and Turkey are right for your business.<br>• Enjoy group business and cultural excursions in Dubai, Abu Dhabi, and Istanbul.<br><br><strong>For additional information on logistics and fees associated with the trade mission, please contact: Tausha Dingman,</strong><a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:tausha.dingman@zionsbank.com">tausha.dingman@zionsbank.com</a><strong>, 801-309-0950</strong><br><br><strong>For additional information on Gold Key Service programming during the trade mission and how to register, please contact: Shelby Peterson,</strong><a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:shelby.peterson@trade.gov">shelby.peterson@trade.gov</a><strong>, 801-255-1872</strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~</strong></p><h3>Fall 2014 - Executive Certificate of Global Business Management Course</h3><p><br>The Salt Lake Community College Global Business Resource Center is now accepting applications for the fall 2014 &quot;Executive Certificate of Global Business Management&quot; Course. The Course is offered to business executives, professionals, working staff, entrepreneurs, and qualified students who wish to increase their exporting knowledge and improve their strategies in global business practices.<br><br>This Certificate course consists of 30 hours of class instruction. It includes a professional text and supplements designed to help guide businesses and professionals into the world market place. The course is a hands-on course taught by experts and leading professional practitioners and will provide how-to instruction on exporting your products and services including, international marketing, market research, financing exports/getting paid, shipping your products, and more.<br><br>Classes start October 1, 2014 and end December 10, 2014. A total of 10 classes will be on Wednesday evenings with each class lasting 3 hours (6:00 PM - 9:00 PM). (No class during the Thanksgiving week.) The class will limited to 18 persons so please register as soon as possible to reserve your place.<br><br>The cost of the course is $995. Discounts for the course are available through the State of Utah Custom Fit training program and the State of Utah Short Term Intensive Training (STIT) program.<br><br>To pre-register or for additional information on this professional development opportunity, contact Stan Rees of the Global Business Center at 801-957-5336 or mail:<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:stan.rees@slcc.edu">stan.rees@slcc.edu</a>. Registration deadline is September 23, 2014.</p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~</strong></p><h2>Upcoming Industry &amp; Market Webinars</h2><p>U.S &amp; Foreign Commercial Services offices worldwide regularly organize educational webinars for U.S. exporters.</p><p><strong><em>For details and registration, click</em></strong><a href="http://export.gov/eac/show_short_trade_events.asp?CountryName=null&amp;StateName=null&amp;IndustryName=null&amp;TypeName=Webinar&amp;StartDate=null&amp;EndDate=null"><em>here</em></a><strong><em>.</em></strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~</strong></p><h2>UtahExport News</h2><p><em><a href="http://www.brookings.edu/research/reports/2010/07/26-mountain-exports-muro">Export West: How Intermountain West Metros Can Lead National Export Growth and Boost Competitiveness</a></em>- Brookings Institution Report</p><p><em><a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/blog/76846/export-west-utah-the-place">Export West: Utah is the Place!</a></em>- The New Republic</p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong>​~</strong></p><p><strong><em>*For a calendar of upcoming international related events, please see the World Trade Center Utah's community event calendar:</em></strong><em><a href="http://www.wtcut.com/calendar.php">http://www.wtcut.com/calendar.php</a></em><strong><em>.​</em></strong></p><h2><br></h2>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Local Events - Utah U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about events presented by the Utah U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Utah, events </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/509.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/509.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/509.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
