<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>515</id>
    <title>Utah Export Resources</title>
    <short_title>Utah Export Resources</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about resources available for exporters in Utah.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/30/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/29/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><h2>International Trade Website Links</h2><p>The international trade links on this page aresorted bysubject andcontain the following information:</p><p></p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Getting Started- lists basic guides, trade portals, and otheruseful links to help businessesbegin the exporting process</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Market Research-includes market research guides, trade statistics, and other information</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Market Development- provides both general and country-specific resourcesfor developing markets</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Export Regulations and Standards- lists a variety of useful links on topicsranging from medical device regulations to European Union regulations</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">U.S. Government Export Finance Programs- includes a trade finance guide linkas well asotherexport finance tools</span><br></li></ul><p></p><p>Thisoverview covers only a small amount of information within the &quot;International Trade Website Links&quot; page. Forthe fulllist of trade links sorted by subject, click<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/localexportresources/internationaltradewebsites/index.asp">here</a>.</p><h2>Utah World Trade Resource Directory</h2><p>This guide contains a wealth of resource data, including listings of federal, state, and local government, educational, and private organizations that can provide you with information and/or assistance you may need in doing international business. To access the directory, go to:<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/utahworldtraderesourcedirectory/index.asp">Utah World Trade Resource Directory</a>.</p><h2>Utah U.S. Export Assistance Center Partner Organizations</h2><p>This page lists Utah USEAC business development partners. Fora list ofour partners, includingsome area-specific ones, click<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/localexportresources/partners/index.asp">here</a>.</p><h2>The International Representatives &amp; Distributors Guide</h2><p>This guide provides thorough insight and guidance on the process of finding the perfectinternational buyer and distributor,writing the perfect contract, and then how help them become themost effective and efficient business partner.To view this document, please click the link on the right entitled &quot;Find Them, Sign Them, &amp; Enhance Their Performance.&quot;</p><h2>International Trade Finance Resource Guide</h2><p><strong></strong>The purpose of this guide is to provide exporters, in the states of the mountain west, information on the various private and public sector organizations that can help a firm with its export financing needs as well as a general description of the various types of export financing. To view this document, please click the link on the right entitled &quot;International Trade Finance Resource Guide.​&quot;</p><h2>Utah District Export Council</h2><p>The Utah District Export Council (DEC) is a volunteer organization comprised of Utah businesspeople appointed by the U.S. Secretary of Commercewho contribute leadership and international trade expertise to complement the U.S. Commercial Service Utah's export promotion efforts throughcounseling and mentoringUtah business's and conducting trade educationas well ascommunity outreach.</p><p>For a list of Utah DEC members, click<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/utahdistrictexportcouncil/list/index.asp">here</a>.</p><p>For additional information on the DEC organization, click<a href="http://www.export.gov/utah/utahdistrictexportcouncil/members/index.asp">here</a>.</p><h2>Resource Guide to the U.S. Foreign Corrupt Practices Act</h2><p>The Guide is an excellent resource on the FCPA for U.S. companies with questions about the statute and its enforcement. The Guide explains the statute in detail and contains hypotheticals, examples of actual enforcement actions, and summaries of FCPA case law and DOJ opinion releases. For a PDF of the guide click<a href="http://www.justice.gov/criminal/fraud/fcpa/guide.pdf">here</a>.</p><h2>China Business Handbook</h2><p><strong></strong>This handbook is a resource guide for doing business in China. To see the updated version click<a href="http://export.gov/china/build/groups/public/%40eg_cn/documents/webcontent/eg_cn_037539.pdf">here</a>.</p><h2>Resources for the International Business Traveler</h2><p>This page provides links to State Department travel warnings, Country specific Holidays, Business Etiquette, Exchange Rates and more. Click<a href="http://export.gov/utah/resourcesfortheinternationalbusinesstraveler/index.asp">here</a>.​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Utah Export Resources</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about resources available for exporters in Utah.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Utah, resources</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/515.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/515.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/515.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
