<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>526</id>
    <title>Welcome to the Middle Tennessee – Nashville U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Nashville USEAC Homepage</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the Middle Tennessee – Nashville U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>9/30/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>9/29/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Nashville%20homepage.jpg" alt="Photo of Nashville and Cumberland River" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><p>The U.S. Commercial Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce is a federal government agency dedicated to helpingU.S. companies export their products and services. For over 30 years the U.S. Commercial Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce has successfully brought together exporters and importers of U.S. goods and services around the world. Our team of more than 1,800 trade professionals in 105 U.S. cities and 151 U.S. Embassies, Consulates and Trade Centers around the worldis here to help companies navigate the complex international trade process. The Nashville Export Assistance Center covers Middle Tennessee to include the cities of Franklin, Clarksville, Cookeville, Dickson, Gallatin, Lebanon, Murfreesboro and Tullahoma. Follow us on Twitter and LinkedIn!</p><span style="line-height:1.6;text-align:justify;"><a href="https://twitter.com/NashvilleUSEAC"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/twitter_logo.jpg" alt="Twitter logo" style="margin:5px;" /></a><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/groups/Nashville-USEAC-7433868"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/linkedin_logo.jpg" alt="LinkedIn logo" style="margin:5px;" /></a> </span><strong style="line-height:1.6;text-align:justify;">For Middle Tennessee Exporters!</strong><span style="line-height:20.7999992370605px;"><b><br></b></span><strong style="line-height:1.6;text-align:justify;"></strong><h2>The U.S. Commercial Service assists U.S. companies in exporting by:</h2><ul><li>Providing expert consulting, counseling, advice, and advocacy</li><li>Producing research on overseas markets and industries</li><li>Promoting your product and service in overseas markets</li><li>Finding international partners (agents, distributors, JV, licensing, etc.)</li></ul><p>The U.S. Commercial Service office in Nashville combines these services and its global network with the trade finance expertise and programs of the U.S. Small Business Administration and the Export-Import Bank of the United States to help make you a successful exporter.</p><p><em><strong>Consider the U.S. Commercial Service your first stop for export consulting, information and guidance! Talk to one of our</strong></em><a href="http://export.gov/tennessee/nashville/nashvillestaffdirectory/index.asp"><em>trade specialists</em></a><em><strong>today!</strong></em></p><p><strong>The Nashville Export Assistance Center serves the following Tennessee counties:</strong>Bedford, Bledsoe, Cannon, Cheatham, Clay, Coffee, Cumberland, Davidson, DeKalb, Dickson, Fentress, Franklin, Giles, Grundy, Hickman, Houston, Humphreys, Jackson, Lawrence, Lewis, Lincoln, Macon, Marion, Marshall, Maury, Montgomery, Overton, Perry, Pickett, Robertson, Rutherford, Sequatchie, Smith, Stewart, Sumner, Trousdale, Van Buren, Warren, Wayne, White, Williamson and Wilson.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Welcome to the Middle Tennessee – Nashville U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the Middle Tennessee – Nashville U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Nashville, Tennessee</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/526.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Nashville%20homepage.jpg" name="Nashville%20homepage"/>
      <image src="/Files/twitter_logo.jpg" name="twitter_logo"/>
      <image src="/Files/linkedin_logo.jpg" name="linkedin_logo"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/526.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/526.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
