<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>540</id>
    <title>Newark Internship Opportunities</title>
    <short_title>Newark Internships</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities offered by the Newark office of the New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/2/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/2/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align:center;"><strong>We are accepting applications.</strong></h2><p><br></p><p>The<strong><em>U.S. Department of Commerce Northern New Jersey</em></strong>Office offers challenging internships to graduate and undergraduate students who are considering a career in international business. Students who are United States citizens and have an interest in international trade should apply.</p><p>The mission of the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service is to assist small and medium-sized firms engaged in international trade. The Northern New Jersey Office of the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service achieves this mission by providing one-on-one business counseling services, foreign contact and sales leads, and market information on products and services.</p><p>Being the premier government organization involved in international trade with a worldwide field presence, the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service can offer a unique internship opportunity in international business. To learn more about our organization please visit:<a href="http://www.export.gov/">www.export.gov</a></p><h2>The purpose of the internship is three-fold:</h2><ol><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">To provide a problem-solving perspective within a &quot;real world&quot; professional environment.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">To provide the stud</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">ent with the ability to creatively link the theoretical world of philosophies, values, and techniques with practical and immediate tasks and goals.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">To provide the student with an inside awareness of the agencies, individuals, and programs associated with the student's specialized area of interest.</span><br></li></ol><p>Throughout the internship the student will conduct a host of duties that include:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Responding to telephone inquiries concerning international trade</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">International market research</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Research New Jersey companies to determine the extent of their international activities, assist New Jersey companies in locating foreign agents and distributors for their products, and pursue foreign sales leads provided by commercial officers at U.S. embassies abroad.</span><br></li></ul><p>The value of the internship is centered on the research and outreach that the student will perform for the office staff. Not only will the intern gain an insight into international market research and exporting, but the student also acquires an understanding of the resources available to businesses who seek to penetrate overseas markets on their own.</p><h2>Required Skills</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Proficient typing skills, data entry skills</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Proficiency in Microsoft Office Programs</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Proficient internet skills using Microsoft Internet Explorer, knowledge in information retrieval, search engines</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Strong telephone etiquette skills, and ability to speak confidently</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Some level of international trade experience or foreign language capability preferred</span><br></li></ul><p>Please note the internship is a<strong>voluntary effort.</strong> No funds are available to cover any costs incurred during this internship. We request that an intern have at least 12 to 16 hours a week to offer.</p><p>To apply , please email a cover letter and resume to<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Ryan.Hollowell@trade.gov">Ryan.Hollowell@trade.gov</a>.​</p><h2 style="text-align:center;"><br></h2>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Newark Internship Opportunities</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities offered by the Newark office of the New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, Newark, New Jersey</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/540.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/540.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/540.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
