<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>550</id>
    <title>Local Events - New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers</title>
    <short_title>Local Events - New Jersey USEACs</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about events presented by the New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/4/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/3/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Visit</strong><a href="http://www.njdec.org/events/month/">http://www.njdec.org/events/month/​</a><strong>to ​view a complete list of international related events happening in NJ, brought to you by the NJ District Export Council (DEC)</strong></p><h2>Discover Global Markets: Greater China Business Forum</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">A two-day conference that will provide numerous opportunities for your company to learn from experts with real-world experience in Greater China markets. Join the U.S. Department of Commerce on<strong>October 7-8, 2014 in New York City</strong>for a unique opportunity to gain insights and contacts to help you access export opportunities in Greater China.</p><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default"><tbody><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:100%;"><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Meet one-on-one with U.S. Commercial Service diplomats.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Acquire practical and actionable market intelligence on the world's fastest-growing major economy.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Obtain the resources necessary to succeed in the challenging, but rewarding markets of Greater China.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Any U.S. company that is already an experienced exporter and is seeking to learn about how to successfully sell its products and services in the Greater China region should consider joining the Forum.</span><br></li><li><a href="http://www.export.gov/newyork/discover/index.asp">Click here to learn more about this event!​</a><br></li></ul></td></tr></tbody></table><h2>NJ Technology &amp; Manufacturing Association presents The Remaking of American Manufacturing in NJ</h2><p></p><p>Wednesday, October 15, 2014</p><p>Hotel Woodbridge @ Metropark (formerly the Hilton Woodbridge)</p><p>120 Wood Avenue South, Iselin</p><p>Register online:Register Now</p><p><em>Event Speakers:</em></p><p><strong>The US Department of Commerce International Trade Administration's</strong>(ITA) Northern NJ Export Assistance Center. This federal government office assists New Jersey exporters navigate the world of international business.</p><p><strong>The Alliance for American Manufacturing</strong>is a non-profit, non-partisan partnership​ formed in 2007 by some of America's leading manufacturers and the United Steelworkers. Our mission is to strengthen American manufacturing and create new private-sector jobs through smart public policies. We believe that an innovative and growing manufacturing base is vital to America's economic and national security, as well as to providing good jobs for future generations. AAM achieves its mission through research, public education, advocacy, strategic communications, and coalition building around the issues that matter most to America's manufacturers and workers. The presenter is Mr. Brian Lombardozzi,VP of state governmental affairs.</p><p><strong>The New Jersey Business Action Center</strong>plays a key role in helping grow, retain and attract business to the State. The center serves as a &quot;one-stop&quot; shop for business. The team at the Center works to encourage entrepreneurship by supporting New Jersey's businesses of all sizes, supporting global competitiveness of New Jersey companies, as well as to promote the State's attractiveness as a vacation destination and business investment location nationally and internationally. The presenter will be Mr. Steven Stegman.</p><h2>IC-Disc Seminar</h2><p><em>Livingston, New Jersey</em></p><p><em>For decades IC-DISC has been saving companies money – why aren't you using it?</em> Join the U.S. Commercial Service in collaboration with Sobel &amp; Co. LLC., on Thursday, October 30, 2014 for an IC-DISC seminar focused on educating U.S. exporters on how to navigate U.S. laws to save on their tax liability for exports. Sobel &amp; Co. LLC is an experienced tax accounting firm with years of experience in helping U.S. businesses take advantage of this little known program. At the seminar you will hear from accounting experts and current clients on the benefits of the IC-Disc program used to help grow their bottom line.</p><p><em>Who should attend</em><strong>:</strong>Presidents, CEOs, Vice Presidents, CFOs, Accountants, Export Managers, and Compliance Managers.</p><p><em>To learn more, contact Brian Beams at</em><a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Brian.Beams@trade.gov"><em>Brian.Beams@trade.gov</em></a><em>.</em></p><p>Register here:<a href="http://go.usa.gov/p88F">http://go.usa.gov/p88F</a>.</p><h2>Automated Export System Compliance Seminar and AESPcLink Training</h2><p><em>Location:</em></p><p>Double Tree by Hilton Hotel Newark Airport<br>443-895-8881<br>128 Frontage Rd<br>Newark, New Jersey 07114<br></p><h3>Export Compliance Program</h3><p>December 10th, 2014 8:00 AM ‐ 5:00 PM</p><p>The Export Compliance Seminar is an all day program where experts from the Department of Commerce will provide training on export filing requirements. Highlights include:</p><ul><li>Mandatory filing requirements</li><li>How to avoid common penalties and seizure of cargo</li><li>Best practices for maintaining compliance with export regulations</li><li>BIS export control requirements</li><li>Overview of Export Control Classification Numbers (ECCN)</li><li>How to classify your product</li></ul><p>$249.00 per person includes breakfast and lunch​</p><p>Thursday December 11th, 2014 8:00 AM ‐ 11:30 AM or 1:00 PM ‐ 4:30 PM</p><p>The AESPcLink Workshop is a 3 1/2 hour program that provides hands‐on experience for the reporting of Electronic Export Information (EEI) through the AESPcLink system. Highlights include:</p><ul><li>Learn how to use AESPClink</li><li>Create shipment templates</li><li>Practice reporting export information</li><li>Learn how to become AES certified</li></ul><p>$75.00 per person</p><p>For more informationand to register for either of these events, visit:<a href="https://classic.regonline.com/builder/site/?eventid=1425179">https://classic.regonline.com/builder/site/?eventid=1425179​</a>.</p><h2>TRADE MISSION</h2><h3 style="text-align:center;">HealthcareEquipment, Services, &amp; Technologies</h3><h3 style="text-align:center;">Egypt, Jordan, &amp; Israel</h3><p>The USDOC is organizing a business development mission to Egypt, Jordan and Israel, with an optional stop in the West Bank with the purpose of introducing representatives from U.S. firms and related trade associations to the region and to promote exports of U.S. healthcare products and services. Mission participants will receive market briefings and participate in customized meetings with prospective partners.<em>Targeted sectors include</em>Maternal and child health needs, Medical equipment and supplies, including diagnostic, monitoring, and imaging equipment, Hospital and outpatient clinic design, Hospital management, E-health: healthcare management systems/software/network design, Laboratory and scientific equipment, Specialty areas such as oncology, cardiology, wound care, and plastic surgery, Products and services for implementing quality standards and accreditation, Robotics, and Mobile clinics.</p><ul><li><strong>When</strong>: May 16–21, 2015</li><li><strong>Where</strong>: Egypt, Jordan and Israel, with an optional stop in the West Bank</li><li><strong>Application Deadline</strong>: March 13, 2015</li><li><strong>Cost:</strong>$3,325 for small or medium-sized enterprise or trade association/organization with fewer than 500 employees, $4,625 for large firms, $1,000 for each additional firm representative</li><li>West Bank optional meetings is in addition to the mission participation fee above, at $750 per SME and $2,300 per large firm</li></ul><p>For more information, visit:<a href="http://export.gov/industry/health/eg_main_076608.asp">http://export.gov/industry/health/eg_main_076608.asp</a>.</p><p><br></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a name="P85_6567"></a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Local Events - New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about events presented by the New Jersey U.S. Export Assistance Centers.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, New Jersey, events</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/550.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/550.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/550.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
