<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>566</id>
    <title>Market Research</title>
    <short_title>Market Research</short_title>
    <summary>Get access to market research articles that can be used to help exporters plan their foreign trade efforts.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/5/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/5/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>Plan your market entry the right way – use market research to learn your product's potential in a given market, the best prospects for success, and the market's business practices before you first export.</p><p>Visit the <a href="https://new.export.gov/market-researches">market research library</a> and access more than 100,000 industry and country-specific market reports from trade specialists working in overseas posts.</p><h1>Browse Articles</h1><h2><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/market-research/posts/123-introduction-to-trade-data-and-analysis">Introduction to Trade Data and Analysis</a> </h2><p>Trade data can help companies identify the best countries to target their exporting efforts. Companies can gauge the size of the market for their product as well as develop a price strategy to become competitive. The official U.S. import and... </p><h2><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/market-research/posts/122-trade-data-from-federal-agencies-and-ngos">Trade Data from Federal Agencies and NGOs</a> </h2><p>U.S. Agricultural Trade Statistics Trade statistics and evaluation toolsfrom the Foreign Agricultural Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation APEC member countries have tariff schedules and other vital information for the exporter. Bureau of Economic Analysis BEA provides foreign... </p><h2><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/market-research/posts/121-trade-analysis">Trade Analysis</a> </h2><p>Which markets represent the best opportunities for your exports ... or the worst? Researching potential markets begins with understanding trade patterns in the international marketplace. Imports &amp; Exports by Country and Commodity - U.N. Statistics Analysis By Industry Sector Healthcare... </p><h2><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/market-research/posts/120-u-s-economic-data">U.S. Economic Data</a> </h2><p>The following links provide information on the U.S. Economy, such as employment, industry trends and exporting statistics. General Reports State Export-Related Jobs SME Exporting Companies: Statistical Overview Aerospace Domestic Aerospace Industry Statistics Aerospace Reports Automotive Domestic Automotive Industry Trends Automotive... </p><h2><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/market-research/posts/119-u-s-state-export-data">U.S. State Export Data</a> </h2><p>The links below provide export data by U.S. State. General Exports, Jobs, and Foreign Investment State Export-Related Jobs Country or Region Specific State Exports to Countries and Regions Bahrain: State Export Perspective Morocco: State Export Perspective Free Trade Areas CAFTA-DR...</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Market Intelligence<sub_topic>Market Research</sub_topic><sub_topic>Trade Data and Analysis</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Market Research</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Get access to market research articles that can be used to help exporters plan their foreign trade efforts.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Market Research, Economic Data, Trade Data, </seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/566.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/566.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/566.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
