<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>593</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - Portland USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about internship opportunities available at the Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/5/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/5/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Portland_internships.jpg" alt="Photo of two interns at the Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p><strong>Intern Coordinator: Allan Christian</strong><br><strong>Phone: (503) 326-3001</strong><br><strong>Email:</strong><a href="http://export.gov/oregon/allan.christian%40trade.gov">allan.christian@trade.gov</a></p><p>The Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center (USEAC) is a joint effort bringing together the export business development programs of the U.S. Commercial Service (an agency of the U.S. Department of Commerce) and the export finance programs of the U.S. Small Business Administration. The Portland USEAC has a limited number of volunteer internships to students considering careers in international business. Only U.S. citizens are eligible for consideration and applicants should have a 3.0 GPA or better.</p><p>We provide firms with direct sales leads, help them establish contacts with prospective overseas business partners, and offer promotional vehicles to introduce their products and services worldwide. As the principal federal government resource for international trade development and assistance, the U.S. Export Assistance Centers offer a unique internship opportunity for those interested in pursuing a career in international business.</p><p>The purpose of the internship is three-fold:</p><ol><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">to provide a problem solving perspective within a &quot;real World&quot; professional business assistance environment;</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">to provide the student with the ability to creatively link their academic studies and skills with the export business development assistance we provide to our client companies; and</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">to provide the student with in-depth knowledge of the organizations, programs and resource base for international trade development.</span><br></li></ol><p>Throughout the internship, the student will be assigned a host of duties and activities that include:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Helping clients assess and address challenges in export business development</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Providing market research and customized information to clients</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Communicating directly with clients and our international offices in day-to-day client assistance</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Working collaboratively with our business development partner organizations to assist clients</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Working together with Portland USEAC staff in the development, promotion, and execution of international trade seminars, webinars, and conferences</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Outreaching to clients for seminars, webinars, and other international trade development events</span><br></li></ul><p>Finally, interns also have the opportunity to work on major projects. Such projects may include research reports on selected topics, (i.e. country market/economic studies, industry studies, and &quot;How to&quot; guides pertaining to the export of specific products), as well as trade event projects such as the planning and recruitment for trade missions, trade shows and international business seminars.</p><p>For further information on internships with the Portland USEAC, please contact Allan Christian at 503.326.3001 or send an e-mail to<a href="http://export.gov/oregon/allan.christian%40trade.gov">allan.christian@trade.gov</a>.​</p><p>The following document provides additional information about our internship program and application process:<a href="http://export.gov/oregon/static/interninfo_Latest_interninfo029850.pdf">Intern Position Information</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about internship opportunities available at the Portland U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Portland, Oregon, internships</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/593.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Portland_internships.jpg" name="Portland_internships"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/593.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/593.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
