<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>609</id>
    <title>Export Awards</title>
    <short_title>Export Awards</short_title>
    <summary>Export Awards afford suitable recognition to persons, firms, or organizations which contribute significantly in the effort to increase United States exports as well as continuing recognition of noteworthy export promotion efforts.
</summary>
    <creation_date>10/8/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/7/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>The President's &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Awards</strong></h1><p>The President's &quot;E&quot; Award was created by Executive Order of the President to afford suitable recognition to persons, firms, or organizations which contribute significantly in the effort to increase United States exports. </p><p>The President's &quot;E Star&quot; Award, which was authorized by the Secretary of Commerce, affords continuing recognition of noteworthy export promotion efforts.</p><p>Winners of the &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Award are authorized to fly the blue and white banner, to display the accompanying certificate of commendation which is signed by the Secretary of Commerce in the name and by the authority of the President, to wear and issue to employees an &quot;E&quot; or &quot;E Star&quot; lapel pin, and to refer to the award in their advertising. </p><h2>History of the &quot;E&quot; Awards </h2><p>During World War II, more than 4,000 &quot;E&quot; Pennants were presented to war plants in recognition of production excellence. The famous flag with the big &quot;E&quot; emblazoned on it became a badge of patriotism in action. </p><p>President Kennedy revived the World War II &quot;E&quot; symbol of excellence to honor and provide recognition to America's exporters. Thus, the &quot;E&quot; Award Program was established by Executive Order 10978 on December 5, 1961. The &quot;E Star&quot; was authorized in l969 to recognize &quot;E&quot; Award winners for continued efforts in export expansion. </p><h2>How to Apply</h2><p>Applications for the 2014 President's E-Awards will be accepted between November 3, 2014 and January 16, 2015. There are two types of &quot;E&quot; Awards. The President's &quot;E&quot; Award for Exports is awarded to a firm or organization that has made significant contributions to the increase of American exports. The President's &quot;E&quot; Award for Export Service is awarded to organizations that may or may not export directly, but which assist or facilitate export activities.</p><p>The primary criterion for the President's &quot;E&quot; Award for Exports is four years of successive export growth, usually accompanied by a rising percentage of export sales within total sales. The application should demonstrate export expansion that is measurable, innovative, sustainable, and has broad impact. </p><p>The primary criterion for the President's &quot;E&quot; Award for Export Service is four years of contributions to export expansion. Applicants must detail results of their work to support the export growth of others. The application should demonstrate export expansion that is measurable, innovative, sustainable, and has broad impact. </p><p>Previous recipients of the President's &quot;E&quot; Award may apply for the President's &quot;E Star&quot; Award for continued superior performance in increasing or promoting exports. &quot;E Star&quot; Award applicants should show four years of successive export growth since winning the &quot;E&quot; Award. Previous &quot;E Star&quot; Award recipients may apply for additional &quot;E Star&quot; Awards once they have four additional years of contributions to export expansion.</p><p>Applications must be reviewed by the local <a href="http://export.gov/usoffices/index.asp"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">U.S. Export Assistance Center</span></a> and approved for submission by the U.S. and Foreign Commercial Service Network Director. Applications should be submitted electronically.</p><h2>Application Workshop:</h2><p>We will host four conference calls for potential applicants or trade specialists to review the application process and answer questions. Registration for the calls is required. The calls have been scheduled as follows:</p><p>&quot;E&quot; Award or &quot;E Star&quot; Award for Exports - Wednesday, October 22, 2014 @2:00 p.m. EDT or Thursday December 4, 2014 at 2:00 p.m. EST</p><p>&quot;E&quot; Award or &quot;E Star&quot; Award for Export Service - Wednesday, October 22, 2014 @3:30 p.m. EDT or Thursday December 4, 2014 at 3:30 p.m. EST</p><p>To register for the webinar, please email <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Eawards@trade.gov"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Eawards@trade.gov</span></a> </p><p>Questions about the E Awards program can be emailed to <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Eawards@trade.gov"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Eawards@trade.gov</span></a> </p><h1>Past &quot;E&quot; Awards</h1><ul><li><a href="http://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2012/05/17/presidential-honors-awarded-record-number-us-exporters-commerce-secre">2012 &quot;E&quot;Awards</a></li><li><a href="http://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2011/05/16/commerce-secretary-gary-locke-honors-us-companies-highest-award-expor">2011 &quot;E&quot; Awards</a></li><li><a href="http://trade.gov/cs/eaward2010.asp">2010 &quot;E&quot;Awards</a></li><li><a href="http://www.commerce.gov/NewsRoom/PressReleases_FactSheets/PROD01_008598">2009 &quot;E&quot; Awards</a></li><li><a href="http://export.gov/articles/successstories/eg_main_017214.asp">2008 &quot;E&quot;Awards</a></li></ul><p><img src="/Files/e%20awards.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></p><h1>Related Files</h1><ul><li><a href="http://export.gov/static/E%20Awards%20Manual_ver%208_Final_10282013_Latest_eg_main_042248.pdf">Program manual (PDF)</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Promotion<sub_topic>Sales</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Information &amp; Communication</industry>
        <industry>Services</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>E-Awards</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>E-Awards</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Export Awards afford suitable recognition to persons, firms, or organizations which contribute significantly in the effort to increase United States exports as well as continuing recognition of noteworthy export promotion efforts.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Export Awards, e awards, sales, E Star, growth</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/609.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/e%20awards.jpg" name="e%20awards"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/609.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/609.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
