<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>616</id>
    <title>U.S. Commercial Service Programs at the World Bank</title>
    <short_title>Programs at the World Bank</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the program offerings at the World Bank offered through the U.S. Commercial Service including business counseling, procurement training, and more.</summary>
    <creation_date>6/12/2011</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/8/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>1</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>U.S. Commercial Service Programs at the World Bank</strong></h1><h2><strong>Business Counseling </strong></h2><ul><li>Provide counsel on the operations of the Bank and how best to approach the Bank and borrowing governments; </li><li>Liaison with project managers at the Bank with respect to specific projects; and </li><li>Advise how best to incorporate Bank-procurement opportunities intocompany strategic planning. </li></ul><h2><strong>Procurement Trainingand Seminars </strong></h2><ul><li>Provide training for associations and their members; </li><li>Providecompany-specific training for business development managers and capture teams; </li><li>Develop company specific strategies for pursuing multilateral development bank business; </li><li>Provide speakers and content forinternational tradepromotion seminarsand events. </li></ul><p>To schedule a training seminar for your company or trade association, contact <a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:David.Fulton@trade.gov">David.Fulton@trade.gov</a>. </p><h2><strong>Identification of Business Opportunities at the World Bank </strong></h2><ul><li>Identify upcoming projects that represent significant commercial opportunities; </li><li>Supply information about specific procurement notices as they become available; and </li><li>Disseminate information on contracts, such as policy studies (e.g., gender, environment), internal governance reviews, and/or goods/services directly procured by the Bank. </li></ul><h2><strong>Facilitate Key Introductions </strong></h2><ul><li>Identify key contacts at the Bank and in the borrowing government regarding a specific project; </li><li>Arrange meetings with key individuals, including World Bank project task managers, industry experts, procurement officers, investment officers, and others as appropriate. </li></ul><h2><strong>Advocate on Behalf ofU.S. Businesses </strong></h2><ul><li>Advocate on behalf of U.S. companies to ensure a &quot;levelplaying field&quot; on Bank-funded procurements.</li></ul><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Export Training</topic>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>U.S. Commercial Service Programs at the World Bank</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the program offerings at the World Bank offered through the U.S. Commercial Service including business counseling, procurement training, and more.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Procurement, Training, Business Opportunities, Advocacy, Connections</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/616.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/616.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/616.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
