<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>633</id>
    <title>Local Events - Long Island U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Local Events - Long Island USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about events presented by the Long Island U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/13/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/12/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="color:#f09609;font-family:'segoe ui semilight', 'segoe ui', segoe, tahoma, helvetica, arial, sans-serif;font-size:1.46em;line-height:1.4;">Upcoming Local Events</span></p><p>Check back with us as some upcoming events will be listed.</p><h2>Past Local Events</h2><h3>Virtual Wine Tasting Event to Promote the Rural Export Initiative</h3><p><strong>Date:</strong>Thursday August 28, 2014 – 7:00PM – 10:00PM<br><strong>Location:</strong>Long Island Forum for Technology, Bethpage, NY</p><p>On August 28, 2014, a virtual wine tasting event to highlight New York State wines from the Finger Lake and Long Island regions was co-hosted by the Long Island, Buffalo, and Rochester USEAC's in partnership with several local partners, including the Finger Lakes Community College, the Long Island Forum for Technology (LIFT) and HSBC. As part of the Rural Export Initiative (REI), this event virtually connected through DVC technology 5 New York wineries, 3 from the Finger Lakes including Dr. Frank Konstantin, Swedish Hill, and LaMoreaux Landing, and 2 from Long Island, Palmer Vineyards, and Paumonok Vineyards, with Japanese importers, restaurateurs, buyers and media who were assembled at the US Embassy in in Tokyo, Japan. Prior the tasting, the wine to be tasted was shipped to the Embassy in Japan. Working together with the New York Wine and Grape Foundation, and the USDA's Foreign Agricultural Service to develop this program, it provided an opportunity to not only promote the general exposure of New York wines to buyers in Japan and educate them on the quality of New York wines available, but to also increase potential export sales. Each winery selected a red and a white wine to present, and all were well received by the Japanese attendees. Long Island Business News, a major LI publication, covered the event.</p><p>Excerpt from Long Island Business News:<br><em>&quot;The USEAC's first-ever virtual wine-tasting event was developed as part of a rural export initiative established earlier this year by President Barack Obama. The initiative offers federal resources to rural businesses looking to increase overseas investment opportunities, according to Susan Sadocha, senior international trade specialist for the USEAC.</em></p><p><em>During the Aug. 28 event, wine importers and representatives from upscale Japanese supermarkets and restaurants sampled some of Long Island's select vintages. Kareem Massoud, a second-generation winemaker at family-owned Paumanok Vineyards, cited a golden opportunity to get his products in front of key Japanese buyers.</em></p><p><em>&quot;It certainly beats flying over there with a case of wine,&quot; Massoud said.&quot;</em></p><h3>HIA-LI 26th Annual Business Trade Show &amp; Conference</h3><p><strong>Date:</strong>Thursday May 22, 2014 – 9:00AM – 4:00PM<br><strong>Location:</strong>Suffolk County Community College Sports &amp; Exhibition Complex, Brentwood Campus</p><h4>Interested in exporting your product or services overseas?</h4><p>Please stop by the US Department of Commerce, LIExport Assistance Center's exhibit booth. LI USEAC staff will be there to answer questions about our services and how we can help your business enter the international marketplace!</p><h4>Business Trade Show &amp; Conference Programming:</h4><p>8 am - 10 am - Executive Breakfast (Auxiliary Gym - fee)<br>9 am – Business Trade Show Floor Opens; Complimentary Seminars Begin<br>10:15 am – 11:15 am – Complimentary Business Seminars<br>11:30 am – 1:30 pm – Executive Luncheon (Auxiliary Gym - fee)<br>1:45 pm – 2:45 pm – Complimentary Business Seminars<br>4 pm – Show Ends</p><h3>Talking Trade: Entrepreneurship in Africa</h3><p><strong>Date:</strong>Tuesday May 13, 2014 - 10:00AM to 12PM (Noon)<br><strong>Location:</strong>Hofstra University, Axinn Library, 2nd floor, Room 246<br><strong>Cost:</strong>Free, but you must register<br><strong>Register:</strong><a href="http://www.hofstra.edu/zarbrsvp">http://www.hofstra.edu/zarbrsvp​</a>(Must RSVP by May 9th)</p><p>Have you ever thought of launching a new business for trading with Africa? Do you wonder how it is done? What are the key traits for entrepreneurship in Africa? Join live speakers from South Africa who do business across the continent. Come hear from the experts: Dr. Richard Hayes, Professor Frank Z. Zarb, Hofstra School of Business and Michael Sudarkasa CEO Africa Business Group share their insight on entrepreneurship and doing business in Africa. Learn branding, marketing and communications tools for success from our own New York City Entrepreneur Adiat Disu, Founder &amp; CEO Adiree PR &amp; Communications and Director of Africa Fashion Week(s) NYC. Take homeUS Commercial Service Global Markets resources.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Local Events - Long Island U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about events presented by the Long Island U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Long Island, New York, events</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/633.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/633.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/633.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
