<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>644</id>
    <title>Local Events - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Events - Philadelphia USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about events presented by the Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/14/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/13/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Philly_events.jpg" alt="Image of hands shaking in front of skyscrapers" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:100%;"><h2>Export Controls Under The International TariffInArmsRegulation(ITAR)</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October9, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>NewCumberlandPA</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>Join the World Trade Center (WTC) Harrisburg to learn how to comply with U.S. export control requirements for munitions items / defense articles as set forth by the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR). The course will also address the new export control reform initiatives.</p><p>Topics Include:</p></blockquote><ul><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Export Control Reform initiative</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Definition of export under ITAR</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Foreign national persons</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Registration with DDTC</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Empowered Officials</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Commodity Jurisdiction Requests</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Defense articles</span></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Case Examples.... AND MORE!</span></li></ul></ul><p><em><a href="http://wtccentralpa.org/itar/">For more details and to register, please click here.</a></em></p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>GoingGlobal Series: Doing BusinessIn Latin America</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October 10, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>Temple University SBDC Announces:</p><p>We hope you will join us for the The Going Global Series: Doing Business in Latin America that will be held on Friday, October 11, 2014 from 8:30 am - 12:30 pm.</p><p>This is a<em>FREE</em>event, but RSVP is required. To RSVP, please contact 215-204-7282 or<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:sbtrain@temple.edu">sbtrain@temple.edu</a></p><p>For more information, please see the<a href="http://informationportalprodfile:///PhiladelphiPA03/Office$/Interns/Derek%20Sexton/GoingGlobal%20Sept%2030.jpg">event flyer here</a>.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>China Town Hall: Local Connections, National Reflections</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October16, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Newark, DE</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>China's rapid development and Sino-American relations have a direct impact on the lives of just about everyone in the United States. CHINA Town Hall: Local Connections, National Reflections, is a national day of programming designed to provide Americans across the United States and beyond the opportunity to discuss these issues with leading experts.</p><p>The National Committee is pleased to present this program, which will feature a live webcast with Jimmy Carter, 39th president of the United States, as part of the Conversations at The Carter Center speaker series, preceded by a local keynote presentation by Dr. Christian Murck of JP Morgan Chase (China) Co. Ltd. The event is co-sponsored by the Confucius Institute and the Institute for Global Studies at the University of Delaware.</p><p>This program is free of charge and open to the public, however space is limited and RSVP is required. Please visit the<a href="http://www.wtcde.com/events/CHINA-Town-Hall-Local-Connections%2c-National-Reflections-58/details">event page</a>for more information.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>Al Día Conversation SeriesWith Walter Bastian</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October17, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>The next installment of Al Día Newsmedia's Conversation series continues with a public interview with the Department of Commerce's Walter Bastian, Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Western Hemisphere. The discussion, entitled &quot;Latin America &amp; The US: Building America By Strengthening the Americas is open to the public and will take place at the Union League of Philadelphia.</p><p>Please review the<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/static/al%20dia_Latest_eg_us_pa_079061.jpg">event flier</a>for more information.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>Exportech: Fast Track to Developing StrategiesFor Intl Sales</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October22, December3, 2014 AND January22, 2015</strong></p><p><strong>Newark, DE</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>This 3 day program helps companies develop and execute their own international growth plan. The program brings together executive leadership from six companies to work in a group project format. It is not a seminar or class it is three 8 hour sessions plus coached time between sessions. Some of the work is done in a group setting while other work is done one-on-one with an international growth coach. Within three months, each company develops a vetted, actionable export growth plan, and gains access to a wide range of expert resources that help overcome barriers to export sales and manufacturing growth.</p><p>For more information, please visit the<a href="http://www.demep.org/events/">DEMEP website</a>.</p><p>To register, please fax<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/static/demep-event-registration-form_Latest_eg_us_pa_078689.pdf">this Seminar Registration form</a>to (302) 282-3137.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>Expand Your Business Horizons in Canada</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October 22, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Breinigsville, PA</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>Presented in collaboration with the Consulate General of Canada in New York, please join the Greater Leigh Valley Chamber of Commerce International Business Council for this breakfast seminar. Featuring keynote speaker Heidi Kutz, Deputy Consul General of Canada, this seminar will provide attendees with an update on U.S. – Canada trade 20 years after enactment of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</p><p>For more information, please see the<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/static/Canada%20Event%20Flyer_Latest_eg_us_pa_078929.pdf">event flyer</a>and<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/philadelphia/upcominglocalevents/lehighvalleychamber.org">register here</a>!</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>Discover Global Markets: The Americas</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October 29-31, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Charlotte, NC</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>Join the U.S. Commercial Service and the North Carolina District Export Council for<em>DISCOVER GLOBAL MARKETS</em>: The Americas, a unique business conference that will help you to transform market potential to market success. This is the premier conference for U.S. executives who want to explore new export market development strategies, innovative tools to promote competiveness and success, and the dynamic markets of North, Central, and South America.</p><p>For more information, please click<a href="http://export.gov/northcarolina/discovertheamericas/">here</a>.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>International Finance Series</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October 30, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>York, PA</strong></p><blockquote style="margin:0px 0px 0px 40px;border:none;padding:0px;"><p>In today's economic climate with rapidly growing new markets, assistance is needed to maximize tax benefits related to export transactions, designing global tax structures to minimize U.S. and foreign taxes, and developing repatriation strategies centered on the use of foreign tax credits. If your company is selling products in the foreign marketplace, there may be opportunities that can be utilized to minimize your company's global effective tax rate. You can also receive CPR credits for this series!</p><p>For more information please click<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/static/International%20Finance%20Series_Latest_eg_us_pa_076527.pdf">here</a>.</p></blockquote></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>InterestCharDomesticInternational Sales Corporation​(IC-DISC) Seminar</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>October 30, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Livingston, NJ</strong></p><p><em>For decades IC-DISC has been saving companies money – why aren't you using it?</em> Join the U.S. Commercial Service (CS) in collaboration with Sobel &amp; Co. LLC., on Thursday, October 30, 2014 for an IC-DISC seminar focused on educating U.S. exporters on how to navigate U.S. laws to save on their tax liability for exports. Sobel &amp; Co. LLC is an experienced tax accounting firm with years of experience in helping U.S. businesses take advantage of this little known program. At the seminar you will hear from accounting experts and current clients on the benefits of the IC-Disc program used to help grow their bottom line.</p><p><strong>Who should attend:</strong>Presidents, CEOs, Vice Presidents, CFOs, Accountants, Export Managers, and Compliance Managers.</p><p>Please see the<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/static/IC-Disc%20Seminar%20Flyer_Latest_eg_us_pa_078850.pdf">event flyer</a>and<strong></strong><a href="http://go.usa.gov/p88F">register</a><a href="http://go.usa.gov/p88F">here</a>!</p><p>To learn more about the event, please go to visit<a href="http://www.export.gov/newjersey/tradeevents/localevents/index.asp">CS New Jersey's event page</a>or contact Brian Beams at<a href="mailto:Brian.Beams@trade.gov">Brian.Beams@trade.gov</a>.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>Essentials of ExportControls and Technology&amp; Encryption Controls Seminars</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>November18-19, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Pittsburgh, PA</strong></p><p style="text-align:justify;">Hosted by the Western Pennsylvania District Export Council, the Bureau of Industry and Security, and the Pittsburgh Office of the U.S. Commercial Service (CS): From consumer goods and industrial equipment to high-tech communication systems, export regulations and controls impact all products and all U.S. exporters. Understanding the Export Administration Regulations and how to comply with regulations is essential as a U.S. exporter.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Join professional speakers from the Bureau of Industry and Security who will lead two days of in-depth training on the fundamentals of export controls as well as detailed instruction on specific export regulations and controls related to software, technology, and encryption.</p><p>For more information and registration, please visit the<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/pittsburghexportcontrols/index.asp?contactid=fdecc840-6e18-4869-abde-03cccaebe8be&amp;campaignid=5cf2d8e9-26fc-4b62-8b39-b88c7ade1620">CS Pittsburgh website​</a>.<br>For questions, please contact Steven Murray at 412-644-2800 or<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/philadelphia/upcominglocalevents/steven.murray%40trade.gov">steven.murray@trade.gov</a></p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>17thAnnual Friend Of Chile Awards Luncheon</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>November 19, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong></p><p style="text-align:justify;">Join the Chilean &amp; American Chamber of Commerce of Greater Philadelphia and other business leaders in honoring our award recipients and recognizing their contribution to the flourishing economic relationship between Chile and the Delaware Valley. To learn about sponsorship opportunities, please contact Ricardo Maldonado at 215-790-3769 or<a href="mailto:ricardo@greaterphilachamber.com">ricardo@greaterphilachamber.com</a>. Your participation helps make the awards ceremony a resounding success and your financial support fuels the Chamber's on-going efforts on behalf of your business.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Please see the<a href="http://www.greaterphilachamber.com/emailer/cacc/140807-cacc-friend-of-chile-save-the-date.html">save the date email​</a>for more information.</p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><h2>18thAnnualHolidayLuncheon and Reception</h2><p style="text-align:right;"><strong>December 5, 2014</strong></p><p><strong>York, PA</strong></p><p style="text-align:justify;">Save the date for the World Trade Center (WTC) Harrisburg's annual Holiday Luncheon and Reception.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Local Events - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about events presented by the Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, events</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/644.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Philly_events.jpg" name="Philly_events"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/644.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/644.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
