<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>646</id>
    <title>MidAtlantic District Export Council</title>
    <short_title>MidAtlantic DEC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the MidAtlantic District Export Council.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/14/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/13/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Representing Pennsylvania, Delaware, and New Jersey, the MidAtlantic District Export Council (DEC) is an organizationwhose members are drawn from U.S. industryand whose knowledge of international business provides a unique source of professional advice to help American firms compete and win business in the global marketplace.</p><p>The MidAtlantic DEC works closely with the U.S. Commercial Service offices in Philadelphia and South Central New Jersey, volunteering their time, energy, and expertise to increase awareness of export opportunities and export resources available to small and medium sized businesses.</p><p>Appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, MidAtlantic DEC members act as consultants to SMEs who seek to export their products and services into markets abroad. For over 30 years, the MidAtlantic DEC's impact has been the expansion of local companies to either enter new overseas markets or export for the first time, thus promoting the nation's economic growth and creating new and higher-paying jobs for the business community. The 58 DECs nationwide combine the energies of nearly 1,500 exporters and export service providers who support the U.S. Government's export promotion efforts throughout the country.​</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>MidAtlantic District Export Council</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the MidAtlantic District Export Council.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>MidAtlantic, export, council, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Delaware</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/646.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/646.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/646.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
