<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>649</id>
    <title>Partners - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Partners - Philadelphia USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the partners of the Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/14/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="height:2644px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:100%;"><h2 style="text-align:center;">Our Export Promotion Partners</h2><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="text-align:center;"><tbody><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:100%;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/World_Trade_Center_Delaware.jpg" alt="Logo for World Trade Center Delaware" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><a href="http://www.wtcde.com/">World Trade Center Delaware</a></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">The World Trade Center Delaware is a private-sector, non-profit organization helping companies succeed in the international marketplace. With a primary focus on export promotion, WTC Delaware develops programs to assist businesses and organizations including educational and networking events, market research, and consulting.</td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/PA_SBDC.jpg" alt="Logo for Pennsylvania Small Business Development Centers" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><a href="http://www.pasbdc.org/">Pennsylvania Small Business Development Centers</a></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default">The Pennsylvania Small Business Development Centers (SBDC) supports the economic development of Pennsylvania by providing entrepreneurs and small businesses with individual consultation, comprehensive education and information necessary to help their businesses start, grow, and prosper.</td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Fox_School_of_Business.jpg" alt="Logo for Temple Fox School of Business Center for International Business Education and Research (CIBER)" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><a href="http://www.fox.temple.edu/cms_research/institutes-and-centers/center-for-international-business-education-and-research/welcome/home/">Temple Center for International Business Education and Research (CIBER)</a>The Centers for International Business Education and Research (CIBERs) were created under the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 to increase and promote the nation's capacity for international understanding and economic enterprise. Thirty-one universities were designated as centers that serve as regional and national resources to business, students, and academics. Together, the CIBERs form a powerful network.</td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><h2>Other Trade Resources</h2></td></tr><tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"><td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/City%20of%20Philadelphia.jpg" alt="Logo for City of Philadelphia" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr></tbody></table></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>City of Philadelphia, International Trade Division</strong><a href="http://www.phila.gov/commerce/comm/lvl_2/mbat_trade_diplomacy.htm">http://www.phila.gov/commerce</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The International Division of the City of Philadelphia Department of Commerce is committed to facilitating opportunities for local businesses in the international marketplace. In the process, our staff aims to create jobs and improve the quality of life, both domestically and abroad. Through the process of promoting trade, the City works with many regional partners to stimulate economic development in the region and promote direct investment and international trade. We encourage you to take advantage of our services to help expand your business globally. If your business grows, it is a success story for the region and further enhances our already vibrant economy.Phone #: (215) 683-2040</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/National_DEC.jpg" alt="Logo for National District Export Council" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Mid Atlantic District Export Council</strong><a href="http://midatlanticdec.com/">http://midatlanticdec.com/</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p style="text-align:center;">The Mid-Atlantic DEC is a private, nonprofit corporation committed to growing the Mid-Atlantic Region's exports. The DEC supports the U.S. Commercial Service by providing regional business leadership and international expertise. The DEC works closely with the Trenton, Harrisburg, and Philadelphia USEACs to assist American firms to win business in the international marketplace. The DEC serves as a link between the local business community (Pennsylvania, South Jersey, and Delaware) and the USEAC. The MidAtlantic DEC provides regional business leadership and international expertise to support the U.S. Commercial Service by offering advice on private sector export matters, promoting and sponsoring export-related seminars, counseling businesses on trade-related topics, and lobbying the U.S. Congress and other legislative bodies in support of export initiatives.</p></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Philadelphia_Regional_Port_Authority.jpg" alt="Logo for Philadelphia Regional Port Authority" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Philadelphia Regional Port Authority</strong><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/philadelphia/philadelphiaarearesources/www.philaport.com">www.philaport.com</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p style="text-align:center;">The Philadelphia Regional Port Authority, an independent agency of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, has as its primary mission the enhancement of water-borne trade and commerce. The Delaware River Port Complex is the 4th largest in the USA, with 104 million tons of cargo transiting the River last year. PRPA facilities are #1 on the Delaware River, with service from the top 3 container lines in the world. A portfolio of export services is available to companies in the Mid-Atlantic region.</p><p style="text-align:center;">Phone #: (215) 426-2600</p></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/World_Trade_Association_Philadelphia.jpg" alt="Logo for World Trade Association of Philadelphia" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>World Trade Association of Philadelphia</strong><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/philadelphia/philadelphiaarearesources/www.wtaphila.com">www.wtaphila.com</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">Established in 1931, the World Trade Association of Philadelphia is an organization that aims to promote and foster international trade through events and seminars. The association currently has over 100 members, representing every segment of the Maritime Industry.Phone #: (856) 642-3957</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Chester_Co_EDC.jpg" alt="Logo for Chester County Economic Development Council" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Chester County Economic Development Council</strong><a href="http://www.cceconomicdevelopment.com/">http://www.cceconomicdevelopment.com/</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">Chester County Economic Development Council (CCEDC) is a private, non-profit economic development organization that has been nurturing economic growth in Chester County and the surrounding region for more than 40 years. The Council's portfolio of business growth services includes: low-interest financing, small business lending, workforce training, retention and expansion, customized international business assistance, land and building site selection, brownfields consultation and remediation, urban redevelopment, and agricultural economic development.Phone #: (610) 458-5700</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Greater_Philadelphia_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" alt="Logo for Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce</strong><a href="http://www.gpcc.com/">http://www.gpcc.com</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">As an advocate for businesses throughout the region, the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce is dedicated to supporting and encouraging the continued growth of each of its nearly 6,000 member companies, and the business community at large. Its main objectives are to influence business-friendly legislation in government, participate in initiatives to improve education and the community, present professional enrichment programs, and to provide members with cost-efficient ways to run their businesses.Phone #: (215) 545-1234</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/World_Trade_Center_Greater_Philadelphia.jpg" alt="Logo for World Trade Center of Greater Philadelphia" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>The World Trade Center of Greater Philadelphia</strong><a href="http://www.wtcphila.org/">http://www.wtcphila.org</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">Economic globalization is a reality. So if you want to prosper locally you will also have to compete outside of the United States, where 95% of the world's population is located. The World Trade Center of Greater Philadelphia -- with a direct link to over 750,000 international companies through approximately 300 World Trade Centers in close to 100 countries - can help. Whether you are an established corporation already trading globally, or a small business interested in international trade, we have the resources you'll need to compete internationally.Phone #: (215) 586-4240</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/BC_Intnatl_Trade_Council.jpg" alt="Logo for Bucks County International Trade Council" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Bucks County International Trade Council</strong><a href="http://www.international-trade.org/">http://www.international-trade.org</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The BCITC is a non-profit organization established in 1994 as a result of a collaborative effort of five (5) Bucks County Chambers of Commerce to provide service and education to businesses of Bucks County in an effort to promote international trade. BCITC is a membership supported organization that provides information and referral services, educational programs and network opportunities in an effort to facilitate, promote and increase international trade.Phone #: (215) 348-0378</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/British_American_Business_Council.jpg" alt="Logo for British American Business Council" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>British American Business Council</strong><a href="http://www.gpcc.com/babc/index.asp">http://www.gpcc.com/babc/index.asp</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">Through the BABC, members have the opportunity to develop valuable business contacts within the British American community and to exchange ideas and information with a cross section of business, trade and governmental interests. British companies have a strong connection to the Greater Philadelphia region and of over 500 international companies in the region, more than a third are British-owned.Located in Center City Philadelphia, the BABC is an affiliate of the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce and is supported by major businesses in the region.Phone #: (215) 790-3686</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Chilean_American_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" alt="Logo for Chilean &amp; American Chamber of Commerce" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Chilean &amp; American Chamber of Commerce</strong><a href="http://caccgp.com/">http://caccgp.com/</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The Chilean and American Chamber of Commerce of Greater Philadelphia (CACCGP) is a non-profit, apolitical membership organization created to foster increased and improved commercial and trade relations between the Republic of Chile and the Greater Philadelphia region. The CACCGP assists entrepreneurs and investors from one nation interested in establishing contacts in the other by providing material valuable to the conduct of importing and exporting activities.Phone #: (215) 790-3690</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/European-American_Busines_Org.jpg" alt="Logo for European-American Business Organization, Inc." style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><p><br><strong>European-American Business Organization, Inc.</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.eabo.biz/">http://www.eabo.biz</a></p></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The European-American Business Organization, Inc. (EABO) is a consulting firm specializing in transatlantic business development and international tax services. It offers a multitude of services such as early stage venture funding, market expansion strategy, international trade show planning, public relations strategies, and legal assistance. The EABO team comprises decades of experience in these fields and speaks the majority of the European Union's principal languages.Phone #: (212) 972-3035</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Philadelphia-Israel_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" alt="Logo for America-Israel American Chamber of Commerce" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>America-Israel American Chamber of Commerce</strong><a href="http://www.americaisraelchamber.com/">http://www.americaisraelchamber.com</a></td></tr><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The America-Israel Chamber of Commerce, Central Atlantic Region, was incorporated as an apolitical, not-for-profit, membership organization in 1987. Serving Pennsylvania, Southern New Jersey, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia and North Carolina, AICC is the only economic development group in the area to promote the interests of the U.S.-Israel business community. AICC stands ready to assist its members in capitalizing on Israel's strong scientific and industrial capabilities. Working closely in partnership with key organizations such as the Israel Economic Mission, the U.S. Department of Commerce, local chambers of commerce, and the Israel Chamber affiliates nationwide, we're able to offer the information needed to do business with Israel.Phone #: (215) 790-3722</td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Greater_Philadelphia_Hispanic_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" alt="Logo for Greater Philadelphia Hispanic Chamber of Commerce" style="margin:5px;" /></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default"><strong>Greater Philadelphia Hispanic Chamber of Commerce</strong><a href="http://www.philahispanicchamber.org/">http://www.philahispanicchamber.org</a></td></tr><tr style="text-align:center;"><td class="ms-rteTable-default">The Greater Philadelphia Hispanic Chamber of Commerce membership primarily consists of Hispanic businesses and individuals who represent all segments of commerce in the Philadelphia Region. Their diversified membership represents a growing list of private and public institutions interested in providing services to our community and the growing Hispanic market. They continue to encourage and facilitate business relationships among the members by providing opportunities to exchange information, ideas as well as business opportunities.Phone #: (215) 790-3723​</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Partners - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the partners of the Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, partners</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/649.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/World_Trade_Center_Delaware.jpg" name="World_Trade_Center_Delaware"/>
      <image src="/Files/PA_SBDC.jpg" name="PA_SBDC"/>
      <image src="/Files/Fox_School_of_Business.jpg" name="Fox_School_of_Business"/>
      <image src="/Files/City%20of%20Philadelphia.jpg" name="City%20of%20Philadelphia"/>
      <image src="/Files/National_DEC.jpg" name="National_DEC"/>
      <image src="/Files/Philadelphia_Regional_Port_Authority.jpg" name="Philadelphia_Regional_Port_Authority"/>
      <image src="/Files/World_Trade_Association_Philadelphia.jpg" name="World_Trade_Association_Philadelphia"/>
      <image src="/Files/Chester_Co_EDC.jpg" name="Chester_Co_EDC"/>
      <image src="/Files/Greater_Philadelphia_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" name="Greater_Philadelphia_Chamber_of_Commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/World_Trade_Center_Greater_Philadelphia.jpg" name="World_Trade_Center_Greater_Philadelphia"/>
      <image src="/Files/BC_Intnatl_Trade_Council.jpg" name="BC_Intnatl_Trade_Council"/>
      <image src="/Files/British_American_Business_Council.jpg" name="British_American_Business_Council"/>
      <image src="/Files/Chilean_American_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" name="Chilean_American_Chamber_of_Commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/European-American_Busines_Org.jpg" name="European-American_Busines_Org"/>
      <image src="/Files/Philadelphia-Israel_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" name="Philadelphia-Israel_Chamber_of_Commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/Greater_Philadelphia_Hispanic_Chamber_of_Commerce.jpg" name="Greater_Philadelphia_Hispanic_Chamber_of_Commerce"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/649.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/649.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
