<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>655</id>
    <title>Recognizing Export Achievement - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Export Awards - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the awards available for excellence in exporting.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/14/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">Nearly 95% of consumers live outside the U.S. accounting for 2/3 of the world's purchasing power. In this current time period, not exporting is like leaving money on the table and there is one federal agency that wants to make sure you explore your full export potential – the U.S. Commercial Service. The U.S. Commercial Service was created in 1980 to focus fully on U.S. export promotion and looks to highlight those companies that are leading the charge in growing their business through finding new export markets or increasing their current export markets. The U.S. Commercial Service is proud to spotlight those companies that are making a difference in U.S. export growth through the below awards. For questions regarding the awards, please contact Lyn Doverspike at 412-644-2800 or</span><a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:lyn.doverspike@trade.gov" style="line-height:1.6;">lyn.doverspike@trade.gov</a>.​</p><h2>Export Achievement Award</h2><p>Created by the Assisting Secretary for Trade Promotion and the Director General of the U.S. Commercial Service in 2001, the Export Achievement Certificate recognizes small and medium-sized companies (less than 500 employees) that have successfully entered the international marketplace with a first time export sale, or that have successfully entered a new export market. Awarded to both private companies and organizations committed to exporting endeavors, the Export Achievement Award highlights how the U.S. Commercial Service and its programs can lead to success for you! To check out recent Export Achievement Awardees,<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_034838.asp">click here</a>.</p><h2>The President of the U.S. &quot;E&quot; Award for Exporting Excellence</h2><p>The President's &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Awards were created in 1961 to recognize those U.S. companies that have had provided and continue to provide significant contributions to U.S. export expansion. It has the distinction of being the highest recognition any U.S. company or organization can receive from the U.S. government. Recipients of the President's &quot;E&quot; Award must demonstrate 4 years of successive growth, usually accompanied by a rising percentage of export sales within total sales while showing export expansion in a measurable, innovative, sustainable broad impact manner. The President's &quot;E Star&quot; Award is only eligible for prior winners of the President's &quot;E&quot; Award and they must demonstrate continued superior performance in increasing or promoting exports. &quot;E Star&quot; applicants need to show 4 years of successive export growth since winning the President's &quot;E&quot; Award. To check out recent President &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Awardees,<a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_034837.asp">click here.</a>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Recognizing Export Achievement - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the awards available for excellence in exporting.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/655.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/655.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/655.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
