<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>673</id>
    <title>Nielsen-Kellerman - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Nielsen-Kellerman</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about Nielsen-Kellerman, a recipient of an Export Achievement Certificate.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/17/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/16/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Nielsen-Kellerman.jpg" alt="Export Achievement Certificate Presentation  to Nielsen-Kellerman Corp. receiving an Export Achievement Certificate" style="margin:5px;" />​</p><h2 style="text-align:center;">Export Achievement Certificate Presentation</h2><h2 style="text-align:center;">to Nielsen-Kellerman Corp.</h2><p>Nielsen-Kellerman designs and manufactures a diverse line of waterproof electronics for use in the rowing industry and also a product line of weather instruments for multiple applications, including military, fire safety, hunting, HVAC, boating, hiking and the sciences. Nielsen-Kellerman has been working with the Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center (USEAC) and local trade partner Temple Small Business Development Center since 1998 to expand their international sales.</p><p>Through this joint assistance, Nielsen-Kellerman has sold products into Southeast Asia, Europe, Central America and the Middle East. The company continues to utilize Commercial Service business counseling and guidance provided by the Philadelphia USEAC to expand their international customer base—utlizing Commercial News USA, USA Pavilions at several European trade shows and updated market research from the U.S. Commercial Service.</p><p>In honor of this achievement, Israel Hernandez, Assistant Secretary for Trade Promotion and Director General of the U.S. Commercial Service, and Congressman Curt Weldon (PA-7) presented the Commerce Department's Export Achievement Certificate to Nielsen-Kellerman, Co. of Boothwyn, PA. The award is presented to U.S. businesses that have benefited from the Department's export assistance to make their first export sale or to expand their international sales into new foreign markets.</p><p>&quot;There has never been a better time to export,&quot; said Hernandez. &quot;The U.S. has cultivated better opportunities for American companies to sell their goods and services around the world, and together with free trade agreements, lowered barriers for American goods and services, Internet, and ease of transportation, American companies like Nielsen-Kellerman are working to increase their bottom line through exporting that support good jobs here at home. I commend Nielsen-Kellerman on their outstanding export accomplishments.&quot;​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Nielsen-Kellerman - Philadelphia U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about Nielsen-Kellerman, a recipient of an Export Achievement Certificate.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, certificate, Nielsen-Kellerman, Philadelphia</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/673.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Nielsen-Kellerman.jpg" name="Nielsen-Kellerman"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/673.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/673.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
