<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>687</id>
    <title>2011 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2011 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about winners of the 2011 Export Achievement Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/19/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em><img alt="Roger Brothers Corporation receiving an Export Achievemnt Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Cardinal_Resources.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></em></strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>Congressman Mike Doyle (PA-14) and Director of U.S. Commercial Service Pittsburgh Lyn Doverspike presenting the Export Achievement Award to President of Cardinal Resources, LLC Kevin Jones</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Cardinal Resources, LLC</strong>was awarded the Export Achievement Award by Congressman Mike Doyle (PA-14) at the Cardinal Resources offices in the South Side neighborhood of Pittsburgh, PA. Cardinal Resources is a world class environmental services and technology firm. From its headquarters in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, the small employee-owned company offers environmental assessments, remediation, and engineering services to the global market. A recent addition to Cardinals Resources environmental solutions has been the Red Bird System, a solar-powered community-sized drinking water system that can bring affordable and sustainable clean water to remote communities. As part of Cardinal Resource's export growth, the company has frequently worked with the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh and a number of international locations. Cardinal Resources has taken advantage of the counseling expertise of the U.S. Commercial Service on topics including export documentation, shipping and logistics, as well export finance. Over the last two years Cardinal Resources with assistance from the U.S. Commercial Service, has successfully developed new markets or increased sales to countries such as Senegal, Ghana, India, China, Brazil, Turkey and Japan. The value of the sales exceeds more than 7 million USD with certainly more sales to follow.</li></ul><p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>​<img alt="Roger Brothers Corporation receiving an Export Achievement Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Roger_Brothers_Corporation.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></em></strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>Congressman Mike Doyle (PA-14), Director of U.S. Commercial Service Pittsburgh Lyn Doverspike, and Director of Saint Francis University's Small Business Development Center Edward Huttenhower presenting the Export Achievement Award to President of Roger Brothers Corporation Mark Kulyk</em></strong></p><ul><li><strong>Rogers Brothers Corporation</strong>is located in rural Albion, Pennsylvania, and has a well-earned reputation for manufacturing superior-quality products. For the past six years, Senior International Trade Specialist Steven Murray of the Pittsburgh office of the U.S. Commerce Service has worked with Mark Kulyk, Rogers Brothers' President. Mr. Kulyk, who now serves as a member of the Western Pennsylvania District Export Council, contacted CS Pittsburgh for assistance on export related issues. Steven Murray responded by highlighting potential markets and opportunities for Rogers® trailers. In the summer of 2009, Mr. Murray was working with the Center of Global Competiveness, which is a part of the Small Business Development Center at St. Francis University, Loretto, Pennsylvania. In September of 2009, the CGC organized a catalog show at EXTEMIN. Rogers Brothers was one of the companies that participated. Two months after the show, Mr. Kulyk received an inquiry for a $250,000 trailer from a contact made through the show. During the next fourteen months the inquiry became an order, a customer representative visited the factory, the trailer was designed and manufactured, and then it was shipped in March, 2011. Along the way, Rogers utilized the counseling services of the U.S. Commercial Service, Pittsburgh and Lima, and the CGC for issues ranging from due diligence, finance, and language. U.S. Congressman Mike Kelly (PA-03) presented Rogers Brothers with the award.</li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2011 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about winners of the 2011 Export Achievement Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/687.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Cardinal_Resources.jpg" name="Cardinal_Resources"/>
      <image src="/Files/Roger_Brothers_Corporation.jpg" name="Roger_Brothers_Corporation"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/687.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/687.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
