<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>688</id>
    <title>2010 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2010 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the 2010 Export Achievement Award winners from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/19/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">​<img alt="International Liner receiving an Export Achievement Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/International_Liner.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></p><ul><li class="List-1" style="border-color:black;text-align:left;line-height:16px;margin-top:0in;margin-bottom:10pt;margin-left:5pt;"><strong>International Liner</strong>was awarded the Export Achievement Award by Senator Robert Casey at their plant located 50 miles south of Pittsburgh in Mt. Braddock, Pennsylvania. International Liner is a world-class producer of protective bed liners for pickup trucks, and is largely credited for introducing bed liners to international markets as a pillar of their export oriented strategy. With so many manufacturing workers in Pennsylvania dependent on exports for their jobs, International Liner demonstrates that exporting is a valuable practice for other small and mid-sized businesses. For more than ten years, International Liner and its president, Mark German, have worked with the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh, Europe, Latin America, and throughout Asia. International Liner has taken advantage of the broad scope of resources offered by the U.S. Commercial Service, including arranging one-on-one business meetings as part of trade missions, providing assistance at trade shows, and providing export counseling.</li></ul><p class="image-1" style="text-align:center;color:#000000;line-height:16px;font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img alt="HERO BX receiving an Export Achievement Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/HERO_BX.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><ul><li class="List-1" style="border-color:black;text-align:left;line-height:16px;margin-top:0in;margin-bottom:10pt;margin-left:5pt;"><strong>HERO BX (formerly Lake Erie Biofuels)</strong>received the Export Achievement Award presented by Congresswoman Kathy Dahlkemper (PA-03) at their office in Erie, Pennsylvania. Established in 2007, HERO BX was Pennsylvania’s first large-scale biodiesel production facility and has grown into one of the leading producers in the United States. In 2008, HERO BX participated in a trade mission to Canada that was sponsored by FirstEnergy and supported by the U.S. Commercial Service. Through the mission, HERO BX was able to meet with potential buyers and get a better understanding of the Canadian market. The mission to Canada was a large success for Hero BX and has resulted in more than a million dollars in sales to the Canadian market. With export counseling from the U.S. Commercial Service, HERO BX is able to expand its imports, strengthening the American economy and creating jobs.</li></ul><p class="image-1" style="text-align:center;color:#000000;line-height:16px;font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img alt="Sauereisen Inc. receiving an Export Achievement Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Sauereisen_Inc.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><ul><li class="List-1" style="border-color:black;text-align:left;line-height:16px;margin-top:0in;margin-bottom:10pt;margin-left:5pt;"><strong>Sauereisen, Inc.</strong>, located in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania,<strong></strong>was awarded the Export Achievement Award by Jason Altmire (PA-04) on February 5, 2010. From its office in Pittsburgh, Sauereisen, Inc. offers a versatile product portfolio encompassing specialty cements, protective coatings, and linings that can be used in steel mills, food processing plants, and in other industrial settings. Sauereisen, Inc. demonstrated a sustained commitment to export expansion, in particular the increase in exports from $2.2 million in 2007 to $4.8 million in 2009 and a corresponding increase in percentage of exports to total sales from 24 to 42 percent. This growth has undoubtedly contributed to the national export expansion efforts that support the American economy and create jobs. As part of Sauereisen Inc.’s export increase, the company worked closely with the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh and various locations internationally. Sauereisen, Inc. Since 2001, Sauereisen, Inc. has taken advantage of counseling offered by the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh, and has successfully developed new markets or increase sales to countries such as China, Mexico, Israel, Kazakhstan, Kuwait, and others.</li></ul><p class="image-1" style="text-align:center;color:#000000;line-height:16px;font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;background-color:#ffffff;">​​<img alt="Aztec Steel Building, Inc. receiving an Export Achievement Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Aztec_Steel_Buildings.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><ul><li class="List-1" style="border-color:black;text-align:left;line-height:16px;margin-top:0in;margin-bottom:0pt;margin-left:5pt;"><strong>Aztec Steel Buildings, Inc.</strong>received the Export Achievement Award from Congressman Mike​(PA-14) on January 25, 2010 at their facilities in McKees Rocks, Pennsylvania. The Export Achievement Award recognizes U.S. companies that have made their first export sale or expanded their sales into overseas market with the assistance from the U.S. Commercial Service. Aztec Steel Buildings is a small company that has, for more than 40 years, manufactured pre-engineered steel buildings for commercial, industrial, agricultural and residential use. For more than a year, Aztec Steel Buildings has worked with the U.S. Commercial Service to explore potential export markets, develop market entry strategies, and to locate potential representatives in overseas markets, one of which is in the Netherlands. For several months the U.S. Commercial Service worked with Aztec Steel Building to develop a better understanding of the market, identify marketing venues, and ultimately to locate a potential representative in the company. By contributing to America’s exports, Aztec Steel Buildings strengthened the American economy and created jobs.</li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2010 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the 2010 Export Achievement Award winners from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/688.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/International_Liner.jpg" name="International_Liner"/>
      <image src="/Files/HERO_BX.jpg" name="HERO_BX"/>
      <image src="/Files/Sauereisen_Inc.jpg" name="Sauereisen_Inc"/>
      <image src="/Files/Aztec_Steel_Buildings.jpg" name="Aztec_Steel_Buildings"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/688.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/688.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
