<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>690</id>
    <title>2005 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2005 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the 2005 winners of the Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/19/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">​​</span><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Intelligent Manufacturing Solutions</strong><strong style="line-height:1.6;"><em></em></strong><strong style="line-height:1.6;">(IMS)</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">is a software company that develops software that allows manufacturers and customers to view the progress, productivity, and performance of the assembly line in real time, while providing 100% traceability, located in Erie, PA. IMS received the Export Achievement Award in August 2005 from Congressman Phil English (PA-03) based on their participation in the U.S. Commercial Service's Gold Key Program and Expo Manufactura 2005 in Mexico, which enabled the company to successfully sign a representative and increase sales to Mexico.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">P.C. McKenzie Company</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">is a small, family owned and operated company that provides its customers with natural gas processing equipment, industrial boilers, and NGV refueling facilities, located in Upper St. Clair, PA. P.C. McKenzie received the Export Achievement Award in November 2005 from Congressman Tim Murphy (PA-18) based on their utilization of the U.S. Commercial Service's International Company Profile Service and counseling, which enabled the company to successfully sign a representative and increase sales to Poland and other Eastern European countries.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Preservation Technologies</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">is a service company located in Cranberry Township, Pennsylvania, that is one of only a few companies worldwide that provides preservation services, which safely neutralize the acids in paper. Preservation Technologies received the Export Achievement Award in October from Congresswoman Hart (PA-04)</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">because of their utilization of the Commercial Service's counseling, which enabled the company to sign a de-acidification contract in Poland.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Systems With Reliability, Inc.(SWR)</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">, a producer of broadcast antennas &amp; transmission systems located in Ebensburg, PA, received the Export Achievement Award in May 2005 from Congressman John Murtha (PA-12). SWR's participation in a U.S. Commercial Service horizontal trade mission resulted in sales to Mexico.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">New Lexington Fire Equipment Company</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">was selected to receive the Export Achievement Award in June of 2005 from Congressman John Murtha (PA-12) in recognition of its successful entry into the Mexican market. Expanding its export portfolio through the international sale of custom fire and rescue vehicles allowed New Lexington Fire Equipment Company to contribute to the regional economy and create jobs.</span><br></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2005 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the 2005 winners of the Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/690.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/690.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/690.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
