<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>691</id>
    <title>2009 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2009 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the 2009 winners of Export Achievement Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/20/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/19/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">​​<img alt=" Congressman Bill Shuster (PA-09) presents an Export Achievement Award to representatives of Vacuum Processes, Inc." src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Vacuum_Processes_Inc.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></p><ul><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Vacuum Processes, Inc</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">. received an Export Achievement Award for exporting to the Mexican market. Congressman Bill Shuster (PA-09) presented the award at Vacuum Processes' facilities in Everett, PA. With fewer than ten employees, Vacuum Processes, Inc. provides custom vacuum and thermal process equipment for various industries. Vacuum Processes uses both state and federal resources to meet its exporting needs. At the state level, this company receives export assistance from the Southern Allegheny Planning and Development Commission (SAP&amp;DC), which is a Regional Export Network Center of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania's Center for Trade Development. In March 2008, Vacuum Processes traveled to Monterrey with the FirstEnergy sponsored Trade Mission to Mexico and Expo Manufactura 2008 and participated in the U.S. Commercial Service's Gold Key Service at the Trade Mission. As a result of this, Vacuum Processes was able to locate a Mexican buyer that now provides steady sales for the company. Vacuum Processes demonstrates that a small company that is committed and resourceful can successfully export.</span><br></li></ul><p style="text-align:center;"><img alt="Representatives of PBM, Inc. receive an Export Achievement Award from Congressman Tim Murphy (PA-18)." src="http://informationportalprod/Files/PBM_Inc.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br>​</p><ul><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">PBM, Inc</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">. was awarded the Export Achievement Award on September 22, 2009. The award was presented by Congressman Tim Murphy (PA-18), at PBM's corporate office in Irwin, PA. PBM is a 109 year-old, third generation family owned small business that manufactures ball valves and specialty valves for sanitary and industrial applications. Last year, PBM was introduced to the US Commercial Service Office in Pittsburgh through the Saint Vincent College Center for Global Competitiveness (CGC). The CGC, a trade partner of the US Commercial Service, is a specialized international marketing program located within the college's Small Business Development Center (SBDC). The CGC was established in 1993 to improve economic vitality and to create sustainable growth by helping businesses compete in the new global economy. With joint export counseling from the US Commercial Service in Pittsburgh and Dhahran, Saudi Arabia, and the CGC at the Saint Vincent College Small Business Development Center (SBDC), PBM was able to successfully sign a sales representative in the Saudi market. PBM's export sales have grown to $4,000,000, part of which is a result from the guidance and assistance provided by the US Commercial Service and the CGC.</span><br></li></ul><p style="text-align:center;"><img alt="Representatives of NABCO, Inc. receive an Export Achievement Award from Congressman Tim Murphy (PA-18)." src="http://informationportalprod/Files/NABCO_Inc.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><ul><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;"><em>NABCO, Inc.</em></strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">has made use of a wide range of U.S. Commercial Service (CS) services to better serve their international market strategy. The Commercial Service Pittsburgh office has advised NABCO on everything from vetting qualified agents to business culture, and company representatives have participated in numerous consultations with Commercial Specialists from CS international offices. Particularly in the markets of Brazil and the United Kingdom, the U.S. Commercial Service facilitated a video conference with the Brazilian Federal Police that lead to the signing of an agent, and advocated on NABCO's behalf to the British Royal Mail to assist NABCO in securing a tender. NABCO was awarded The Export Achievement Award presented by Congressman Tim Murphy (PA-18). The award ceremony was heldatNABCO'scorporate officein Canonsburg, PA on March 9, 2009.The award was accepted by NABCO's Chairman and CEO, Frank Tobin.</span><br></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2009 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the 2009 winners of Export Achievement Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/691.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Vacuum_Processes_Inc.jpg" name="Vacuum_Processes_Inc"/>
      <image src="/Files/PBM_Inc.jpg" name="PBM_Inc"/>
      <image src="/Files/NABCO_Inc.jpg" name="NABCO_Inc"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/691.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/691.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
