<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>695</id>
    <title>2003 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2003 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the winners of the 2003 Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/20/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/19/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">​​​</span><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Integ Process Group, Inc.</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">is based in Wexford, Pennsylvania, and designs web enabled process controls and develops process and systems models utilized in the steel industry. In December of 2003, Integ Process Group, Inc. received the Export Achievement Award from Congresswoman Melissa Hart (PA-04) during the &quot;10 Years of NAFTA: Review and Outlook for the Future&quot; conference. Integ Process Group, Inc. provided jobs for the regional economy through its entry into the international market, which was enabled by export counseling and assistance from the U.S. Commercial Service.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Leech Carbide</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">, started in 1965 in Meadville, Pennsylvania, is a manufacturer of fine grain tungsten carbide used by various industries. In August of 2003, Leech Carbide received the Export Achievement Award from Congressman Phil English (PA-03) for expanding their export portfolio, which already included offices in Mexico, Singapore, and Taiwan, into Brazilian markets. The U.S. Commercial Service, along with the Gannon Small Business Development Center, was able to provide key export assistance and counseling that allowed Leech Carbide to further expand its business, increases the number of workers employed, and contribute job creation in the region.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">SinterFire, Inc.</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">received the Export Achievement Award in April of 2003 from Congressman John Peterson (PA-05) for entering international markets in Germany, the Philippines, and Turkey. Joe Benini, president of SinterFire, founded the company in 1998. A manufacturer of lead-free ammunition components, SinterFire soon began receiving sales requests from overseas. Mr. Benini realized that he needed advice on how to respond and sought assistance from local resources. Through the cooperative efforts of the U.S. Commercial Service office in Pittsburgh, the North Central PA Regional Planning &amp; Development Commission, and Catherine Thornberry, a member of the Western PA District Export Council, Mr. Benini was able to address the growing worldwide demand for his products, identify qualified overseas buyers and agents, and obtain the necessary export license through the U.S. State Department. As a result, SinterFire made its first international sale in 2001 to Germany and has since developed business in a number of other countries.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Penn Power</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">, a First Energy Company, was awarded the Export Achievement Award by Congresswoman Melissa Hart (PA-04)</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">in April of 2003 for assisting their customers in entering new export markets.</span><br></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2003 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the winners of the 2003 Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/695.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/695.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/695.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
