<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>696</id>
    <title>2002 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2002 EAA Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the winners of the 2002 Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/20/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/19/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">​​​​</span><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Synergy Applications</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">, a small manufacturer of coolant filtration products and systems located in Erie, Pennsylvania, was awarded an Export Achievement Award in December 2002 for their excellence in exporting to Canada and Mexico. Through the resources and assistance of the U.S. Commercial Service, Synergy has been able to channel what they noted as &quot;previously unobtainable business&quot; in both countries. Congressman Phil English (PA-3) presented Synergy Applications with the award.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">F.B. Leopold Company</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">, a manufacturer of systems for municipal water treatment located in Zelienople, Pennsylvania, was awarded an Export Achievement Award by Congresswoman Melissa Hart (PA-04) for their excellence in exporting to Thailand, Vietnam, South Korea, and Indonesia. The U.S. Department of Commerce selected F. B. Leopold to receive its Award</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">of Export Achievement based on the company's aggressive but strategic approach to the Vietnamese, Thai, and Indonesian markets. The U.S. Commercial Service office in Pittsburgh and its colleagues in Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, Bangkok, Thailand, and Jakarta, Indonesia identified, qualified, and introduced prospective representatives and distributors to the company in the three countries. In each case, F.B. Leopold selected a business partner to sell F.B. Leopold products and systems.</span><br></li><li><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Gannon University Small Business Development Center (SBDC)</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">was presented with an Export Achievement Award by Congressman Phil English (PA-03) in December of 2002. SBDC of Gannon University was recognized for its highly effective partnership with the U.S. Commercial Service in helping area firms enter overseas markets. Professionals from both organizations work as a team to offer strategic advice, market research, and introductions to prospective foreign partners through the global network of the U.S. Commercial Service.​</span><br></li></ul>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2002 Export Achievement Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the winners of the 2002 Export Achievement Award from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, achievement, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/696.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/696.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/696.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
