<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>704</id>
    <title>E Award and E Star Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>E Award Winners - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about E Award and E Star Award winners from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:4px;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;text-align:center;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><em><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/E_Award.jpg" alt="Image for The President's E Award and E Star Award: Recognizing Excellence in Exporting" style="margin:5px;" />​</em></strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>Congratulations to Carver International, Inc. in Erie, Pennsylvania for receiving The President's &quot;E&quot; Award for Export Excellence in 2013!</em></strong></p><p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Carver_International.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><strong>Carver International, Inc.</strong>, located in Erie, Pennsylvania, is a freight forwarder and export consulting company that received the President's &quot;E&quot; Award for export service companies on May 20, 2013 at a Washington D.C. ceremony. Carver has been committed to finding unique solutions for their customers while also assisting in growing their export sales to new foreign markets. They uniquely and only focus on U.S. export shipments that even as a small company, have provided broad impact on the positive promotion and sales of exports in their region. Carver will remain committed to the long term promotion of increasing U.S. exports and play a vital role in the Erie community.</p><p>Past Award Recipients:</p><ul><li><em style="line-height:1.6;"></em><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_062781.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">2013</a><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;"></em><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_062780.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">2012</a><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;"></em><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_062779.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">2010</a><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;"></em><a href="http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/pittsburgh/recognizingexportachievement/eg_us_pa_062778.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">2004</a><br></li></ul><h2 style="text-align:center;">The President of the United States' &quot;E&quot; Award for Exporting Excellence</h2><p>The President's &quot;E&quot; Award was created by Executive Order of the President on December 5, 1961, to afford suitable recognition to persons, firms, or organizations which contribute significantly in the effort to increase United States exports. The President's &quot;E Star Award&quot;, which was authorized by the Secretary of Commerce on August 4, 1969, affords continuing recognition of noteworthy export promotion efforts.</p><p>The &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Awards are the highest recognition any U.S. entity may receive for supporting export activity. Companies are nominated through their local US&amp;FCS office.</p><p>The primary quantitative criterion for the &quot;E&quot; Award is four years of successive export growth, usually accompanied by a rising percentage of export sales within total sales. An applicant's demonstration of creative or innovative marketing that shows the company's commitment to breaking into foreign markets generally is a significant factor in making award decisions.</p><p>&quot;E Star&quot; Award applicants should show four years of successive export growth since winning the &quot;E&quot; Award and show how marketing activities or services to exporters have increased since receiving the &quot;E&quot; Award. Businesses that continue to demonstrate excellence in exporting may receive additional &quot;E Star&quot; Awards.</p><h2 style="text-align:center;">Background</h2><p>During World War II, more than 4,000 &quot;E Pennants&quot; were presented to war plants in recognition of production excellence. The famous flag with the big &quot;E&quot; emblazoned on it became a badge of patriotism in action.</p><p>President Kennedy revived the World War II &quot;E&quot; symbol of excellence to honor and provide recognition to America's exporters. Thus, the &quot;E&quot; Award Program was established by Executive Order 10978 on December 5, 1961. The &quot;E Star&quot; was authorized in l969 to recognize &quot;E&quot; Award winners for continued efforts in export expansion.</p><p>Winners of the &quot;E&quot; and &quot;E Star&quot; Award are authorized to fly the blue and white banner, to display the accompanying certificate of commendation which is signed by the Secretary of Commerce in the name and by the authority of the President, to wear and issue to employees an &quot;E&quot; lapel pin, and to refer to the award in their advertising.</p><p>For more information on the President's &quot;E&quot; Award, please contact Lyn Doverspike at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:lyn.doverpsike@trade.gov">lyn.doverpsike@trade.gov</a>.</p><p><br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>E Award and E Star Award Winners - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about E Award and E Star Award winners from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/704.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/E_Award.jpg" name="E_Award"/>
      <image src="/Files/Carver_International.jpg" name="Carver_International"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/704.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/704.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
