<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>709</id>
    <title>2010 Presidential "E" Award Recipients - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>2010 E Awards - Pittsburgh USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about recipients of 2010 Presidential "E" and "E Star" Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/21/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​​</p><p></p><p><strong><img alt="Representatives from Sauereisen Inc. receive the 2010 Presidential &quot;E Star&quot; Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Sauereisen_Inc_E_Star.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></strong></p><p><strong></strong><strong></strong><strong>Sauereisen, Inc.</strong>,​​located in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania,<strong></strong>was awarded the Presidential &quot;E Star&quot; Award, the highest recognition any U.S. company may receive for excellence in supporting export activity, by U.S. Commerce Secretary Gary Locke. From its office in Pittsburgh, Sauereisen, Inc. offers a versatile product portfolio encompassing specialty cements, protective coatings, and linings that can be used in steel mills, food processing plants, and in other industrial settings. Sauereisen, Inc. demonstrated a sustained commitment to export expansion, in particular the increase in exports from $2.2 million in 2007 to $4.8 million in 2009 and a corresponding increase in percentage of exports to total sales from 24 to 42 percent. This growth has undoubtedly contributed to the national export expansion efforts that support the American economy and create jobs. As part of Sauereisen Inc.'s export increase, the company worked closely with the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh and various locations internationally. Sauereisen, Inc. Since 2001, Sauereisen, Inc. has taken advantage of counseling offered by the U.S. Commercial Service in Pittsburgh, and has successfully developed new markets or increase sales to countries such as China, Mexico, Israel, Kazakhstan, Kuwait, and others.</p><p><img alt="Representatives from Saint Vincent College’s Small Business Development Center (SBDC) receive a 2010 Presidential “E” Award" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Saint_Vincent_College_SBDC.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><strong style="line-height:1.6;">Saint Vincent College's Small Business Development Center (SBDC) in the Center for Global Competitiveness</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">from Latrobe, Pennsylvania, is a </span><span style="line-height:1.6;">2010 recipient of the Presidential &quot;E&quot; Award for Export Service. Awarded by U.S. Commerce Secretary Gary Locke, the Presidential &quot;E&quot; Award is the highest honor available for American businesses that display excellence in exporting. Saint Vincent College's SBDC demonstrates an enduring commitment to expanding exports through its export assistance services to rural businesses, and its hands-on counseling style. Surely the SBDC at Saint Vincent College has contributed to the national growth of exports and creation of quality American jobs. Since 1999, Saint Vincent College's SBDC took advantage of the expertise in export assistance offered by the Pittsburgh office of the U.S. Commercial Service. The SBDC was able to utilize these numerous counseling sessions to bolster exports to various countries throughout the world by rural Pennsylvanian businesses.</span></p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>2010 Presidential "E" Award Recipients - Pittsburgh U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about recipients of 2010 Presidential "E" and "E Star" Awards from the Pittsburgh area.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, award, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/709.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Sauereisen_Inc_E_Star.jpg" name="Sauereisen_Inc_E_Star"/>
      <image src="/Files/Saint_Vincent_College_SBDC.jpg" name="Saint_Vincent_College_SBDC"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/709.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/709.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
