<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>730</id>
    <title>Export Finance Resources - Sacramento U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Sacramento Export Finance</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about financial resources available for exporters in Sacramento.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/24/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/23/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">G</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">etting paid is probably the most important aspect of selling internationally. There are a number of ways to reduce the risk of non-payment from your foreign buyer. The Commercial Service offers online and live training courses on export financing assistance found through our Export.gov web site.</span></p><p>You can also access this free<a href="http://trade.gov/media/publications/abstract/trade_finance_guide2008desc.html">Trade Finance Guide</a>to begin learning on your own.</p><p>Resources on this page:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Export-Import Bank of the United States</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Small Business Administration</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">US Department of Agriculture</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Western USA Trade Association</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">California Sales Tax on Exported Products</span></li></ul><span style="line-height:20.7999992370605px;"><br></span><h2>Ex-Im Bank</h2><p>The Export-Import Bank of the United States (Ex-Im Bank) is the official export credit agency of the United States. Ex-Im Bank's mission is to assist in financing the export of U.S. goods and services to international markets.</p><p>Ex-Im Bank enables U.S. companies — large and small — to turn export opportunities into real sales that help to maintain and create U.S. jobs and contribute to a stronger national economy. Some of Ex-Im Bank's programs include:</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.exim.gov/products/work_cap.cfm" style="line-height:1.6;">Working capital guarantees</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">which allow exporters to obtain working capital loans from commercial lenders.</span><br></li><li><a href="http://www.exim.gov/products/insurance/index.cfm" style="line-height:1.6;">Export credit insurance</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">helps US exporters limit their risk and offer credit terms to international buyers.</span><br></li><li><a href="http://www.exim.gov/products/loan_guar.cfm" style="line-height:1.6;">Loan guarantees</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">enables international buyers to obtain loans for purchase of U.S. goods and services.</span><br></li></ul><p>The Sacramento Export Assistance Center works closely with our local Ex-Im Bank representative. The Sacramento area is serviced by Mr. Jim Lucchesi in Ex-Im Bank's office in San Francisco. His contact information is:</p><p>Jim Lucchesi</p><p>Senior Business Development Officer</p><p>San Francisco Branch Office</p><p>50 Fremont Street, Suite 2450<br>San Francisco, CA 94105<br>(415) 705-2285<br>(415) 705-1156 FAX</p><p>Email: Jim.Lucchesi@exim.gov</p><p>Website: <a href="http://www.exim.gov/">http://www.exim.gov​</a></p><p><br></p><h2>Small Business Administration</h2><p>The Small Business Administration also has a number of loan programs to help U.S. exporters. They include:</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/content/export-loan-programs">Export Express Loan Program</a>, a fast and easy loan for small exporters.</li><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/content/export-loan-programs">Export Working Capital Program</a>provides lenders with a guaranty on export loans as a credit enhancement.</li><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/content/export-loan-programs">International Trade Loan Program</a>offers term loans to businesses that plan to start or continue exporting, or that have been adversely affected by competition from imports.</li><li><a href="http://www.sba.gov/content/export-loan-programs">SBA and Ex-Im Bank Co-Guarantee Program</a>provides small business exporters the ability to obtain larger export working capital loans through the Export Working Capital Program than SBA can support alone</li></ul><p>The Sacramento Export Assistance Center works closely with our local SBA representative. The Sacramento area is serviced by Mr. Jerry Avila, located in Citrus Heights. His contact information is:</p><p>Jerry R. Avila<br>Regional Manager, Export Solutions Group<br>Office of International Trade<br>U.S. Small Business Administration<br>6501 Sylvan Road<br>Citrus Heights, California 95610<br>Tel : 916-735-1708<br>Fax: 202-741-6851<br>Email:<a href="mailto:jerry.avila@sba.gov">jerry.avila@sba.gov</a></p><p><br></p><h2>USDA - United States Department of Agriculture</h2><p>Export Credit Guarantee Programs</p><p>The Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC), U.S. Department of Agriculture, administers export credit guarantee programs for commercial financing of U.S. agricultural exports. The programs encourage exports to buyers in countries where credit is necessary to maintain or increase U.S. sales, but where financing may not be available without CCC guarantees. Under all CCC programs:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Exporters must apply to be qualified to participate in CCC programs</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Exporters must use qualified U.S. and foreign banks</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Exporters must have a firm export sale before submitting an application</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">The product must meet the definition of a U.S. agricultural commodity</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">The guarantee fee paid at the time of application is non-refundable</span><br></li></ul><p>Two programs underwrite credit extended by the private banking sector in the United States to approved foreign banks using dollar-denominated, irrevocable letters of credit to pay for food and agricultural products sold to foreign buyers. The Export Credit Guarantee Program (GSM-102) covers credit terms up to three years. The Intermediate Export Credit Guarantee Program (GSM-103) covers longer credit terms up to 10 years. These programs are designed to expand and maintain foreign markets for U.S. agricultural commodities, and can help developing nations make the transition from concessional financing to cash purchases. The Supplier Credit Guarantee Program (SCGP) guarantees payments on promissory notes from importers for a percentage of the face value up to 180 days. The Facility Guarantee Program (FGP) provides payment guarantees to facilitate the financing of U.S. goods and services exported to improve or establish agriculture-related facilities in emerging markets. Under these programs, which are administered by the Foreign Agricultural Service (FAS), the CCC does not provide financing, but guarantees payments due from foreign banks. Typically, 98 percent of principal and a portion of interest at an adjustable rate are covered. Because payment is guaranteed, financial institutions in the United States can offer competitive credit terms to the foreign banks, usually with interest rates based on the London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR). Any follow-on credit arrangements between the foreign bank and the importer are negotiated separately and are not covered by the CCC guarantee.</p><p>USDA Contact Information</p><p>Deputy Administrator, Export Credits; FAS, USDA</p><p>Stop 1031, 1400 Independence Avenue, SW</p><p>Washington, DC 20250-1031</p><p>(202) 720-6301 Phone</p><p>(202) 690-0727 Fax</p><p>Email: askec@fas.usda.gov</p><p>Website: <a href="http://www.fas.usda.gov/">http://www.fas.usda.gov​</a></p><p><br></p><h2>WUSATA - Western USA Trade Association</h2><p>WUSATA's integrated marketing services are designed to help exporters of Western U.S. agricultural products to develop and expand their international markets. By utilizing a combination of WUSATA services companies can achieve maximum marketing impact.</p><p>WUSATA Local Contact Information</p><p>Shelly Caldwell, Outreach Coordinator</p><p>4601 North East 77th Ave, Suite 120</p><p>Vancouver, WA 98662</p><p>(360) 693-3373 Phone</p><p>(360) 693-3464 Fax</p><p>Email: shelly@wusata.org</p><p>Website: <a href="http://www.wusata.org/">http://www.wusata.org</a></p><p><br></p><h2>California Sales Tax on Exported Products</h2><p>Sales tax generally does not apply to your transaction when you sell a product and ship it directly to the purchaser at an out-of-state location, for use outside California. Your sale is not taxable if you:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Ship th</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">e product directly to the purchaser, using your own delivery vehicle or another means of transport that you own; or</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Ship the product by delivering it to a common carrier (including the U.S. Postal Service), contract carrier, customs broker, export packer, or forwarding agent (see Note, below); or,</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Sell items that will be used in other countries, deliver the product in a way that meets the special delivery conditions explained below; or</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">​Sell new, noncommercial vehicles to foreign residents, deliver the vehicle in a way that meets specific conditions explained in Regulation 1620, Interstate and Foreign Commerce</span><br></li></ul><p>From the Board of Equalization:<a href="http://www.boe.ca.gov/sutax/pub101/index.html">http://www.boe.ca.gov/sutax/pub101/index.html</a></p><p>Aaron Bone</p><p>Board of Equalization</p><p>Outreach Services Manager</p><p>916-322-9195</p><p><a href="mailto:aaron.bone@boe.ca.gov">aaron.bone@boe.ca.gov</a>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
        <topic>Trade Finance</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Export Finance Resources - Sacramento U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about financial resources available for exporters in Sacramento.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, finance, Sacramento, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/730.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/730.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/730.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
