<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>750</id>
    <title>Whitford Corporation: Export Success Story</title>
    <short_title>Whitford Export Success</short_title>
    <summary>Get details about how Whitford Corporation earned an Export Achievement Award from the Department of Commerce.</summary>
    <creation_date>4/30/2013</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Whitford Corporation Receives Export Achievement Award from the Department of Commerce</h1><p>Not Rated </p><p><br></p><h2>Whitford Corporation Receives Export Award</h2><p>Whitford Corporation received an Export Achievement Certificate for recent accomplishments in the global market place. Whitford Corporation of Elverson, PA is a leading manufacturer of the world's largest range of nonstick fluoropolymer coatings used in both consumer and industrial applications. They focus on providing specialty coatings containing fluoropolymers as the active ingredient and manufacture the largest, most complete line of fluoropolymer coatings in the world.</p><p>Whitford Corporation's international market development office has been working with the Middletown, CT Export Assistance Center for seven years. Whitford has made extensive use of the Commercial Service's Gold Key Service program and has utilized this service over nineteen times to foreign markets including: China, Russia, Japan, India and others. Many of these Commercial Service assisted visits have resulted in opening or expanding overseas markets for Whitford Corporation products.</p><p>&quot;Whitford has participated in numerous market research and development projects internationally. The Commercial Service has been instrumental in contributing to the company's growth, &quot; Richard Adler, Whitford, Market Development Manager commented.</p><p><em>With its network of offices across the United States and in more than 80 countries, the U.S. Commercial Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce's International Trade Administration utilizes its global presence and international marketing expertise to help U.S. companies sell their products and services worldwide. For more information, visit</em><a href="http://www.export.gov/"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><em><strong>www.Export.gov</strong></em></span></a><em>.</em></p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
        <topic>Trade Promotion<sub_topic>Business Matchmaking</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Asia</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Industrial Equipment &amp; Supplies</industry>
      </industries>
      <countries>
        <country>China</country>
        <country>Russia</country>
        <country>Japan</country>
        <country>India</country>
      </countries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Whitford Corporation: Export Success Story</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Get details about how Whitford Corporation earned an Export Achievement Award from the Department of Commerce</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Connecticut Export Assistance Center, Gold Key Service Program, Export Achievement Certificate</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/750.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/750.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/750.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
