<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>755</id>
    <title>Trade Assistant Internship - San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Trade Internship - SF USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about trade assistant internship opportunities available at the San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/28/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">There are</span><strong style="line-height:1.6;">two</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">Trade Assistant internships available for</span><strong style="line-height:1.6;">summer 2014</strong><span style="line-height:1.6;">. We offer a highly international work environment, as well as on-the-job training. Our past interns have leveraged their experience with us to gain admission to top graduate schools, as well as to land jobs with major international companies and follow-on internships in U.S. Embassies around the world.</span></p><p><strong><em>Note: You must be a US citizen and currently enrolled in an academic institution.</em></strong></p><h2>Responsibilities:</h2><p>As a member of our team in San Francisco, your duties will include educating prospective clients about our services, as well as working with our team of international business advisors to provide research and other services to our current clients. Additionally, you will work with our team of international business advisors to develop market research information about firms in key sectors of the San Francisco area. Lastly, you will also have the opportunity to learn to operate new programs and platforms such as Google Earth Pro tools and websites for our clients.</p><h2>Qualifications:</h2><p>Ideal candidates will possess excellent written and oral communication skills as well as interpersonal and research skills. Knowledge of the Microsoft Office Suite including Excel and Word is<em>critical</em>. Skills in website design programs are helpful. Prior knowledge of business is not necessary, but a demonstrated strong interest in international affairs will be important. Asecond language and/or international experience would be a plus, but is not required. We are also looking for someone who can dedicate a 3-4 months and 20-25 hours per week during normal business hours (Monday-Friday from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.). The internship will ideally start in<strong>June and run through August 2014.</strong></p><h2>​How to Apply:</h2><p>Please send a resume, writing sample, and a brief explanation of your interest in the internship to Internship Coordinator, Daniel Giavina at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:office.sanfrancisco@trade.gov">office.sanfrancisco@trade.gov</a>. Applicants who do not submit all three items will not be considered.</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Trade Assistant Internship - San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about trade assistant internship opportunities available at the San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, San Francisco, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/755.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/755.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/755.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
