<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>756</id>
    <title>Cleantech Internship - San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Cleantech Internship - SF</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about cleantech internship opportunities with the San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/28/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/27/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">We offer a highly international work environment, as well as on-the-job training. Our past interns have leveraged their experience with us to gain admission to top graduate schools, as well as to land jobs with major international companies and follow-on internships in U.S. Embassies around the world.</span></p><p><strong><em>Note: You must be a US citizen and currently enrolled in an academic institution.</em></strong></p><h2>Responsibilities:</h2><p>We are seeking one Cleantech Research Analyst Intern. In San Francisco, much of our work centers on clean technology. This internshipprovides an unusual opportunity to gain government experience while workingdirectly withsome ofthe world's most innovative cleantech firms. Duties include tracking industry trends across Northern California, monitoring and reporting on policy and market developments on five continents, and researchingspecific issues brought to us by individual firms.</p><h2>Qualifications:</h2><p>Students in any major with excellent research and writing skills are encouraged to apply. Prior knowledge of business is not necessary, but a demonstrated strong interest in clean technology and international affairs will be important. Asecond language and/or international experience would be a plus, but is not required.We are also looking for someone who can dedicate a minimum of 15-18 hours per week to the job during normal business hours (Monday-Friday from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.). The internship will ideally start in<strong>May and run through August 2014.</strong></p><h2>How to Apply:</h2><p>Please send a resume, writing sample, and a brief explanation of your interest in the internship to Internship Coordinator, Daniel Giavina at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:office.sanfrancisco@trade.gov">office.sanfrancisco@trade.gov</a>. Applicants who do not submit all three items will not be considered.​​</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Cleantech Internship - San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about cleantech internship opportunities with the San Francisco U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, San Francisco, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/756.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/756.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/756.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
