<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>763</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - San Jose U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - San Jose USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the San Jose U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/29/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/28/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;">​The United States Commercial Service, an agency within the U.S. Department of Commerce, works to assist the U.S. business community in expanding into international markets worldwide. Our network includes over 160 offices in nearly 90 countries. The Commercial Service office in San Jose offers programs to assist U.S. companies located in the Silicon Valley.</span></p><p>As a member of our team in San Jose, your duties will include educating prospective clients about our services, as well as working with our team of international business advisors to provide research and other services to our current clients. Additionally, you will work with our team of international business advisors to develop market research information about firms in key sectors of the Silicon Valley.</p><p>We offer a highly international-focused work environment, as well as on-the-job training. Our past interns have leveraged their experience with us to gain admission to top graduate schools, as well as to land jobs with major international companies and follow-on internships in US Embassies around the world.</p><p>Ideal candidates will possess excellent written and oral communication skills, interpersonal and research skills. Knowledge of Microsoft Office is critical.</p><p>Students in any major with excellent research and writing skills are encouraged to apply. Prior knowledge of business is not necessary, but a demonstrated strong interest in technology and international affairs will be important. Asecond language and/or international experience would be a plus, but is not required.We are also looking for someone who can dedicate a minimum of 15 hours per week to the job during the summer. This is a non-paid internship.</p><p><strong>Note: You must be a US citizen and currently enrolled in an academic institution.</strong></p><p>If you are interested in applying for an internship with the U.S. Commercial Service's Silicon Valley Export Assistance Center, please email your resume to Karl Kailing, International Trade Specialist at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:Karl.Kailing@trade.gov">Karl.Kailing@trade.gov</a>.​</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - San Jose U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the San Jose U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, San Jose, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/763.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/763.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/763.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
