<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>774</id>
    <title>FUSE Qualifications</title>
    <short_title>FUSE Qualifications</short_title>
    <summary>Information about how to qualify for and receive export assistance services through FUSE.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/30/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date/>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/104282-1.jpg" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></p><h1><strong>Qualifications for Listing on Local U.S. Commercial Service Websites</strong></h1><p>This program is offered to <strong>clients</strong> of the U.S. Commercial Service. </p><p>If your company is not a client of the U.S. Commercial Service but is interested in learning more about our export promotion services, please locate <a href="http://export.gov/usoffices/index.asp">your nearest Export Assistance Center</a> by zip code. Most companies with a U.S.-made product available for export overseas will qualify for assistance. </p><p>Typically, U.S. exporters will use our services to seek a manufacturer's representative, distributor, buyers, or franchisees in non-U.S. markets. </p><p>We may decline the following for posting to overseas U.S. Commercial Service websites: </p><ul><li>Products of companies that do not provide complete or accurate information when registering </li><li>Products which, in the local market for which a posting is requested, are currently not viable due to local market regulation or other conditions </li><li>Products which, if listed in a particular local website's directory, may hurt the overall effectiveness of the website by offending local norms </li><li>Products of companies without a functioning online presence (website or webpage), such that we are unable to obtain an appropriate image </li></ul><p>The final determination of the suitability of a listing will be made by the management of each U.S. Commercial Service overseas office for which a listing on the local website is requested, or by the Featured U.S. Exporters Program Manager. </p><p>Unfortunately, due to the high volume of requests for listings, we are unable to respond to requests from companies that do not qualify for participation. If you are unsure, please contact a Trade Specialist at your nearest <a href="http://export.gov/usoffices/index.asp">Export Assistance Center</a> first, before registering. </p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
        <topic>Trade Promotion<sub_topic>Business Matchmaking</sub_topic></topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Services</industry>
        <industry>Information &amp; Communication</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Featured U.S. Exporters - FUSE</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>FUSE Qualifications</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Information about how to qualify for and receive export assistance services through FUSE.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>FUSE, featured exporters, language, commercial service</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/774.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/104282-1.jpg" name="104282-1"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/774.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/774.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
