<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>781</id>
    <title>Internship Opportunities - San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>Internships - San Diego USEAC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/31/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/30/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p></p><p>An internship offers the opportunity for students to learn about career opportunities with the federal government and gain international business experience. International Trade Interns assist International Trade Specialists in preparing market research and advising San Diego business clients on exporting strategies. Interns participate in meetings with San Diego area companies, international business organizations, and foreign officials. They also assist in developing and organizing trade promotion events and activities.</p><h2>Requirements:</h2><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Full or part-time student - U.S. Citizen</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Relevant academic field - Minimum 160 hour requirement</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Strong writing and verbal communication - Good interpersonal skills</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Knowledge of PC software: Word, Excel, Outlook, Adobe</span><br></li></ul><h2>Internship Duties:</h2><p>Business Counseling: Assist companies through export process, regulations, and organizing trade events.</p><p>International Market Research: Undertake market research utilizing a variety of resources, including databases and internet.</p><p>Trade Event Promotion: Organization of international and U.S. trade events.</p><p>Administrative: Preparing communications with companies, and maintaining company database profiles.</p><h2>How to Apply:</h2><p>To be considered for an internship, please submit a cover letter and resume to Internship Coordinator, Julia Rauner Guerrero.</p><ul><li>By December 1st for Spring Semester<br></li><li>By March 1st for Summer​<br></li><li>By August 1st for Fall Semester<br></li></ul><p><strong>For more information</strong>contact Julia Rauner Guerrero at (858) 467-7043 or send<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:julia.rauner@trade.gov">email</a>with resume and we will return your inquiry.</p><p>Thank youfor considering an internship with the U.S. Dept. of Commerce. Although the<strong>internship in unpaid</strong>, we provide a solid entry level experience or students who wish to pursue careers in international trade.</p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Internship Opportunities - San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about internship opportunities available at the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, internships, San Diego, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/781.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/781.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/781.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
