<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>783</id>
    <title>Welcome to the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center</title>
    <short_title>San Diego USEAC Homepage</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center.</summary>
    <creation_date>10/31/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>10/30/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<span style="line-height:1.6;text-align:justify;">We are the export office of the International Trade Administration working on behalf of U.S. business to promote trade and investment, to help U.S. organizations compete at home and abroad.</span></p><p style="text-align:justify;">ITA supports President Obama's recovery agenda and the National Export Initiative to sustain economic growth and support American jobs. Our experienced staff of international trade specialists provide business persons face-to-face counseling at no charge. We are able to meet with you personally, confidentially and as frequently as necessary to define and analyze your opportunities and win international sales.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">To schedule a meeting with a trade specialist please click here: <a href="http://www.export.gov/california/sandiego/tuay/index.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">TellUsAboutYou</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">.</span></p><h2>The San Diego/Baja California Border Trade Office Located in San Diego​​</h2><p style="text-align:justify;">Recognizing the ongoing business potential the Baja and Northwest Mexico market offers U.S. exporters, the San Diego Export Assistance Center has created an Americas Center and California/Mexico Border Trade Office. With almost 900 maquiladora (manufacturing for export) operations, Baja California has more of these plants than any other state in Mexico. To increase their worldwide competitiveness, many of these companies are aggressively seeking local suppliers from Southern California and the border region to meet their needs. The Border Trade Office can provide U.S. firms with market counseling and business matchmaking support needed to tap into this market. For more information, contact Commercial Officer Rick de Lambert at<a href="http://informationportalprodmailto:rick.delambert@trade.gov">rick.delambert@trade.gov</a></p><table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default"><tbody><tr><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"><p><strong>2014 Monthly Newsletter</strong></p><p><strong>Calendar of California Events</strong></p></td><td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"><a href="http://export.gov/california/static/Pacific%20South%20Newsletter%20April%202014_Latest_eg_us_ca_072656.pdf">Control Click to View Newsletter</a></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Welcome to the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the San Diego U.S. Export Assistance Center.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, San Diego, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/783.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/783.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/783.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
