<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>809</id>
    <title>Our Partners - Chambers of Commerce</title>
    <short_title>Our Partners - COC</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about Chambers of Commerce that you could partner with.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/11/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets<source_office>U.S. Commerical Service</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Strategic Partners</h1><p>The use of logos does not connote endorsement by the Department of Commerce of the organizations' views, products, or services.</p><h2>Chambers of Commerce</h2><p>​<img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20belize.jpg" alt="American Chamber of Commerce - Belize Logo" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchambelize.org/welcome.php#mission">American Chamber of Commerce – Belize</a> promotes and facilitates trade and commerce between the United States of America and Belize by representing business interests at Government level and in the media, encouraging linkages with Belizean companies and to provide a forum for exchange of information beneficial to all parties.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20dominican%20republic.jpg" alt="AMCHAMDR Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amcham.org.do/en">American Chamber of Commerce of the Dominican Republic (AMCHAMDR)</a> is a nonprofit organization made up of around 2,500 companies, both Dominican and American, that seeks to empower its members to develop their potential to the maximum based on three pillars – economic, professional, and social – through the facilitation of access to knowledge, opportunities, a culture of best practices, respect for the rule of law, and corporate social responsibility. AMCHAMDR is the only institution of its kind with a truly national presence through its10 offices around the country.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/chilean-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" alt="AmCham Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchamchile.cl/node/110125">Chilean-American Chamber of Commerce (AmCham)</a> was founded in Valparaíso in 1918 with the mission of promoting free trade and business between the United States and Chile. It presently provides its associates with a variety of benefits, including practical assistance for their business and lobbying representation before the appropriate Chilean or U.S. authorities. AmCham has become a driving force in promoting bilateral trade between Chile and the United States. AmCham has almost 700 member companies and represents 90% of US investment in Chile. </p><p><span><img alt="AmCham Colombia Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/colombo%20american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /></span></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchamcolombia.com.co/index.php?&amp;lang=en">Colombo American Chamber of Commerce</a> (AmCham Colombia) is a non-profit organization founded on 1955. AmCham brings the private sector in Colombia and the United States together and carries out an active work agenda, destined to promote trade and investment between the United States, Colombia and other countries in the region. Members of AmCham include US and Colombian companies, as well as companies in other countries. Today, AmCham has approximately 1000 affiliated members across the country, which together represent close to 24% of the national GDP. Apart from Bogotá, AmCham has regional offices in Barranquilla, Cali, Cartagena and Medellín.</p><p><img alt="AmCham Costa Rica Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/costa%20rican%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amcham.co.cr">Costa Rican-American Chamber of Commerce (AmCham Costa Rica)</a> was founded thirty-nine years ago by a group of Costa Rican and US business executives. With a vision towards promoting and nurturing the bilateral commercial relationship between the United States and Costa Rica on the principle that a strong private sector is essential to the country's economic well-being and it will strengthen its democratic principles. Today AmCham Costa Rica's organization consists of 400 companies and 1300 corporate representatives divided almost 50/50 between Costa Rican and US interests. The Chamber's membership represents 80% of Costa Rica's foreign direct investment and 80% of the country's exports.</p><p><img alt="American Chamber of El Salvador Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20el%20salvador.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchamsal.com?cat=1000">American Chamber of El Salvador</a> is an independent, non-profit institution representing, promoting and developing U.S. business interests in El Salvador , as well as serving the business community at-large by fostering trade and investment between the United States and El Salvador. AmCham El Salvador works with the Salvadoran government on projects of mutual interest and benefit, serves as a liaison with the U.S. Embassy, and represents its members before the government, the business community and the general public. Services include business facilitation and networking opportunities, strategic analysis, advocacy initiatives, events, government relations, commercial information resources and more.</p><p><img alt="AMCHAM-Honduras Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/amcham-honduras.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchamhonduras.org/default_en.asp">AMCHAM-Honduras</a> is an apolitical and independent non-profit organization composed by American and Honduran companies as well as other organizations that are supportive of AMCHAM`s activities through their annual monetary contribution, and their valued time and talent. Its main objective is to tighten and strengthen the commercial relationships and promote the investment between Honduras and the United States of America. </p><p>AMCHAM-Honduras is a link within the network of American Chambers of Commerce in over 60 countries in Latin America, Asia, and Europe affiliated to the Chamber of Commerce of the United States in Washington D.C., through the American Association of Chambers of Commerce in Latin America (AACCLA).</p><p><img alt="AmCham Mexico" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20mexico.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>From its inception, <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amcham.org.mx">American Chamber of Commerce of Mexico (AmCham Mexico)</a> has worked to promote the openness, transparency, and best practices within and outside the member companies. AmCham Mexico works to improve and grow their businesses by maintaining a neutral, apolitical, objective, and truthful voice by seeking the best for its members in Mexico, the U.S., and the world. AmCham Mexico has garnered a list of accomplishments in Mexico by developing an extensive range of activities focused on serving its members.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry%20of%20panama.jpg" alt="AmCham Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://panamcham.com">American Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Panama</a> (AMCHAM) was created on October 31, 1979, by a handful of business people who felt that the organization could be an important voice in promoting business ideas in Panama. AMCHAM membership has grown from 68 firms in its first year, to over 460+ member companies today. Since its founding, the Chamber has provided members with conferences and seminars on a variety of important topics. In addition, the Chamber publishes a selection of newsletters, research articles, a monthly magazine and an annual directory. </p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20peru.jpg" alt="AmCham Peru Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amcham.org.pe/home">American Chamber of Commerce of Peru (AmCham Peru)</a> is an independent nonprofit founded on January 17, 1968. It has approximately 3,000 members representing over 580 member companies in the U.S. and Peru. AmCham Peru is part of the Association of American Chambers of Commerce in Latin America (AACCLA), which has 23 chambers of commerce in 21 countries in Latin America and the Caribbean. AACCLA consists of more than 20,000 associates who meet 85% of American investments in the region and is part of the Chamber of Commerce of the United States (USCC), the largest business federation in the world with over 3 million associated.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20in%20shanghai.jpg" alt="American Chamber of Commerce in Shanghai Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amcham-shanghai.org/AmChamPortal/PortalDefault.aspx?HLLink=Par_link_Homepage&amp;tb_Name=Home">American Chamber of Commerce in Shanghai</a>, known as the &quot;Voice of American Business&quot; in China, is the largest and fastest growing American Chamber in the Asia Pacific region. Founded in 1915, AmCham Shanghai was the third American Chamber established outside the United States. As a non-profit, non-partisan business organization, AmCham Shanghai is committed to the principles of free trade, open markets, private enterprise and the unrestricted flow of information. </p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/chamber%20of%20commerce%20uruguay-usa.jpg" alt="Chamber of Commerce Uruguay-USA Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ccuruguayusa.com/en"> Chamber of Commerce Uruguay-USA</a>, founded in 1934, is an independent, non-profit organization whose main objective is the promotion of trade and investment between the United States and Uruguay. At present, the Chamber has more than 100 members representing the American business presence in Uruguay. AmCham Uruguay is one of the largest bi-national Chambers in Uruguay and it is exclusively financed via member contributions.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/coimbatore%20district%20small%20industries%20association.jpg" alt="CODISSIA Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://codissia.com">Coimbatore District Small Industries Association</a> (CODISSIA) was established in the year 1969 with strength of 40 members. Today the organization has grown and serves more than 5200 members. CODISSIA has made a significant contribution towards building a strong and stable industrial city in Coimbatore. CODISSIA focuses on small-scale industries and has made a mark at the District /State and National level. The Association renders guidance and help to the new entrepreneurs to identify products, preparation of project reports, getting financial assistance from banks etc. and licenses from various departments. </p><p><img alt="Flint and Genesee Chamber of Commerce Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/flint%20and%20genesee%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.flintandgenesee.org">Flint &amp; GeneseeChamber of Commerce</a> is the economic engine driving business development in the City of Flint and Genesee County, Michigan. The Chamber serves as the voice of community advocacy. Our mission is to facilitate partnerships between public, private and nonprofit entities to maximize economic growth and diversity in the county. Born with an entrepreneurial spirit that jump-started the automobile industry, the region offers a wealth of amenities that embrace tradition and innovation. Nationally ranked universities, leading medical centers and internationally acclaimed performing arts groups provide a rich quality of life for Genesee visitors, businesses and families.</p><p><img alt=" Guatemalan-American Chamber of Commerce Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/guatemalan-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.amchamguate.com/index.php"> Guatemalan-American Chamber of Commerce</a> is a non profit, non-religious, non-government association whose main purpose is to promote and strengthen trade and investment between Guatemala and the United States. We work to improve business climate in Guatemala and defend rule of law. Our core objectives always include the defense of intellectual property rights, fight contraband, and promote business social responsibility, among others. We currently have 496 members, making us the largest bi-national chamber of commerce in the country. We are an opinion leader, making solid and objective pronouncements on issues that concern international trade.</p><p><img alt="ICCI Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry,%20cochin.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://iccicochin.com">Indian Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Cochin</a> (ICCI) is one of the oldest organizations of its kind in the country. The Indian Chamber of Commerce was established in 1912. The chamber was originally incorporated in 1897 as &quot;The Cochin Native Merchants' Association&quot;. The membership of the chamber includes about 500 ordinary members and 10 affiliated members representing important segments of trade. The Chamber is affiliated to the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) and the All India Organization of Employers (AIOE), New Delhi. Although the mission of ICCI, Cochin is to serve the business community, it also seeks to proactively influence public policy on issues that impact economy, trade, commerce and industry as well as the social issues of education, health, infrastructure and the environment.</p><p><img alt="ICC Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>Founded in 1925,<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.indianchamber.net/default.aspx"> Indian Chamber of Commerce </a>(ICC) is the leading and only national Chamber of Commerce operating from Kolkata. As one of the most pro-active and forward-looking Chambers in the country, its membership includes some of the most prominent industrial groups. ICC is the founder member of FICCI, the apex body of business and industry in India. ICC's forte is its ability to anticipate the needs of the future, respond to challenges, and prepare the stakeholders in the economy to benefit from these changes and opportunities. The ICC is an important chamber partner for the U.S. Commercial Service in eastern and northeastern India. Three American Business Corners are managed by ICC staff in Assam, Bihar, and Odisha.</p><p><img alt="Irvine Chamber of Commerce Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/irvine%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.irvineglobalmarkets.com"> Irvine Chamber of Commerce</a> hosts the Irvine Global Market Intelligence series which features bi-monthly webinars on international trade that are open to the public at no cost and are later archived. The series focuses on specific country markets with presentations on exports (with the Senior Commercial Officer at US Embassies) and imports (counterpart export promotion agency in the US). In addition, the Irvine Chamber hosts in-bound trade delegations, holds training seminars and has monthly meetings focused on international business. </p><p><img alt="MCC Logo" src="http://informationportalprod/Files/manhattan%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.manhattancc.org">The Manhattan Chamber of Commerce (MCC)</a> represents member businesses ranging from sole proprietors to large corporations. With 10,000 members and subscribers, we represent the voice of over 100,000 companies in Manhattan and partner with over 300 diverse business organizations in the city. Our mission is to advocate for, connect and educate the business community in Manhattan. Our MCC Global Network offers the chance for businesses, state economic and commercial agencies, bilateral chambers of commerce, trade associations and educational institutions to work together to provide global resources for NYC companies and for foreign companies seeking to do business in NYC.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/metro%20atlanta%20chamber.jpg" alt="Metro Atlanta Chamber Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.metroatlantachamber.com/Default.aspx?AspxAutoDetectCookieSupport=1">Metro Atlanta Chamber</a> is a private business organization focused on growing metro Atlanta companies. The Metro Atlanta Chamber's Global Commerce team can assist you in your international growth efforts in the following ways:</p><ul><li>Consult with you to ensure you are properly prepared to go international;</li><li>Connect you with appropriate contacts (service providers &amp; government contacts as well as industry and market experts) both locally and in country; and </li><li>Take you to market via regular Trade Missions to introduce you to relevant companies and influential business contacts in country.</li></ul><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/mohali%20industries%20association.jpg" alt="MIA Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.mohaliindustries.com">Mohali Industries Association</a> (MIA) was established in 1972, and our membership strength of 450 members includes small to large scale manufacturing units which cover a wide range of sectors from auto/tractor parts to refrigeration and electronic &amp; electrical (medical, instrumentation, defense etc).. We have advocates, consultants and advisors as our associate members. The aim of our Association is to strive for Unity, Continual Improvement and Flourishing Business for MIA members. We have affiliated memberships of Confederation of Indian Industry (CII), PHD Chamber of Commerce and Industry and Federation of Indian Small and Medium Enterprises (FISME). </p><p><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.anierm.org.mx/es/default/home">The National Association of Importers and Exporters of Mexico</a> (ANIERM) is a civil non-profit organization that brings together and represents not only importers and exporters of a wide range of products, but also logistics providers, brokers, lenders, service companies and generally, the whole community directly or indirectly linked to foreign trade in Mexico. The ANIERM provides its partners a wide range of specialized services in international trade and customs ranging from financial information, newsletters and publications, through counseling, agency, consultancy and training, to promotion and identification of business opportunities. </p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/rajasthan%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" alt="RCCI Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>Located in Jaipur, Rajasthan, the <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.rajchamber.com">Rajasthan Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry</a> (RCCI), started functioning in 1949 under the Jaipur Companies Act, 1942. RCCI is the apex organization of industry and trade in Rajasthan. The Divisional Chamber of Commerce and Industry located in different regions, namely Jaipur, Marwar (Jodhpur), Hadoti (Kota), Udaipur and Mewar (Bhilwara), along with more than 300 Product Manufacturing Associations, Professional Bodies and Organizations of Micro-level Entrepreneurs including Handicraft and Handloom Manufacturing Associations, Federation of Mining Association of Rajasthan, Federation of Association of Small Industries of Rajasthan, and Federation of Organizations of Rajasthan Exporters are affiliated with it. In addition, District Industries Associations, Distric Vyapar Mandals, Foodgrain Associations and Industrial Area Associations are also affiliatedwith RCCI. </p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/southern%20gujarat%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" alt="SGCCI Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.sgcci.in">Southern Gujarat Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry</a> (SGCCI), established in 1940, is one of the oldest chambers in Gujarat, with a focus on growth and the development of trade and industry in the Southern Gujarat region of India. SCGGI has a base of nearly 6000 members and 92 associations from a wide spectrum of trade and industry. To boost trade and share information with its members and the public at large, SGCCI conducts seminars, workshops and training programs on subjects of varied interests. SGCCI is committed to the development and strong evolution of the Micro Small &amp; Medium Enterprises segment in Southern Gujarat.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/tamilnadu%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" alt="Tamilnadu Chamber of Commerce and Industry Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://tnchamber.in">Tamilnadu Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry</a> was incorporated in 1924 in Madurai with just 24 members with the primary objective of serving the cause of Trade and Industry. Over the years, it has steadily grown in strength and diversified its services and activities. The present membership of the Chamber is more than 6500 with more than 350 smaller chambers and trade associations affiliated to it. By far, it is now the largest Chamber in India in membership strength. The Chamber's objective is to make effective and timely representations to the State and Central Governments to address the grievances of Trade and Industry, and to provide necessary infrastructure for establishment of heavy industries in the Southern districts of Tamilnadu.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/tri-county%20black%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" alt="Tri-County Black Chamber of Commerce Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.tcbcc.org">Tri-County Black Chamber of Commerce</a>'s goal is to provide our network of member business owners with high level business development services focused on securing large public and/or private contracts; stimulating job creation; and facilitating entry into the global marketplace.<br></p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/vizagapatam%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" alt="VCCI Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://vizagchamber.com">Vizagapatam Chamber of Commerce (VCCI)</a> is a non-government, nonprofit, industry led and industry managed organization that plays a proactive role in India's development process. VCCI was incorporated in 1931 with an emphasis to invite national and international companies to invest in Visakhapatnam and make it a vibrant Chamber at a domestic and global level. It grew as an association with the increase of industrial and commercial establishments in and around Vizag with the primary aim of facilitating trade and commerce and providing a common platform for all industries in Vizag to come together, exchange ideas, and make their voices heard.<br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Services</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnership Program</trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnerships</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Our Partners - Chambers of Commerce</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about Chambers of Commerce that you could partner with.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>strategic partnership program, strategic partners, chamber of commerce, commercial service</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/809.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20belize.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20belize"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20dominican%20republic.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20-%20dominican%20republic"/>
      <image src="/Files/chilean-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="chilean-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/colombo%20american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="colombo%20american%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/costa%20rican%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="costa%20rican%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20el%20salvador.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20el%20salvador"/>
      <image src="/Files/amcham-honduras.jpg" name="amcham-honduras"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20mexico.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20mexico"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry%20of%20panama.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry%20of%20panama"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20peru.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20of%20peru"/>
      <image src="/Files/american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20in%20shanghai.jpg" name="american%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20in%20shanghai"/>
      <image src="/Files/chamber%20of%20commerce%20uruguay-usa.jpg" name="chamber%20of%20commerce%20uruguay-usa"/>
      <image src="/Files/coimbatore%20district%20small%20industries%20association.jpg" name="coimbatore%20district%20small%20industries%20association"/>
      <image src="/Files/flint%20and%20genesee%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="flint%20and%20genesee%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/guatemalan-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="guatemalan-american%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry,%20cochin.jpg" name="indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry,%20cochin"/>
      <image src="/Files/indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="indian%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/irvine%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="irvine%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/manhattan%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="manhattan%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/metro%20atlanta%20chamber.jpg" name="metro%20atlanta%20chamber"/>
      <image src="/Files/mohali%20industries%20association.jpg" name="mohali%20industries%20association"/>
      <image src="/Files/rajasthan%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" name="rajasthan%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry"/>
      <image src="/Files/southern%20gujarat%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" name="southern%20gujarat%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry"/>
      <image src="/Files/tamilnadu%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry.jpg" name="tamilnadu%20chamber%20of%20commerce%20and%20industry"/>
      <image src="/Files/tri-county%20black%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="tri-county%20black%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/vizagapatam%20chamber%20of%20commerce.jpg" name="vizagapatam%20chamber%20of%20commerce"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/809.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/809.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
