<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>810</id>
    <title>Christy Test Regression</title>
    <short_title>Christy Test Regression</short_title>
    <summary>Christy Test Regression</summary>
    <creation_date>11/12/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date/>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration</source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1 class="Header-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:16px;color:#000000;font-weight:bold;line-height:1.6em;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:4pt;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong>​Strategic Partners</strong></h1><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The use of logos does not connote endorsement by the Department of Commerce of the organizations’ views, products, or services.</p><h2 class="SubHeader-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:13px;color:#000000;font-style:italic;font-weight:bold;line-height:1.4em;margin:12px 3pt 12px 0pt;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><a name="P4_147"></a>Associations</strong></h2><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="230" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-1.jpg" height="45" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">ACA</a>is a voluntary, nonprofit trade association working to advance the needs of the paint and coatings industry and the professionals who work in it. The organization represents paint and coatings manufacturers, raw materials suppliers, distributors, and technical professionals. ACA serves as an advocate and ally for members on legislative, regulatory and judicial issues, and provides forums for the advancement and promotion of the industry through educational and professional development services.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="175" alt="American Gear Manufacturer Association Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-2.jpg" height="60" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">AGMA</a>, founded in 1916, is a member and market-driven organization, conducting programs and providing services to the gear industry and its customers. As a voluntary association of companies, consultants and academicians with a direct interest in the design, manufacture, and application of gears and flexible couplings, our mission is to help members compete more effectively in today's global marketplace.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="115" alt="AHRI Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-3.jpg" height="63" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">AHRI</a>is one of the largest trade associations in the nation, representing more than 300 heating, water heating, ventilation, air conditioning and commercial refrigeration manufacturers within the global HVACR industry. AHRI’s 300+ member companies account for more than 90 percent of the residential and commercial air conditioning, space heating, water heating, and commercial refrigeration equipment manufactured and sold in North America. AHRI advocates on behalf of its members at all levels of government, working to ensure that member’s interests are included in final legislation. We also have a certification program that is specified globally and relied heavily upon by regulators for accurate and unbiased evaluation of heating, water heating, ventilation, air conditioning, and commercial refrigeration equipment. Lastly, AHRI develops industry-recognized performance standards for industry equipment. These three tiers – advocacy, standards, and certification – are at AHRI’s core. Aside from these three tiers, AHRI is viewed as a resource for industry shipment data, education and workforce information, and research. AHRI is an industry powerhouse, providing our members with one industry voice, both domestically and abroad.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="132" alt="The Association For Manufacturing Technology logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-4.jpg" height="46" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">The Association For Manufacturing Technology (AMT)</a>represents and promotes U.S.-based manufacturing technology and its members—those who design, build, sell, and service the continuously evolving technology that lies at the heart of manufacturing.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">Founded in 1902 and based in Virginia, the association specializes in providing targeted business assistance, extensive global support, and business intelligence systems and analysis. AMT advocates for advanced manufacturing through innovation and R&amp;D, as well as the development of an education initiative known as Smartforce. AMT owns and manages The International Manufacturing Technology Show (IMTS), which is the premier manufacturing technology event in North America.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="87" alt="CCAI logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-5.jpg" height="101" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">The Chemical Coaters Association International (CCAI)</a>is a technical and professional organization that provides information and training on surface coating technologies. CCAI works to raise the standards of finishing operations through educational meetings, seminars &amp; trade shows, training manuals, certification programs, and outreach programs with colleges and universities. CCAI has a network of local and regional chapters that assist in meeting our mission of serving as the industry’s educational and networking resource.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="233" alt="Coalition for America’s Gateways and Trade Corridors Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-6.jpg" height="75" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">Based in Washington, DC, the<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">Coalition for America’s Gateways and Trade Corridors</a>(CAGTC) was established to bring national attention to the need to significantly expand U.S. freight transportation capabilities and to work toward solutions for this growing national challenge. Our sole purpose is to raise public recognition and Congressional awareness of this need and to promote sufficient funding in federal legislation for trade corridors, gateways, intermodal connectors and freight facilities. CAGTC is comprised of over sixty representative organizations, including state DOTs, MPOs, ports, engineering firms, and freight corridors that have come together to improve national freight policy.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="142" alt="CMA Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-7.jpg" height="72" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><a style="color:#5aa9e1;font-weight:normal;">Credit Management Association</a></strong>is a non-profit trade Association formed in 1883 to help companies succeed by making better business decisions. We are the preeminent resource for export training and export financing guidance. CMA offers educational programs, networking, tools and resources to help companies (from small to large) grow internationally. CMA is ready to serve and fulfill your needs.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;"><img border="0" width="300" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-8.jpg" height="134" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><a style="color:#5aa9e1;font-weight:normal;">FCIB</a></strong>is the premiere association of executives in Finance, Credit and International Business. Since 1919, FCIB has met the needs of the international commercial credit and trade finance community, providing resources for global and political risk analysis. FCIB offers numerous educational and professional development opportunities to help professionals increase their skill sets, and maintains two of the industry’s most prestigious designations—the lifetime Certified International Credit Professional (CICP) and the International Certified Credit Executive (ICCE). The collective experience of more than 1,100 members and a history of success have enabled FCIB to be an industry leader.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="311" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-9.jpg" height="41" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><a style="color:#5aa9e1;font-weight:normal;">Global Ties U.S.</a></strong>is a nonprofit that makes international exchange programs more effective. We work with our members and the Department of State to bring current and future leaders from around the world to communities across the United States.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">Over 50 years, we have provided our members—from large, national organizations to smaller, community-based ones across 44 states and 13 countries—with connections, leadership development, and professional resources, so that they are the strongest, most effective organizations they can be. Together, we build deep connections among people from many countries, resulting in a more peaceful, prosperous world.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="166" alt="Indore Management Association Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-10.jpg" height="56" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">Indore Management Association</a>(IMA) is an association of entrepreneurs and professional managers and was formed in 1963. The association was registered in July 1990 under the provision of M.P. Non - Trading Corporation Act. 1962. IMA is affiliated to All India Management Association (AIMA) as one of its constituent bodies. The objective of IMA is (1) To provide a forum and facilities for the exchange of information and experience, (2) To promote development of sound management practices, (3) To promote, encourage and take part in survey and research studies in the management field, and (4) To cooperate and collaborate with other institutions having similar objectives.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="72" alt="IHEA logo  " src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-11.jpg" height="72" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The Industrial Heating Equipment Association (IHEA) represents the major segments of the industrial heat processing equipment industry to promote industrial furnace &amp; oven manufacturers and the accessories &amp; auxiliary equipment related to the process heating industry. The organization currently includes equipment used for the melting, refining and heat processing of ferrous and nonferrous metals and certain nonmetallic materials. Included in their member's product scope are: furnaces; ovens; dryers; heaters; heating equipment; infrared equipment; kilns; induction and dielectric apparatus; coke ovens; tanks for melting glass; salt bath or salt bath furnaces; oil, chemical and petro-chemical processing equipment; and industrial combustion equipment.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="119" alt="Logo of the Industrial Minerals Associan - North America" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-12.jpg" height="90" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">The Industrial Minerals Association - North America (IMA-NA)</a>is the representative voice of companies that extract and process a vital and beneficial group of raw materials known as industrial minerals.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">Industrial minerals are the ingredients for many of the products used in everyday life, and our companies and the people they employ are proud of their industry and the socially responsible methods they use to deliver these beneficial resources. IMA-NA represents ball clay, barite, bentonite, borates, calcium carbonate, diatomite, feldspar, industrial sand, kaolin, magnesia, mica, soda ash, talc, wollastonite and a variety of other industrial minerals.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="96" alt="International Franchise Association Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-13.jpg" height="86" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">International Franchise Association</a>is the world's oldest and largest organization representing franchising worldwide. IFA works through its government relations and public policy, media relations and educational programs to protect, enhance and promote franchising. Through its media awareness campaign IFA promotes the economic impact of the more than 825,000 franchise establishments, which support nearly 18 million jobs and $2.1 trillion of economic output for the U.S. economy. IFA members include franchise companies in over 300 different business format categories, individual franchisees and companies that support the industry in marketing, law and business development.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="129" alt="ISEA logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-14.jpg" height="60" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">ISEA, the International Safety Equipment Association</a>, is the association for manufacturers and suppliers of personal protective equipment and technologies that enable people to do work in hazardous environments. Its member companies are world leaders in the design, manufacture, testing and application of protective clothing and equipment used in factories, construction sites, hospitals and clinics, farms, schools, laboratories, emergency response and in the home. For more than 75 years, ISEA has set the standard for personal protective equipment and technologies, supporting its member companies in their mission of protecting the health and safety of working men and women around the world.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;"><img border="0" width="202" alt="Marine Technology Society logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-15.jpg" height="101" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">Marine Technology Society (MTS)</a><a name="P79_9554"></a>, founded in 1963, is a non-profit international community of ocean engineers, technologists, academicians, business leaders, and scientists all involved in the advancement of technologies that dovetail directly with the oceans; and especially in the areas of energy and environmental technologies. The mission of MTS is to facilitate a broader understanding of the relevance of marine technology to wider global issues by enhancing the dissemination of marine technology information. MTS also promotes and improves marine technology and related educational programs, and advances the development of the tools and procedures required to explore, study and further the responsible and sustainable use of the oceans.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="79" alt="NASCO Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-16.jpg" height="92" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">North American Strategy for Competitiveness</a>(NASCO), is a tri-national coalition of governments, businesses and educational institutions driven by a common interest in collaboration along key freight, energy and trade networks. Founded in 1994, NASCO encourages North America’s competitiveness in the global marketplace. At NASCO, we believe that the best strategy for North American competitiveness lies in freight logistics and operational efficiencies, innovative supply chain technologies, and skilled workforce training programs. We also believe that the only way to achieve results and success is from the grassroots level – the local, state and provincial governments partnering with industry expertise. Those public and private partnerships and connections across the continent are what NASCO does best.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="85" alt="Nexco Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-17.jpg" height="92" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">NEXCO</a>is a nonprofit association serving the international business community since 1963. NEXCO specializes in high quality affordable seminars that take the mystery out of trade. Its educational seminars, webinars, and networking events attract individuals and employees of companies involved in international trade. Online educational courses are available through podcasts. NEXCO’s Board of Directors is comprised of international business leaders from the New York City area. Its membership includes individual, corporate and sponsor level categories from importers, exporters and service-oriented companies engaged in global trade.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><span style="font-size:8pt;"></span><img border="0" width="90" alt="NAHAD logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-18.jpg" height="72" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">Association for Hose &amp; Accessories Distribution (NAHAD)</a>, is the international trade association dedicated to serving the needs of companies, worldwide, engaged in the distribution and manufacture of all types of hose and hose assemblies, tubing, couplings, fittings, clamps and related services and accessories serving all major markets, including: industrial, hydraulic, medical, bioprocess, food &amp; beverage, pharmaceutical, energy, automotive, aerospace, mining and marine applications.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">NAHAD members who also agree to fabricate hose assemblies in compliance with the NAHAD Hose Assembly Guidelines and who meet other qualification requirements may also become members of NAHAD's Hose Safety Institute,dedicated to hose safety, quality and reliability.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="141" alt="NAITA logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-19.jpg" height="54" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">North Alabama International Trade Association</a>(NAITA) is a business-driven organization with the mission to promote economic growth through international trade education, training, and networking. NAITA, a non-profit membership organization, provides an international networking forum, education on trade issues, and prepares businesses for global success. NAITA began in 1983 and has grown to become the regional resource for international trade development. NAITA is managed by the Madison County Commission International Trade Development Center—Your Partner in the Global Marketplace.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"></p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="80" alt="National Fliud Power Association (NFPA)" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-20.jpg" height="80" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">The National Fluid Power Association (NFPA)</a>, provides a forum for the fluid power industry's channel partners-manufacturers, suppliers, distributors, customers and educators. Its U.S. members work cooperatively to strengthen the industry and to advance hydraulic and pneumatic technology through the association's many programs and initiatives. A key element of that cooperation is the development of new business opportunities throughout the world. The U.S. Foreign and Commercial Service offers a wide range of program and information that can be very helpful to NFPA members in finding and pursuing new trade opportunities. The partnership with NFPA will help our members connect with specific trade specialists and take advantage of these services, and supports NFPA's strategic initiative to help members compete globally.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;"><img border="0" width="109" alt="National Marine Manufacturers Association Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-21.jpg" height="61" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">National Marine Manufacturers Association (NMMA)</a>is the nation's leading trade association representing recreational boat, marine engine and accessory manufacturers. Collectively, NMMA members manufacture an estimated 80 percent of marine products used in North America. NMMA is a unifying force and powerful voice for the recreational boating industry, working to strengthen and grow boating and protect the interests of its member companies. All that we do at NMMA, including consumer boat shows, marketing the Discover Boating program, providing export counsel and international trade opportunities, producing market research and statistics, and certifying marine products support our core objectives.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;"><img border="0" width="62" alt="Recreation Vehicle Industry Association logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-22.jpg" height="22" style="margin:5px;" /></a></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><strong><a style="color:#5aa9e1;font-weight:normal;">Recreation Vehicle Industry Association</a></strong><a name="P115_14657"></a>(RVIA) is the national trade association representing manufacturers and component suppliers producing 98% of all RVs manufactured in the United States. The group serves as the chief source for technical data, market research and production statistics. It also maintains an inspection process to audit manufacturer compliance with the NFPA 1192 RV Standard; represents the RV industry with federal and state governments and regulatory bodies; promotes RV ownership and travel to the public; and sponsors industry trade shows.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="141" alt="Receptive Services Association of America Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-23.jpg" height="90" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">Receptive Services Association of America</a>(RSAA) is the leading trade association focused on the development and promotion of the U.S. inbound travel industry. Founded in 1991, RSAA’s mission is to serve as the voice of the U.S. inbound travel industry, promote professional excellence, and create a collaborative atmosphere for all companies and entities involved in the U.S. inbound travel industry.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">RSAA is comprised of the nation’s leading receptive tour operators, suppliers and destinations and is dedicated to providing members with innovative and timely marketing, education, and networking opportunities in order to secure their portion of the important inbound travel market.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="76" alt="USCIB Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-24.jpg" height="76" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a href="http://www.export.gov/csassociations/eg_main_019692.asp" style="color:#5aa9e1;">United States Council for International Business</a>(USCIB)<a name="P126_15933"></a>promotes open markets, competitiveness and innovation, sustainable development and corporate social responsibility supported by international engagement and regulatory coherence. USCIB’s vision and strength are provided by an active membership of leading corporations and organizations, while our unique global network helps turn the vision into reality. USCIB also provides a range of valuable services to facilitate overseas trade, including the ATA Carnet, electronic certificates of origin (eCOs), and titles from its international bookstore, including Incoterms 2010®.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="132" alt="USIIC Logo" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-25.jpg" height="73" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a style="color:#5aa9e1;">U.S.-India Importers’ Council</a>(USIIC): The primary mission of USIIC is to advance President Obama’s National Export Initiative, and to support the efforts of Indian companies that import products from the United States. USIIC’s key role is to provide advice and guidance to Indian SME importers and first time importers as well as host regular activities, interactions, events and recognition for its members. The Council is led by Dr. V. Rangaraj and assisted by an Executive Committee, which comprises leading U.S. importers and service providers. The Executive Committee members collectively represent about 50 U.S. companies and facilitate U.S. exports worth approximately $110 million.</p><p class="image-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;background-color:#ffffff;"><img border="0" width="152" src="http://export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-26.jpg" height="76" alt="" style="margin:5px;" /></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The<a style="color:#5aa9e1;">U.S.-Saudi Arabian Business Council (USSABC)</a>is the premier U.S. organization that assists U.S. companies in identifying business partners in Saudi Arabia. The Business Council’s mission is to foster, develop, and expand the strategic business alliance between the U.S. and Saudi Arabia and contribute to the accurate depiction of the Saudi business environment.</p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"></p><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;">The USSABC has a membership base of 400 leading companies in the U.S. and Saudi Arabia, enjoys strong government support from both countries, and interacts regularly with senior government officials to promote issues of mutual interest to U.S. and Saudi firms.</p><br><p class="DefaultParagraph-1" style="font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;color:#000000;line-height:16px;margin-left:0pt;margin-top:11px;margin-bottom:11px;background-color:#ffffff;"><a name="P143_17837"></a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <topics/>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Expand</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <countries>
        <country>Algeria</country>
      </countries>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Christy Test Regression</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Christy Test Regression</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>test, regression</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/810.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-1.jpg" name="234560-1"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-2.jpg" name="234560-2"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-3.jpg" name="234560-3"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-4.jpg" name="234560-4"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-5.jpg" name="234560-5"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-6.jpg" name="234560-6"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-7.jpg" name="234560-7"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-8.jpg" name="234560-8"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-9.jpg" name="234560-9"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-10.jpg" name="234560-10"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-11.jpg" name="234560-11"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-12.jpg" name="234560-12"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-13.jpg" name="234560-13"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-14.jpg" name="234560-14"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-15.jpg" name="234560-15"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-16.jpg" name="234560-16"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-17.jpg" name="234560-17"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-18.jpg" name="234560-18"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-19.jpg" name="234560-19"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-20.jpg" name="234560-20"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-21.jpg" name="234560-21"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-22.jpg" name="234560-22"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-23.jpg" name="234560-23"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-24.jpg" name="234560-24"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-25.jpg" name="234560-25"/>
      <image src="http&amp;#58;//export.gov/build/groups/public/%40eg_main/documents/webcontent/~export/eg_main_051034~39~DCT_Center_Content_2col/234560-26.jpg" name="234560-26"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/810.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/810.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
