<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>814</id>
    <title>MidAtlantic District Export Council Member bios</title>
    <short_title>MidAtlantic DEC Member Bios </short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about the members of the MidAtlantic District Export Council.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/14/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h2>​​DEC Officers</h2><p><strong><br></strong></p><p><strong>Michael Ford</strong></p><p><strong></strong><b>Chair<br></b>Michael Ford is a career professional in international transportation, specializing in import/export documentation and regulatory compliance. He is responsible for BDP International's Regulatory Compliance unit.<br><br>Mr. Ford's activities include developing and administering the company's consulting arm in value-added product offerings such as Regulatory Compliance, Supply Chain Security, Duty Drawback, Insurance, Customer Education and Logistics Process Analysis/Management, and all topical governmental issues connected with the handling and administration of export and import cargo.<br><br>Mr. Ford's leadership in communication and system logic on governmental rules and regulations is central to BDP's ability to understand and resolve complex regulatory issues quickly, decisively and with minimal impact upon customers.</p><p><br>Mr. Ford has been associated with BDP for more than 34 years, Prior to his current role; he headed the company’s regional ocean export service division as Vice President. For the past 17 years, he has worked with and served as an advocate for some of the world’s leading companies, interacting with the U.S. Customs Service and the Department of Commerce/Census Bureau, in the development, piloting and automation of import and export programs. Among his other affiliations, Mr. Ford is the Co-chair for Trade on the Export Committee in the development of the new Customs ACE system and has served with Customs as a member of COAC (Commercial Operations Advisory Council), A Vice-chair of the Mid-Atlantic District Export Council, and chair the Partner sector with the American Chemistry Council, Responsible Care Committee. He also teaches an MBA international Logistics course at Saint Joseph’s University in Philadelphia.​</p><p><br></p><p><strong>Margaret McClellan Gatti</strong></p><p><strong>Vice Chair</strong></p><p>Margaret McClellan Gatti, Esquire is an international business lawyer engaged exclusively in the practice of Customs law, international trade law, international corporate law, international tax law and international transportation law. She founded her own law firm, Gatti &amp; Associates in 1992 and established the firm's office in Haddonfield, New Jersey.</p><p>Licensed to practice law in New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania and the District of Columbia, Ms. Gatti is also admitted to the Court of International Trade. She has a solid working knowledge of the German, Spanish and Russian languages and obtained the following degrees on the dates indicated: Saint Joseph's College (B.A., 1974); University of Pennsylvania (M.A., 1976); Temple University (M.B.A., 1982); Rutgers University School of Law- Camden (J.D., 1991).</p><p>Ms. Gatti has over 30 years of practical international business experience. In addition to engaging exclusively in the practice of international business law since 1992, she held the position of Senior Vice President in the International Banking Department of Mellon Bank (where she was employed from 1978 through 1988) and also founded and managed her own import \ export company. Ms. Gatti has managed several offshore business offices and has traveled overseas extensively.</p><p>She is the author of many published articles dealing with international trade and international tax, including articles in the Customs House Guide (1994-2006), the Official Export Guide (1994-2006), the North American Trade Guide (1994-1998), and the Journal Treasury Management Association (1997). Ms. Gatti is Chairperson of the Mid-Atlantic District Export Council, Presidential Advisor (former president) of the World Trade Association of Philadelphia, a Regional Coordinator of the Export Legal Assistance Network (ELAN) and a board member for and legal counsel to the NCITD. She additionally is a member of the Pennsylvania, New Jersey State, New York State and American Bar Associations; The District of Columbia Bar; and the Customs and International Trade Bar Association.</p><p>Ms. Gatti can be reached by telephone at 856-428-3104 or by e-mail at<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/mailto:mgatti@gattiassociates.com">mgatti@gattiassociates.com</a>. The office of Gatti &amp; Associates, Attorneys At Law is located at 44 Tanner Street in Haddonfield, NJ 08033. For additional information on Gatti &amp; Associates Attorneys At Law, please visit the firm's website at<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.gattiassociates.com">http://www.gattiassociates.com​</a>.​</p><p><br></p><p><strong>Mr. Joseph A. Zeccardi, Jr.</strong></p><p><strong>Treasurer</strong></p><p>International Banking Trade Specialist with over 35 years of Commercial Banking experience in the Pennsylvania/New Jersey/Delaware marketplaces. Presently responsible for marketing trade products. Past responsibilities as department head included the management and marketing of all aspects of the Issuance of Import, Export and Standby Letters of Credit, Document Examination and Processing, Paying and Receiving International Wire Transfers, Foreign Collections and Currency Trading.</p><p>Traveled to Europe and The Far East having responsibility of maintaining and promoting Foreign Bank Correspondent relationships. Has given numerous seminars for various Chambers of Commerce and local universities. Currently a member of The Philadelphia Rotary Club and serves as Treasurer for the Mid-Atlantic District Export Council (DEC).</p><p>A graduate of the Valley Forge Military College, he also attended the ABA School of International Banking, the Stonier Graduate School of Banking at Rutgers University and the Pennsylvania Bankers' School of Bucknell University.</p><p><br></p><h2>DEC Members​</h2><p><strong><br></strong></p><p><strong>Peter B. Alois</strong></p><p>Mr. Alois retired from the U.S.G. in 2005, creating an export consulting company to promote international business. During his career as a Foreign Service Officer with the U.S. Department of Commerce, he worked on four continents, helping thousands of American firms with targeted marketing, in-country advocacy and customized information. He created and led interagency business teams in American Embassies and Consulates around the world that united the U. S. Departments of Commerce, State, Defense, Treasury and Justice to support American companies, universities and non-profits.</p><p>His achievements as a diplomat were highly diverse; they included:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">persuading NASA to exhibit in its first international fair (in Germany in 1983),</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">launching a preregistration review of IPR data by the Government of Ecuador with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (1989),</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">creating one of Commerce's global industry teams (safety and security equipment, in 2002),</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">leading the first official trade mission of American companies into Iraq (2004), and</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">supporting American universities in recruiting foreign students in Ecuador, Italy, Singapore and Kuwait (1987 to 2005).</span><br></li></ul><p>Among his civilian awards, he received the Vice President's &quot;Golden Hammer for Reinventing Government&quot; and also the Director General's Award for Assistance to Minority Exporters. Peter was qualified in Spanish, German and Italian.</p><p>He served three years with the U.S. Army as a Thai Linguist. While in Vietnam in 1970, he worked in civil affairs in economic development and education, and was awarded the Bronze Star.</p><p>He has a BSFS in International Affairs from Georgetown University (1972), and an MBA in Applied Economics from George Washington University (1979).</p><p>In the Philadelphia region, Peter is active with the following:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Mid-Atlantic District Export Council – member</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Middle East Council of American Chambers of Commerce – U.S. Advisory Board member</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">World Trade Center Delaware - member</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Delaware County Chamber of Commerce - member</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">West Chester Area School District – member of B.E.S.T.</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">Global Philadelphia Association – Director of the Board</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">German-American Chamber of Commerce of Philadelphia – Director of the Board</span><br></li></ul><p>He is married, has three adult children, one daughter-in-law and a grandson.</p><p><br></p><p></p><p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Alfred N. Basilicato</strong></p><p>Alfred N. Basilicato, Founding Partner of<em>USA Strategic Ventures, LLC</em>is an entrepreneur, an international marketer, a manufacturer and an investor. This consulting firm was organized in late 2012 to pursue international business for US companies interested in expanding their reach worldwide. As Chairman and CEO, Numonics Corporation, Montgomeryville, PA for the last twenty years he was a purposeful world traveler crisscrossing the globe to develop a robust international business for Numonics. He is a pro-active, multi-disciplined person constantly developing new products and market entry strategies for innovative technology while exploring infrastructure improvements.</p><p>Basilicato led Numonics to double-digit international sales growth by participating in foreign exhibitions and trade missions sponsored by both the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and the Federal government. He exhibited at and attended trade missions around the world and accompanied former Pennsylvania Governor Tom Ridge on a high-tech focused trade mission to Singapore, Japan and Korea. Governor Ridge presented him with the&quot;Exporter of the Year Award&quot;for a Manufacturing firm in 2003. He was the recipient of the &quot;Presidential &quot;E&quot; Export Award&quot;in 2008 and was invited to meet President George W. Bush in the Oval Office as part of the ceremony.</p><p>He was honored twice by the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce. In 2003 he was honored as&quot;The Manufacturer of the Year&quot;and in 2007 as the&quot;Small Business Person of the Year&quot;recognizing his achievements, vitality, creativity, stability and impact on our small business community. The Ben Franklin Technology Partnership recognized his leadership in awarding his company the &quot;Technology Innovation Award&quot;; and, under his leadership they bestowed (3) three technology grants to his company over a ten year period.</p><p>Basilicato is an active member of the District Export Council (DEC) and the World Trade Center of Greater Philadelphia (WTCGP) and he currently serves as on the following Advisory Boards:</p><ul><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">To the Dean of The Information Sciences School (I School) of Drexel University</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">The President of the World Trade Center</span><br></li><li><span style="line-height:1.6;">The President of the Mid Atlantic Employers Association (MEA)</span><br></li></ul><p>He was recently appointed to the Australian Commercialization Expert Network member to assist Australian companies develop a market entry strategy for the USA.</p><p>He was an active member of the Small Business Board of the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce, a member of the Technology Council of Eastern Pennsylvania and the Team Pennsylvania Foundation. He is a past board member of the Mid-Atlantic Employers Association (MEA), has acted as an advisor to the Wharton Export Network and has served as a board member for the Product Development Management Association (PDMA) of Philadelphia.</p><p><br></p><p><strong>Jeff Briggs</strong></p><p>Duringhis27 years with UPS, Jeff Briggs hasheld various positions in operations, human resources, and sales. In hiscurrent assignment as Regional Sales Coordinator for the United States East Region of UPS, Jeff and his team assist companies along the East Coast in developing and executing their Global Supply Chain strategy. His team is responsible for maintaining and growing UPS international revenues at the businesses that are located in 26 states within the UPS - US East Region.</p><p>A graduate from Rutgers University School of Business, Jeff has continued his education by participating in certificate programs in Logistics and Supply Chain Management at Penn State University. Jeff is currently a member of the Mid Atlantic District Export Council and serves on the World Trade Center of Greater Philadelphia advisory council.</p><p><br></p><p><strong>Kimberly A. Cahill</strong></p><p style="text-align:justify;">Kim joined Villanova School of Business (VSB)in January 2012 to accept a new position as director of the Center for Global Leadership. The Center promotes three core ideals: cross-cultural awareness, ethical international business relationships, and responsible global leadership. Her role is to execute, direct, organize, and support the development of CGL initiatives including academic programs, events, relationship management, public relations, fund-raising, grant development, fiscal management, and communications involving a varied set of cross-college and external stakeholders.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Prior to joining Villanova, Kim served as the Director for the Institute of Global Management Studies and Temple CIBER (Center for International Business Education and Research) and as Managing Editor of the<em>Journal of International Management</em>at the Fox School of Business, Temple University.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Kim has been in the field of international education for nearly 20 years and has secured and managed nearly $5 million in grant awards. In 2010, she was appointed to the MidAtlantic District Export Council by U.S. Secretary of Commerce Gary Locke for a four year term. She was recognized as a VIP and Top Female Professional by the Cambridge Who's Who Registry of Executives and is the 2008 recipient of the Musser Award for Excellence in Leadership at the Fox School of Business.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">While at Temple, she oversaw the nationally ranked (Top 10) undergraduate International Business major, IB research initiatives and outreach activities, while also serving as the Managing Editor for the<em>Journal of International Management</em>, an emerging quarterly IB journal. She managed, developed, and advised study abroad opportunities and international internships for business students and administered the Certificates of Specialization combining area studies, IB, and language, for business and liberal arts students. Under her leadership, study abroad by business students increased 1,000 percent.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Kim also served as the Office Manager and International Programs Coordinator for the Organizational Dynamics Program at the University of Pennsylvania. She managed Penn faculty, on-site academic advisors, and program coordinators associated with a series of international programs located in Europe, Latin America and Asia. She designed and implemented program-specific intercultural and sensitivity training, curriculum development and pedagogy. Prior to that, Kim was Assistant Director of inlingua, a full service international training center offering language instruction, translation, interpreting, and intercultural services. She has taught English as a Second Language and has several years experience in global sales. She has studied, lived, and traveled in more than 30 countries across five continents, is proficient in French, and aspires to improve her basic Spanish language skills.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Kim was a founding board member and Vice President of Domestic Violence HELP, a non-profit organization whose mission is to reduce the incidence of domestic violence through Healthcare consultation, Education, Legal systems advocacy and by Promoting awareness, with an emphasis on the healthcare response to domestic violence.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Kim earned an MS in International Business and Culture from the University of Pennsylvania and a BA in International Relations from Bucknell University. As an undergraduate, she spent a semester abroad at Université Francois Rabelais, Tours, France.</p><p style="text-align:justify;"><strong style="color:#000000;font-family:verdana;font-size:12px;line-height:16px;text-align:center;"><br></strong></p><p><strong>James W.K. Chan, Ph.D</strong><strong>.​</strong></p><p>James Chan is President of<a>Asia Marketing and Management</a><a name="P3_91"></a>(AMM), a Philadelphia-basedconsultancy that has enabled more than 100 American firms to expand in Asia.</p><p>He has worked with many industrial manufacturers, technology firms, and trade associations including Westinghouse Electric Company, Kingsbury, Kodak, 3 Com, Nationwide Insurance, Monitor Aerospace, Glenayre, Vulcan Spring Mfg. Co., Lucent Technologies, American Management Association (AMA), Metal Powder Industries Federation (MPIF), Robotic Industries Association (RIA), ISI of Thomson Reuters, and ASTM. He is a frequent keynote speaker on international marketing strategy and Asian business practices.</p><p>In 1996, the American Management Association (AMA) commissioned Dr. Chan to create its first three-day course for Fortune 1000 companies, “Business Skills for the China Market.” Dr. Chan teaches a special course on China for the Global Biomedical Service program of the University of Pennsylvania. He also teaches a new course, “Global Exporting: Asia Focus” at the Villanova School of Business. He is a member of the Mid-Atlantic District Export Council of the U.S. Department of Commerce.</p><p>James Chan founded his practice in 1983 after he had served as the China Area Manager and International Promotion Manager of Academic Press, a subsidiary of HBJ, a Fortune 500 company in New York.</p><p>An experienced, animated public speaker in three languages—English, Mandarin Chinese, and Cantonese—James Chan is the author of the 60-minute DVD “<a>Secrets of Business Success in China</a><a name="P11_1587"></a>” published by Malvern Press.</p><p>Born Wah-Kong Chan ( 陈华江) in Guangzhou (Canton), China in 1949, James grew up in Hong Kong and received his B.A. from the University of Hong Kong in 1970. He came to America in 1971 and received his M.A. from the University of Chicago and his Ph.D. in 1977 from the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor in geography. A naturalized U.S. citizen since 1987, James Chan lives and works in Philadelphia.</p><p>Karen E. Klein of Bloomberg BusinessWeek interviewed him in 2011 in an article titled “<a>How to Sell to China Now</a><a name="P15_2135"></a>.” Mike Cote of The Union Leader interviewed him in 2012 in a news piece titled “<a>Made in USA sounds good to China</a><a name="P15_2252"></a>.” To view his detailed profile, go to<a>http://www.AsiaMarketingManagement.com</a><a name="P15_2331"></a>.</p><p>​<br></p><p><strong>Matt Glenn​</strong></p><p><span style="line-height:1.6;">Prior to joining AGI in 2004, Matt was a business analyst and product manager for​</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">Honeywell Aerospace near Seattle. In that role, he led proposal efforts and​</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">negotiated with avionics departments of major international airlines and aircraft</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">manufacturers. Earlier in his 20-year career in the aerospace community, he</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">worked for Rockwell as a Space Shuttle flight design engineer, and also as a​ Guidance &amp; Procedures Officer in mission control at the Johnson Space Center in Houston.</span><br></p>Matt has an M.B.A. from the University of Michigan (with internship at the Central Aerohydrodynamics Institute, TsAGI inZhukovsky, Russia) and a B.S. inaerospace​<span style="line-height:1.6;">e</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">n</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">gineering from St. Louis University.</span><p></p>Due to his father’s foreign assignments with a U.S. company, as a boy Matt lived 4 years in India and 5 years in Germany. While there, he learned soccer, and later played as team captain at the<span style="line-height:1.6;">high school and college level back in theU</span><span style="line-height:1.6;">.S., and he is still active in the sport.</span><br>Matt has been involved in a broad range of community activities, including: As a volunteer to the U.S. Forest Service ranger station of North Bend, Washington; as a supporting member of the Cascade Gateway Foundation, which lawfullychallenged a gravel mining operation in Washington state; and as a youth soccer coach in Houston.<br><br><p><strong>Elliot Levin</strong></p><p style="text-align:justify;">Elliot is Pathfinder's Senior Vice President responsible for all financial activities throughout the company, which include treasury, tax, invoicing, insurance, benefits, payroll, information technology and other related areas. Elliot is a Certified Public Accountant licensed in New Jersey and Pennsylvania. He has a B.A. degree from Rutgers University, NJ and holds an M.B.A. degree from Philadelphia University, PA. Prior to Pathfinder, Elliot was Vice President for an international family owned manufacturing and distribution business. Elliot started his career with the Philadelphia office of PricewaterhouseCoopers, an international accounting, tax and consulting firm. Past business responsibilities have included European acquisitions, establishment of a Representative Sales Office in China, raw material procurement from the Far East and ISO Certification. Elliot has traveled throughout China and the Far East. Elliot's former employer had won the Pennsylvania Governor's Special Regional Award for Export Excellence and Elliot has been a speaker on Doing Business in China and was the sole US business representative on a US Government web cast on China.</p><p style="text-align:justify;">Elliot is a member of the Pennsylvania and American Institutes of CPAs. He is a member of the U.S. Department of Commerce Mid-Atlantic District Export Council and was appointed to the U.S. Government Industry Trade Advisory Committee which advises the Department of Commerce and the U.S. Trade Representative Office on export issues.</p><br><p><strong>Dominic V. O'Brien</strong>​</p><p>As Senior Marketing Representative for the Philadelphia Regional Port Authority, Dominic O'Brien sells the Port's services to shippers, steamship lines, and other supply chain professionals.</p><p>He is a frequent lecturer on port and transportation issues, speaking to trade groups, university classes, and civic associations throughout the Delaware Valley.</p><p>He is President of the World Trade Association of Philadelphia and a Board Member of the District Export Council – Mid-Atlantic.</p><p>A graduate of LaSalle University, Mr. O'Brien lives with his wife and daughter in the Wissahickon neighborhood of Philadelphia, where he enjoys yelling at the television during Eagles games.</p><br><br><p><strong>Myriam Siftar</strong></p><p>When Myriam Siftar founded MTM LinguaSoft in 2003 her goal for the company wasto become the mid-sized language services provider known for client satisfaction andinformation technologysavvy.Since its founding, MTM LinguaSoft has met those goals, winning clients and kudos for high quality translation and no-hassle project management.</p><p>Today, MTM LinguaSoft provides translation and localization services for a wide range of companies that do business with international markets or in multilingual environments and is recognized as a specialist in the translation and globalization of websites, software and online applications, such as e-learning modules. This work made MTM the subject of a feature article in<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.export.gov/pennsylvania/philadelphia/midatlanticdec/listofdecmembers/philadelphia.bizjournals.com/philadelphia/stories/2008/06/02/smallb1.html"><em>Philadelphia Business Journal</em></a>). In 2010 and 2011, MTM was recognized as one of the &quot;<a href="http://www.philadelphia100.com/">Philadelphia 100</a>&quot; – the 100 fastest growing companies in the Philadelphia region as determined in a merit-based competition.</p><p>In building the company, Myriam Siftar drew from her own cross cultural experiences as an information technology consultant with an international background. For 15 years she was a successful project manager who implemented several ERP systems and e-commerce systems for both Fortune 500 and startup companies within the US, Europe and Latin America. As a result of this experience, she has developed an awareness of and a methodology for addressing cultural issues that arise in global business settings. She is used to working with clients to understand business requirements and deliver solutions.</p><p>After completing the equivalent of an M.S. in Computer Science at a leading French engineering school, Myriam went on to receive a Masters from the European School of Management in Paris (formerly, Ecole Superieure de Commerce de Paris) and an M.B.A. from Drexel University.</p><p>In addition to heading MTM LinguaSoft, Myriam has presented seminars on website globalization and multicultural communication for a number of groups including the World Trade Centers of Greater Philadelphia, Central Pennsylvania and Delaware, and the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce. She has also been a regular speaker at events organized by the Department of Commerce in Pennsylvania and New Jersey, including<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.nist.gov/mep/exportech.cfm">ExporTech</a>courses and the <a href="http://events.r20.constantcontact.com/register/event?oeidk=a07e5w9uafy469a4a2e&amp;llr=xnvwtbjab">Discover 2012 International Business Conference</a>. She is active in various other business and professional organizations. As a result of her activities and experience, she has been appointed by the U.S. Secretary of Commerce to a four-year term on the Mid-Atlantic District Export Council.</p><p>Myriam's articles have been published in<em><a href="http://www.multilingual.com/articleDetail.php?id=1479">Multilingual</a></em>,<em><a href="http://www.bizjournals.com/philadelphia/blog/guest-comment/2013/04/cultural-awareness-training-a-new.html">Philadelphia Business Journal</a></em>, and<em>Intercom</em>. She has been interviewed by<em><a href="http://viewer.zmags.com/publication/53f7a96d?page=14">SmartCEO Magazine</a></em>,<em><a href="http://www.bizjournals.com/philadelphia/stories/2006/02/13/smallb4.html?hbx=e_sw">Philadelphia Business Journal</a></em>, and<a href="http://executiveleadersradio.com/shows/executive-leaders-pa/04-05-2013.aspx">Executive Leaders Radio</a>.</p><p>In 2011, Myriam was chosen to attend the<a href="http://www.wbenc.org/Opportunities/Tuck-WBENC-Executive-Program/">Tuck-WBENC Executive Exchange Program​</a>at the IBM Executive Palisades Conference Center in Palisades, NY. The intensive executive leadership program is designed for experienced women business owners, and offers them the latest strategies and executive leadership &quot;best practices&quot; from some of the most notable thought leaders in the field of executive education who are on the faculty at Tuck, Dartmouth's business school. Participants in this program are selected from scores of applicants nationwide.</p><p>Myriam lives in University City with her husband and two daughters. In her spare time, Myriam practices yoga and experiments with her cooking group.​</p><br><p><strong>Fred P. Slack​</strong></p><p>Fred joined Schramm in January 2010 after more than 25 years of experience in industrial sales, business development and licensed manufacturing to the Western Hemisphere, Europe, Asia and the Middle East. Prior to joining the company, he was Vice President of International Sales at Dayton Superior Corporation, responsible for global business development across multiple operating divisions that focused on concrete construction materials and equipment used in heavy civil and commercial construction. With field experience in more than 70 countries to date, Fred is familiar with complex channel issues relating to independent distribution, OEM and strategic account development. He has managed culturally diverse sales, manufacturing and PE level engineering resources across multiple divisions within the USA and offshore. He is also a former Foreign Affairs Officer with the U.S. State Department. He holds a B.A. from Northwestern University in Political Science/International Relations and an M.B.A. in Industrial Economics from University of Illinois in Chicago.<br></p><p><br></p><p><strong>Blair Woodring</strong></p><p>Blair Woodring has 20+ years in progressive plant and sales management experience, primarily in steel conversion and end use development. The majority of histime has been in Power Generation, subsea oil production/transmission, and defense markets. Resultant roles in Business Development and manufacturing expansion to Custom Alloy, a specialty forging operation focusing in the previously stated markets. He has aBA in International Business from Ohio Wesleyan and anMBA inOperations Management fromLoyola University of Chicago.</p><p><br></p><p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Thomas Zieser</strong></p><p><strong>Experience​</strong></p><p>President and CEO, JACE System</p><p>Specialty orthopedic rehabilitation equipment manufacturer and health services provider. Our products are used to assist patients in their post operative rehabilitation following surgery to the knee. . Our products are sold in the USA, Europe, Japan and Mexico. I prepared the company's flagship product, the K-100-A knee CPM device for export sales by completing regulatory requirements to obtain ISO 9001 and ISO 13485 Registrations, CE Mark Registration and Certifying Body (CB) Registration</p><p>Participant in Trade Winds Eastern Europe Warsaw, Poland April 2008</p><p>Participant in Trade Winds The Americas, Sao Paolo, Brazil 2009</p><p>Participant in Trade Winds Central America, Mexico City, Mexico 2010</p><p>Participant in Trade Mission to Mexico with Under Secretary Francisco Sanchez 2012</p><p>Scheduled Trade Mission Participant to Colombia, September 9-12, 2013</p><p>Member Mid Atlantic District Export Council (DEC) 2008 to present</p><p>Member Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Chemicals, Pharmaceuticals, and Health/Science Products &amp; Services (ITAC 3) 2010 to present</p><p><strong>Education</strong></p><p>Northland College, Ashland WI, BS, Biology, 1970</p><p>Seton Hall University, South Orange, NJ M.B.A., 1976</p><p><strong>Publications / Professional Activities</strong></p><p>Testimony before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform Subcommittee on Government Organization, Efficiency and Financial Management September 12, 2012</p><p>Presenter to the NE/MW Congressional Manufacturing Coalition on the Trade Act Assistance for Firms (TAAFF) and the Mid Atlantic Trade Act Assistance Center (MATAAC)</p><p>Presenter at WTC of Greater Philadelphia's Advancing Technology Seminar on March 22, 2012</p><p><br></p><p><br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>MidAtlantic District Export Council Member bios</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about the members of the MidAtlantic District Export Council.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, assistance, MidAtlantic, council, members, biographies</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/814.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/814.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/814.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
