<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>816</id>
    <title>Our Partners - Education</title>
    <short_title>Our Partners - Education</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about Education/Research Centers you can partner with.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/15/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/15/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets<source_office>U.S. Commerical Service</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1>Strategic Partners</h1><p>The use of logos does not connote endorsement by the Department of Commerce of the organizations' views, products, or services.</p><h2>Education/Research Centers</h2><p><span><h1><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/American%20International%20Recruitment%20Council.jpg" alt="AIRC Logo" style="margin:5px;" /></h1></span></p><p>​The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://airc-education.org"> American International Recruitment Council </a>(AIRC) is a 501(c)(3) non-profit membership association of accredited U.S. post-secondary institutions, pathway programs and student recruitment agencies which work together to establish quality standards for international student placement within the United States. AIRC Certification for recruitment agencies is a peer reviewed and rigorous methodology based on global best practice which is utilized by U.S. institutions within their international recruitment partnering strategies. AIRC is registered as a Standards Development Organization with the U.S. Department of Justice.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Birmingham%20International%20Center.jpg" alt="BIC Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://bic-al.org"> Birmingham International Center</a> (BIC) is the nation's oldest cultural-education organization. Founded in 1951, the BIC has grown into a resource for international business-education needs, including intercultural training. The BIC operates as a liaison to international businesses and cultural interests. They are connected to global opportunity, leadership and social competency. Since 1992, the BIC has presented workshops and seminars on how to do business with over 20 different countries. These programs continue to provide learning and networking environments that assist in global business development.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/MSU%20Franklin%20Furniture%20Institute.jpg" alt="MSU Franklin Furniture Institute Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The mission of the <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ffi.msstate.edu">MSU Franklin Furniture Institute</a> is to help sustain and increase the competitiveness of the home furnishings industry in Mississippi and the region. FFI's objectives are to become a national resource center for furniture-related issues; to enhance sustainable manufacturing and design in furniture; to expand furniture-related curriculum to appeal to students interested in pursuing advanced degrees; to provide testing capabilities in furniture components, frames, fabric, flammability, and packaging and develop bariatric furniture test standards; to educate and train workers, supervisors and management to improve skills, efficiencies and technical knowledge; and to partner with state and federal resources to provide export resources to increase international trade opportunities for the industry.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Georgia%20Tech%20Center%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research.jpg" alt="GT CIBER Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ciber.gatech.edu"> Georgia Tech Center for International Business Education and Research (GT CIBER)</a> works to increase and promote Georgia's capacity for international business understanding and competitiveness. As part of the nation-wide CIBER network, the GT CIBER links the manpower and technological needs of the Georgia business community with the international education, language training, and research capacities of universities across the country and with companies around the world. With a global presence in diverse fields and partnerships reaching into multiple sectors of industry around the world, GT CIBER stands at the leading edge of global connectivity and technology.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/GlobalPittsburgh.jpg" alt="GlobalPittsburgh Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.globalpittsburgh.org">GlobalPittsburgh</a> boosts international connections in the Pittsburgh Region and around the world through member activities and hosting programs. - Activities and Events for Globally-Minded Members - Hosting International Leaders for the U.S State Department - Attracting International Students to the Region - Connecting Corporations with International Resources </p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Goldman%20Sachs%20Foundation.jpg" alt="Goldman Sachs Foundation Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.slcc10ksb.com">Goldman Sachs Foundation</a>, in partnership with the Initiative for a Competitive Inner City and Babson College, created the <em>10,000 Small Businesses </em>program through a $500 million dollar investment in small business infrastructure and growth. The initiative is designed to provide a unique approach to support established businesses that need resources to grow. These resources include world class business education/ training, one/one mentoring and counseling, and access to capital. Salt Lake Community College is one of eleven sites named for delivery of the national program and has completed training for 135 small business owners in Utah. Aggregate results of the program include: creation of 197 net new jobs; average company revenues increasing between 4-6%; and over 8 million dollars of capital funding achieved by companies graduating from this program.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Frank%20G.%20Zarb%20School%20of%20Business%20at%20Hofstra%20University.jpg" alt="Frank G. Zarb School of Business at Hofstra University Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>&quot;The mission of the <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.hofstra.edu/Academics/Colleges/Zarb/index.html">Frank G. Zarb School of Business at Hofstra University</a> is &quot;Educating for Personal and Professional Achievement.&quot; Located just 25 miles from New York City, Zarb is among only 10 percent of business schools to earn accreditation in both business and accounting from AACSB International. The Martin B. Greenberg Trading Room is among the most technologically advanced academic facilities in the nation. Community partnership projects, executive speaker series, experiential learning opportunities are offered to enhance leadership skills. Our network of successful alumni consistently provide connections leading to prestigious internships and full-time positions.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/ICEF.jpg" alt="ICEF Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.icef.com">ICEF</a> connects educators, education agents, work and travel professionals, and industry service providers to key markets worldwide, supporting the growth of international education and global student mobility. Through ICEF's various services, education institutions and agents achieve real results in growing international student enrolments. <br><br>ICEF is best known for its Workshops. Occurring across ten locations annually and covering every international student market, ICEF Workshops bring together international educators and carefully screened, high-quality student recruitment agents at networking forums. ICEF Workshops are renowned for their organization and sophistication - and most importantly, for the quality of educator/agent relationships they facilitate.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/International%20Student%20Network.jpg" alt="ISN Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.isnexpo.com">International Student Network</a> (ISN) introduces admissions teams from U.S. undergraduate, graduate, and language programs to the finest international applicants in the world. ISN organizes their award-winning events – from boutique fairs to sprawling American education expos – with the goal of providing the most thorough recruitment experiences possible. Each recruitment endeavor is tailored to meet the needs of every admissions counselor present to ensure that each institution represented has a substantial pool of applicants in each market. Since its establishment in 1995, ISN has achieved excellence in international student recruitment. ISN's strategy emphasizes the importance of the old-fashioned, face-to-face connection between admissions teams and prospective students.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/New%20York%20Public%20Library%27s%20Business%20Center.jpg" alt="SIBL Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.nypl.org/locations/tid/65/about">New York Public Library's Business Center (SIBL)</a> offers all in the local and international business community free information resources in economics, finance, competitive intelligence, domestic and foreign market and industry research, logistics, intellectual property, small business start-up, and career exploration. Supplementing print volumes for consultation and borrowing are specialized online databases such as Emerging Markets and Panjiva. Experienced reference librarians and business advisors from partners such as SCORE guide patrons through the research process, on a walk-in or appointment basis. SIBL hosts workshops by expert practitioners and hands-on training in e-resources such as the New York Small Business Resource Center (smallbiz.nypl.org). Amenities include free meeting rooms and wi-fi.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Study%20in%20the%20USA.jpg" alt="Study in the USA Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.studyusa.com">Study in the USA</a> is the first print publication and website promoting United States higher education programs to prospective international students. Study in the USA's mission is to connect international students with reputable programs at colleges and universities across the United States in addition to providing access to a wealth of information and resources. In addition to publishing ten regional magazines with over 300,000 copies annually distributed around the world, Study in the USA has an award-winning website that contains hundreds of information profiles featuring high quality American programs in fourteen languages. Over the last 35 years, Study in the USA and StudyUSA.com has helped millions of foreign students attend programs at United States schools, colleges, and universities.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Centers%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research.jpg" alt="CIBERs Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.fox.temple.edu/cms_research/institutes-and-centers/center-for-international-business-education-and-research/welcome/home">Centers for International Business Education and Research</a> (CIBERs) were created under the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 to increase and promote the nation's capacity for international understanding and economic enterprise. Administered by the U.S. Department of Education, CIBERs link the manpower and information needs of U.S. business with the international education, language training, and research capacities of universities across the U.S. 33 universities, including Temple University, were designated as centers that serve as regional and national resources to businesses, students, and academics focused on improving American competitiveness and providing comprehensive service and programs for U.S. business success in global markets.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/U.S.%20Journal%20of%20Academics.jpg" alt="U.S. Journal of Academics Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.usjournal.com"> U.S. Journal of Academics</a> and its family of sites promote the United States as the world's premier education destination, by representing an exclusive list of U.S. colleges, universities and English Language Programs. USjournal launched its online presence in 1996, and has evolved into a family of 16 independent, multi-lingual domains. One of its newest sister sites, FundsV, helps improve campuses' conversions of initial student inquiries to financially-qualified applicants by improving the efficiency and integrity of the funds verification component within the international admissions cycle. Contact us to learn more!<br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Services</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnership Program</trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnerships</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Our Partners - Education</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about Education/Research Centers you can partner with.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>stratgic partnership program, strategic partners, commercial service, education, research centers</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/816.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/American%20International%20Recruitment%20Council.jpg" name="American%20International%20Recruitment%20Council"/>
      <image src="/Files/Birmingham%20International%20Center.jpg" name="Birmingham%20International%20Center"/>
      <image src="/Files/MSU%20Franklin%20Furniture%20Institute.jpg" name="MSU%20Franklin%20Furniture%20Institute"/>
      <image src="/Files/Georgia%20Tech%20Center%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research.jpg" name="Georgia%20Tech%20Center%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research"/>
      <image src="/Files/GlobalPittsburgh.jpg" name="GlobalPittsburgh"/>
      <image src="/Files/Goldman%20Sachs%20Foundation.jpg" name="Goldman%20Sachs%20Foundation"/>
      <image src="/Files/Frank%20G.%20Zarb%20School%20of%20Business%20at%20Hofstra%20University.jpg" name="Frank%20G"/>
      <image src="/Files/ICEF.jpg" name="ICEF"/>
      <image src="/Files/International%20Student%20Network.jpg" name="International%20Student%20Network"/>
      <image src="/Files/New%20York%20Public%20Library%27s%20Business%20Center.jpg" name="New%20York%20Public%20Library%27s%20Business%20Center"/>
      <image src="/Files/Study%20in%20the%20USA.jpg" name="Study%20in%20the%20USA"/>
      <image src="/Files/Centers%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research.jpg" name="Centers%20for%20International%20Business%20Education%20and%20Research"/>
      <image src="/Files/U.S.%20Journal%20of%20Academics.jpg" name="U"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/816.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/816.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
