<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>829</id>
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions - Asian Development Bank</title>
    <short_title>FAQs - ADB</short_title>
    <summary>Learn answers to frequently asked questions about Asian Development Bank's activities, funding, membership, and other topics of interest.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/17/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/20/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets - Asia</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​</p><h2>ADB Activities</h2><ul><li><p>What is the Asian Development Bank?The Asian Development Bank (ADB) is a multilateral development financing institution dedicated to reduce poverty in Asia and the Pacific. ADB aims to improve the quality of people's lives by providing loans and technical assistance for various development activities.<br></p></li><li><p>How is the ADB different from commercial banks?ADB engages in mostly public sector lending for development purposes in its<a href="http://www.adb.org/countries/main">developing member countries</a>. ADB's clients are its member governments, who are also its<a href="http://www.adb.org/about/members">shareholders</a>.<br></p></li><li><p>Can an individual borrow from the ADB?No. ADB lends to governments for development projects. It has no individual clients.<br></p></li><li><p>​Why is the ADB in Manila?On 30 November 1965, delegates of the United Nation's Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East voted Manila to host the ADB headquarters.<br></p></li><li><p>Does the ADB have offices in other countries?Yes. While the ADB headquarters is in Manila, the Bank also has resident offices in many of its borrowing countries, as well as representative offices in<a href="http://www.adb.org/offices/europe/main">Frankfurt</a>,<a href="http://www.adb.org/offices/japan/main">Tokyo</a>, and<a href="http://www.adb.org/offices/north-america/main">Washington, DC</a>.</p></li><li><p>Does the ADB work with NGOs?Yes. The ADB encourages cooperation with nongovernment organizations. The Bank integrates NGO knowledge and expertise into its activities to better serve the priorities and needs of the people of the region.<a href="http://www.adb.org/site/ngos/main">Visit ADB's NGO center​</a>.</p></li></ul><h2>ADB Membership and Staffing</h2><ul><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">How many member countries own ADB?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">Members now number 67 compared with 31 in 1966. View a <a href="http://www.adb.org/about/members">completelist of members</a>and their joining dates.</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Where do ADB staff come from?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">ADB staff come from around 50 member countries. Over half are Filipino, but the Bank's culture is international.</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Is the President of the ADB always Japanese?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">By tradition, the President is Japanese. The<a href="http://www.adb.org/documents/agreement-establishing-asian-development-bank-adb-charter">charter</a>states that the President must be from a regional member country.</span><br></li></ul><h2>Funding and Lending</h2><ul><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Where does the ADB get its funding?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">ADB raises funds through bond issues in the world's capital markets. The Bank relies on its members' contributions, retained ​earnings from lending operations, and loan repayment.</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">What is technical assistance (TA)?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">TA is a vital service used to assist countries to identify and design projects, improve institutions, formulate development strategies or foster regional cooperation. TA can be financed by grants, and from loans through ADB's central budget, or from a number of special funds provided by ADB's donor members.</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Does the ADB only offer assistance to governments of developing member countries?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">No. Although most lending is in the public sector, and to governments, ADB's Private Sector Department also provides direct assistance to private enterprises of DMCs through equity investments, loans and guarantee products.</span><br></li></ul><h2>Opportunities</h2><ul><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Does the ADB offer opportunities for consultants and contractors?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">Yes. ADB hires individual consultants and consulting firms for a wide range of assignments. They provide expert advice on projects, policies and many other development matters. ADB also yield opportunities for contractors.</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">How do I get a job at the ADB?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">First, review the professional staff and local staff vacancies, and read about working at ADB. This website regularly posts updated professional and local staff vacancies (</span><a href="http://export.gov/adb/adbgeneratedbusinessopportunities/adbemploymentopportunities/index.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">Job Opportunities</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">).</span><br></li><li><em style="line-height:1.6;">Does the ADB offer an internship program?</em><span style="line-height:1.6;">Yes. ADB internships are available to eligible students of ADB member countries. ADB selects interns on a highly competitive basis. The assignments are from eight (8) weeks to 26 weeks (six [6] months).​</span><br></li></ul><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
        <topic>Trade Promotion</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions>
        <geo_region>Asia</geo_region>
      </geo_regions>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Frequently Asked Questions - Asian Development Bank</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn answers to frequently asked questions about Asian Development Bank's activities, funding, membership, and other topics of interest.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Asian Development Bank, membership, staffing, activities, lending, funding</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/829.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/829.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/829.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
