<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>835</id>
    <title>Our Partners - Legal</title>
    <short_title>Our Partners - Legal</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about Legal and Regulatory Advice/Due Diligence businesses that you can partner with.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/18/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets<source_office>U.S. Commerical Service</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Strategic Partners</strong></h1><p>The use of logos does not connote endorsement by the Department of Commerce of the organizations' views, products, or services.</p><h2>Legal and Regulatory Advice/Due Diligence</h2><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Baker%20and%20McKenzie.jpg" alt="Baker &amp; McKenzie Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.bakernet.com">Baker &amp; McKenzie</a> has a global network of 3,600 attorneys, located in 70 locations throughout 38 countries. It provides expertise in international trade regulation and corporate compliance for most commercially significant countries in the world, including: customs laws and trade regulation, export controls and anti-boycott regulations, and antidumping and countervailing duty law.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Global%20Business%20Information%20Services%20Inc.jpg" alt="GloBIS Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.glo-bis.com">Global Business Information Services, Inc. </a>(GloBIS) provides credit reports on any company, any size, anywhere in the world. GloBIS conducts Background Investigations on individuals globally, Company Site Visits, Reference Checking, highly customized Market Research, compiles Database Lists of Companies &amp; Individuals, and Import/Export Customs Records, etc. </p><p>GloBIS has been a US Commercial Service's International Company Profile (ICP) provider in China since 2004, in Iraq since 2011, and can do this type of report on companies everywhere. GloBIS reports are accepted by the US Export Import Bank.</p><p>Performing due diligence on your international business partners is integral to your export compliance.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/TUV%20Rheinland.jpg" alt="TUV Rheinland Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.tuv.com">TUV Rheinland</a> assists U.S companies in penetrating markets outside the United States through knowledge of how to navigate the compliance and regulatory requirements for each country they wish to export to in addition to specific product testing and certification laws within different geographical areas. In order to get their products into foreign markets most quickly and efficiently, Department of Commerce clients need to be kept up to date with the latest standard and certification rules so as to not preclude their products from crossing borders or receiving monetary sanctions. TUV has a proven track record of helping manufacturers sell all over the world on a daily basis.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/UL.jpg" alt="UL Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.ul.com/global/eng/pages">UL</a> is a premier global safety science company with more than 100 years of proven history. Founded in 1894, UL is evolving the future of safety by focusing on product safety, environment, life and health, commercial testing, workplace safety, and knowledge services to meet the world's changing needs. UL is a global leader in developing safety and sustainability standards. UL facilitates trade through certification, testing, validation, auditing, inspection, and advisory/education services delivered from our worldwide network of 131 facilities. UL's team of more than 10,000 serves customers in over 100 countries.<br></p><p><br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Services</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnership Program</trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnerships</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Our Partners - Legal</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about Legal and Regulatory Advice/Due Diligence businesses that you can partner with.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>strategic partnership program, strategic partners, commercial service, due diligence, regulatory advice, legal advice</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/835.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Baker%20and%20McKenzie.jpg" name="Baker%20and%20McKenzie"/>
      <image src="/Files/Global%20Business%20Information%20Services%20Inc.jpg" name="Global%20Business%20Information%20Services%20Inc"/>
      <image src="/Files/TUV%20Rheinland.jpg" name="TUV%20Rheinland"/>
      <image src="/Files/UL.jpg" name="UL"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/835.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/835.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
