<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>836</id>
    <title>Our Partners - State Governments</title>
    <short_title>Partners - Governments</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about State Governments you can form a strategic partnership with.</summary>
    <creation_date>11/18/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>11/18/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets<source_office>U.S. Commerical Service</source_office></source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Strategic Partners</strong></h1><p>The use of logos does not connote endorsement by the Department of Commerce of the organizations' views, products, or services.</p><h2><strong>State and Local Government</strong></h2><p>​<span><a href="http://informationportalprodhttp://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.madeinalabama.com"><span><h1><strong><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Alabama%20Department%20of%20Commerce.jpg" alt="Alabama Department of Commerce Logo" style="margin:5px;" /></strong></h1></span></a></span></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprodhttp://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.madeinalabama.com">Alabama Department of Commerce</a> brings overseas and/or foreign buyers together with Alabama suppliers through the organization, promotion, and recruitment of Alabama companies to participate in:International trade missions, trade shows and exhibitions, and incoming trade missions. The Alabama Department of Commerce provides individual counseling and sponsors international trade workshops, seminars, and conferences on relevant international business topics. Maintains a statewide international trade database and publishes the Alabama Exporters Directory, Alabama International Trade Resource Guide, and The Year in Trade, which provides a statistical overview of Alabama's exports and imports.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Appalachian%20Regional%20Commission.jpg" alt="ARC Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.arc.gov">Appalachian Regional Commission (ARC)</a> is a regional economic development agency that represents a partnership of federal, state, and local government. Established by an act of Congress in 1965, ARC is composed of the governors of the 13 Appalachian states and a federal co-chair, who is appointed by the president. Local participation is provided through multi-county local development districts.</p><p>Each year ARC provides funding for several hundred projects in the Appalachian Region, in areas such as business development, education and job training, telecommunications, infrastructure, community development, housing, and transportation. These projects create thousands of new jobs.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Business%20Oregon.jpg" alt="Business Oregon Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p><a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.oregon4biz.com">Business Oregon</a> works to create, retain, expand and attract businesses that provide sustainable living wage jobs for Oregonians through public-private partnerships, leveraged funding, and support of economic opportunities for Oregon companies and entrepreneurs. Business Oregon has an interest in this project because of its interest in ensuring a sustainable economic recovery which will be achieved in part through increasing U.S. exports. Participation in this project also furthers Business Oregon's programs to encourage the economic growth of Business Oregon clients and other small and medium-sized enterprises.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Las%20Vegas%20Convention%20and%20Visitors%20Authority.jpg" alt="LVCVA Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The<a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.lvcva.com"> Las Vegas Convention and Visitors Authority</a> (LVCVA) is charged with marketing Southern Nevada as a tourism and convention destination worldwide, and also with operating the Las Vegas Convention Center, the nation's only convention center designated as a World Trade Center and one of the largest convention centers in the United States, and Cashman Center. With more than 150,000 hotel rooms in Las Vegas alone and 10.7 million square feet of meeting and exhibit space citywide, the LVCVA's mission centers on attracting ever increasing numbers of leisure and business visitors to the area.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/North%20Carolina%20Small%20Business%20and%20Technology%20Development%20Center.jpg" alt="North Carolina Small Business and Technology Development Center Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.sbtdc.org/export">North Carolina Small Business and Technology Development Center'</a>s International Business Development (IBD) unit assists small and mid-sized businesses with exporting. Our IBD specialists are highly trained, Certified Global Business Professionals (CGBP) with extensive experience in international business development. Our goal is to provide export-related guidance and assistance to small and mid-sized businesses – enhancing their export success.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Nebraska%20Department%20of%20Economic%20Development.jpg" alt="NDED Logo" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>The <a href="http://informationportalprod/Pages/http://www.neded.org">Nebraska Department of Economic Development</a>, Office of International Trade and Investment (&quot;NDED&quot;), works with existing and start up businesses to expand their international market exposure, exports and investment. In this role,NDED works with new-to-export companies, counseling them on exporting issues and providing information resources. </p><p>In addition to export focused activities,NDED fosters a business climate conductive to recruiting and supporting international business investment in the state by working with foreign companies wishing to gain market exposure or create a physical presence in the United States to establish contacts and take the necessary steps to open a business in Nebraska. </p><p><br></p><p><br></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Ready</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Services</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnership Program</trade_programs>
        <trade_programs>Strategic Partnerships</trade_programs>
      </trade_programs>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Our Partners - State Governments</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about State Governments you can form a strategic partnership with.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>strategic partnership program, strategic partners, state governments, commercial service</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/836.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Alabama%20Department%20of%20Commerce.jpg" name="Alabama%20Department%20of%20Commerce"/>
      <image src="/Files/Appalachian%20Regional%20Commission.jpg" name="Appalachian%20Regional%20Commission"/>
      <image src="/Files/Business%20Oregon.jpg" name="Business%20Oregon"/>
      <image src="/Files/Las%20Vegas%20Convention%20and%20Visitors%20Authority.jpg" name="Las%20Vegas%20Convention%20and%20Visitors%20Authority"/>
      <image src="/Files/North%20Carolina%20Small%20Business%20and%20Technology%20Development%20Center.jpg" name="North%20Carolina%20Small%20Business%20and%20Technology%20Development%20Center"/>
      <image src="/Files/Nebraska%20Department%20of%20Economic%20Development.jpg" name="Nebraska%20Department%20of%20Economic%20Development"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/836.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/836.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
