<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>873</id>
    <title>Han's Technologies, Inc.</title>
    <short_title>Han's Technologies, Inc.</short_title>
    <summary>Learn more about Han's Technologies, one of Oakland U.S. Export Assistance Center's most successful clients.</summary>
    <creation_date>12/2/2014</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>12/1/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<p>​<a href="http://www.hanstech.net/index.asp" style="line-height:1.6;">Han's Technologies, Inc.​</a><span style="line-height:1.6;">(HTI) is an engineering and management firm providing environmental planning, construction supervision to municipalities, industry, and private developers.</span></p><p>HTI's main office in Oakland is supported by permanent liaison offices in Shenzhen, Guizhou, Hong Kong of China and Vancouver, Canada. With the history of anticipating challenges and proven experiences under 14 US patents in the area of waste-energy technologies, the company has developed a premier reputation as a leading international provider for over 60 environmental projects worldwide and was awarded an Export Achievement Certificate (EAC) by the US Department of Commerce, State of California.</p><p>HTI's ability to lead multi-disciplinary teams of experts and to define international project priorities has been demonstrated through the Build On Transfer (BOT) projects succeeded in Guizhou Province in China.</p><p>Whether it's tap water for homes, sophisticated waste treatment for industry, centralized or decentralized treatment, or the design, construction, operation and financing of entire water and wastewater projects.</p><p>Below is a history of Han's Technologies' history of awards and events with the corresponding photos:</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Hans_Technologies.jpg" alt="Photo of Han's Tech. CFO James Li pictured with Rod Hirsch and Ro Khanna, U.S. Commercial Service Deputy Assistant Secretary" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>Han's Tech. CFO<strong>James Li</strong>pictured with<strong>Rod Hirsch</strong>and<strong>Ro Khanna</strong>, U.S. Commercial Service Deputy Assistant Secretary.</p><p><img src="http://informationportalprod/Files/Hans_Technologies_2.jpg" alt="Photo of Han's Tech. CFO James Li with Rod Hirsch and William Brekke, Senior Commercial Officer, based in Beijing, China" style="margin:5px;" /><br></p><p>Han's Tech. CFO<strong>James Li</strong>with<strong>Rod Hirsch</strong>and<strong>William Brekke</strong>, Senior Commercial Officer, based in Beijing, China</p><h2>August 2010</h2><h3>Nantong, China Clean Technology Matchmaker</h3><p>On<strong>Thursday, August 19th</strong>, Han's Technologies, Inc. partnered with Oakland Export Assistance Center Director Rod Hirsch to host a government delegation from the City of Nantong, in Jiangsu Province, China. The Nantong Economic &amp; Technological Development Bureau representatives were Ms. Ling Li, Sophie Shi, Cheryl Gao, Linda Cao and Maxine Chen. Representating Han's Technologies, Inc. at the meeting were Mr. Weiping Xia, Vice President of Han's Technology and Mr. Jerry Moseley, President Emeritus of Han's Technology. The clean technology meetings were with the following companies:​</p><p><a href="http://www.principlepowerinc.com/">Principal Power</a>, Mr. Jon Bonanno, Chairman</p><p>(Principal Power participated in the May, 2010 Secretary of Commerce led<a href="http://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2010/05/04/forty-six-us-business-executives-join-commerce-gary-locke-china-and-i">Trade Mission</a>to China, investigating offshore wind power opportunities)</p><p><a href="http://www.electricmotorsport.com/">Electric Motorsports​</a>, Mr. Raul Aguilar, Chief Operations Officer</p><p>A Proprietary Lithium Ion Battery Manufacturer</p><p>Photo -<a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/eg_us_ca_023781.asp">Nantong Delegation Matchmaker</a></p><p>Photo -<a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/eg_us_ca_023782.asp">Nantong Gift Presentation</a></p><h2>June 2006</h2><p>Han's Tech is Guest Speaker at American Water Works Assocation (AWWA)2006</p><p>Mr. Jerry Moseley, President and Mr. Wieping Xia, Vice President of Han's Technologies were invited by Oakland Export Assistance Center Director Rod Hirsch to be guest speakers at the U.S. Commercial Service's Environmental Techno​logy Team meeting during the AWWA 2006 tradeshow in San Antonio, Texas. Han's Technologies arranged a VIP delegation consisting of key government decision makers to attend the tradeshow and panel discussion.</p><p>Mr. Zhao Youliang, Commissioner of the Administrative Office of Bijie Prefecture of Guizhou Province, China was an honored guest and keynote speaker at the Environmental Technology Team panel discussion.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/eg_us_ca_023785.asp">Photo - Han's Tech at AWWA 2006</a></p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/eg_us_ca_023786.asp">Photo - Commissioner Zhao Youliang</a></p><h2>October 2005</h2><p>Oakland Platinum Key Check Signing Ceremony</p><p>Han's Technologies, Inc. piloted a Domestic Platinum Key Service with the Oakland Export Assistance Center in which customized services would be rendered over the course of one year to assist the company in expanding their presence in the China market.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023787.asp">Photo - Platinum Key Check Signing Ceremony</a></p><h2>March 2004</h2><p>&quot;U.S. Water Treatment Firm 'Taps' Chinese Market&quot;</p><p>Han's Technologies' success story in obtaining 17 build-operate-transfer projects in China is featured in &quot;Export America,&quot; a prestigious publication by the U.S. Department of Commerce. These projects will provide much needed water &quot;in six counties of Bijie prefecture for domestic, municipal, and industrial consumers, and for the development of irrigated agriculture in the surrounding areas.&quot; To view the full article, please click on the link below.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ca/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ca_023789.pdf">Han's Tech Export America Article</a></p><h2>January 2004</h2><p>Ground Breaking Ceremony in Guizhou, China</p><p>Director Rod Hirsch from the Oakland Export Assistance Center (EAC) and Mr. Bruce Blakeman, Special Envoy to China, were invited to attend the Ground Breaking Ceremony for Han's Technologies' new water supply plant in Guizhou, China.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023868.asp">Photo - Groundbreaking Ceremony (1)</a></p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023869.asp">Photo - Groundbreaking Ceremony (2)</a></p><h2>November 2003</h2><p>Han's Technologies Meet with Ms. Yue Cao, Commercial Specialist from CS Beijing</p><p>On November 9, 2003, Director Rod Hirsch (Oakland EAC) and Director Eduardo Torres (Fresno EAC) collaborated in a joint effort to host Ms. Yue Cao, Commercial Specialist from Commercial Service Beijing, China. Director Hirsch and Director Torres arranged a meeting for Han's Technologies with Ms. Cao to discuss China's market potential and opportunities.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023870.asp">Photo - Meeting with Commercial Specialist Yue Cao</a></p><h2>May 2003</h2><p>&quot;Weiping Xia: Sending U.S. tech back home&quot;</p><p>Mr. Weiping Xia, Vice-President, and Han's Technologies is featured in an article in the East Bay Business Times on May 9, 2003. A brief exerpt from the article states: &quot;About 90 percent of the plant's technology comes from the United States, and Xia considers it a showcase for his engineering firm, which specializes in water pollution control technologies. Since then, Han's has done about $12 million worth of business across China. It was the first company to develop a U.S.-China joint environmental consulting firm in the country. In all, the venture, called Shenzhen Han's Environmental Technology and Engineering Co., has helped build five wastewater treatment plants.&quot;</p><p>To view the full article, please refer to<a href="http://www.export.gov/california/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ca/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ca_023871.pdf">East Bay Business Times</a>.</p><h2>April 2003</h2><p>Han's Technologies' Export Achievement Certificate Ceremony</p><p>On April 9, 2003, Director Rod Hirsch arranged for Ms. Maria Cino, Assistant Secretary of Commerce &amp; Director General (U.S. Department of Commerce), and Mr. Bruce Blakeman, Deputy Assistant Secretary (U.S. Department of Commerce), to present the Department of Commerce's Export Achievement Certificate to Han's Technologies' Mr. Fernando Chen (Board of Directors, Mr. Weiping Xia (Vice-President), and Mr. Jerry Moseley (President). This event was a partnership effort between the Oakland Export Assistance Center, the Small Business Administration, and the Bay Area World Trade Center.</p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023872.asp">Photo - Export Achievement Certificate Ceremony (1)</a></p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/oakland/usexporterprofiles/eg_us_ca_023873.asp">Photo - Export Achievement Certificate Ceremony (2)</a></p><p><a href="http://www.export.gov/california/build/groups/public/%40eg_us_ca/documents/webcontent/eg_us_ca_023874.pdf">GDI Luncheon &amp; Export Award Ceremony Flyer</a></p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <industries/>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Exporting</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <trade_initiatives/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Learn</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Han's Technologies, Inc.</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn more about Han's Technologies, one of Oakland U.S. Export Assistance Center's most successful clients.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>export, exporting, success, awards, Oakland, California</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/873.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images>
      <image src="/Files/Hans_Technologies.jpg" name="Hans_Technologies"/>
      <image src="/Files/Hans_Technologies_2.jpg" name="Hans_Technologies_2"/>
    </images>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/873.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/873.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
