<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articles>
  <article>
    <id>883</id>
    <title>Export Success Story: Knit-Rite Inc.</title>
    <short_title>Knit-Rite Success Story</short_title>
    <summary>Learn about the export achievement award presented to Knit-Rite Inc.</summary>
    <creation_date>4/30/2013</creation_date>
    <release_date/>
    <expiration_date>12/9/2015</expiration_date>
    <source_agencies>
      <source_agency>International Trade Administration<source_business_unit>Global Markets</source_business_unit></source_agency>
    </source_agencies>
    <evergreen>0</evergreen>
    <content><![CDATA[<h1><a href="https://new.export.gov/community/users/export-success-stories/posts/179-knit-rite-inc-receives-export-achievement-certificate">Knit-Rite, Inc. Receives Export Achievement Certificate</a></h1><p>Not Rated </p><p> </p><p>U.S. Department of Commerce Under Secretary for Economic Affairs Cynthia A. Glassman today presented the Commerce Department's Export Achievement Certificate to Knit-Rite, Inc. The award recognizes companies that have benefited from the U.S. Commercial Service assistance to make their first export sale or successfully enter new foreign markets.</p><p>&quot;Knit-Rite, a manufacturer of medical textiles, is an excellent example of how area firms are boosting their bottom line by expanding their international sales,&quot; said Glassman. &quot;I am hopeful we can help even more U.S. companies increase their export business by passing in the coming months, four new free trade agreements with Peru, Colombia, Panama and South Korea. I congratulate Knit-Rite on their outstanding export accomplishments.&quot;</p><p>Knit-Rite, Inc. headquartered in Kansas City, Kan., began in 1923 as a producer of simple &quot;stump socks&quot; and has grown into a manufacturer of high quality medical and consumer textiles, including prosthetic socks, orthotic textiles, diabetic socks, compression hosiery and other medical applications. Building on over 80 years of medical textile innovations, today Knit-Rite's foot and leg wear products are specifically designed to provide health benefits to the wearer and are exported to more than 40 countries. Among these markets are Australia, Mexico and Chile, all of which have free trade agreements with the United States.</p><p>Over the years, Knit-Rite has been able to grow its export sales by using the assistance of the Commercial Service's Kansas City U.S. Export Assistance Center and foreign offices in evaluating new customers and partners, registration requirements in foreign markets, participating in trade events, and using Ex-Im Bank programs to insure export credit terms to new customers. Most recently, with this assistance, the firm was able to make its first sales into Turkey, Greece and Lebanon.</p><p>&quot;The Commercial Service has saved our company valuable time and resources, enabling us to boost our exports, and achieve a higher level of sales in the face of international competition,&quot; said Executive Vice President, CFO, COO Chris Vering. &quot;Our export sales continue to make a vital contribution to our company's growth here at home, enabling us to both maintain and add local jobs.&quot;</p><p>The U.S. Commercial Service is a U.S. Commerce Department agency that helps small and midsize U.S. businesses sell their products and services globally, and has more than 100 Export Assistance Centers throughout the United States and 150 international offices in over 80 countries. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.export.gov/">www.export.gov</a>.</p><p>Knit-Rite, Inc., is a leading designer, marketer, and manufacturer of innovative textiles for medical and retail markets. Knit-Rite manufactures products under the registered brand names, Knit-Rite, SmartKnit, and Therafirm. Knit-Rite also maintains an active R&amp;D staff with a scientific background in textile manufacturing technology. For more information, visit<a href="http://www.knitrite.com/">www.Knitrite.com</a></p><p>​</p>]]></content>
    <keyword/>
    <tags>
      <countries/>
      <topics>
        <topic>Trade Counseling</topic>
      </topics>
      <geo_regions/>
      <trade_regions/>
      <trade_programs/>
      <export_phases>
        <export_phase>Exporting</export_phase>
      </export_phases>
      <industries>
        <industry>Industrial Equipment &amp; Supplies</industry>
      </industries>
      <trade_initiatives>
        <trade_initiatives>Discover Global Markets</trade_initiatives>
      </trade_initiatives>
    </tags>
    <seometadatatitle>Export Success Story: Knit-Rite Inc.</seometadatatitle>
    <seometadatadescription>Learn about the export achievement award presented to Knit-Rite Inc.</seometadatadescription>
    <seometadatakeyword>Export-Import Bank, Distribution Partners, Trade Events</seometadatakeyword>
    <trade_url> www.export.gov/883.htm</trade_url>
    <files/>
    <images/>
    <data>
      <html>http://informationportalprod/Data/Article/883.htm</html>
      <xml>http://informationportalprod/Data/883.xml</xml>
    </data>
  </article>
</articles>
